<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LEAF-VRE/code_snippets/refs/heads/main/CSS/lwc.css"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>HUMN100 FALL 2025: The Murder of William Desmond Taylor</title>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Diane Jakacki</persName>
               <resp>Instructor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Waina Ali</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Jada Alvarez</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Colin Caricato</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>John Cochran</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Lucy DiChristina</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Nick Eisele-Bockelkamp</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Ethan Esclamado</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Spencer Firestone</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Henry Gibbons</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Daniel Hou</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Campbell Killian</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Olivia King</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>William Le</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Charlie Meehleib</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Carter Morton</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Kate Reyen</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Blythe Sena</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Hunter Sloan</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Rylie Smith</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Lily Stein</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Riley Twiss</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Katrina von Behren</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Emma Walkowiak</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Amanda Woertz</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Produced by members of the HUMN100: Introduction to Text Analysis course, Fall
               2025</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>These interviews and statements are gathered from a number of sources, including
               "Taylorology" and Robert Giroux's Deed of Death</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy>
               <category xml:id="actor"/>
               <category xml:id="director"/>
               <category xml:id="studio_employee"/>
               <category xml:id="military"/>
               <category xml:id="law_enforcement"/>
               <category xml:id="legal"/>
               <category xml:id="servant"/>
               <category xml:id="family"/>
               <category xml:id="professional"/>
               <category xml:id="writer"/>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="interview">
            <head>Interview with Ethel May Harrison</head>
            <div type="section" n="1">
               <byline>Edited by Charlie Meehleib</byline>
               <p> Interviews with Taylor's Ex-Wife * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * *
                  * * * * * * * * * February 5, 1922 NEW YORK HERALD</p>
               <p><persName key="taylor">William Desmond Taylor</persName>, the slain movie
                  director, was well known in this city in <date>1908</date>. But he was not known
                  as <persName key="taylor">Taylor</persName>. He was <persName key="taylor">William
                     Cunningham Deane-Tanner</persName>, expert in <objectName type="furniture"
                     >antiques</objectName> in those days, and he moved in good society, was well
                  supplied with <objectName key="money">money</objectName> from a mysterious source
                  in Ireland and eventually was married to <persName key="eTanner">Ethel May
                     Harrison</persName> of one of the<orgName key="store"> Floradora
                     Sextettes</orgName>.</p>
               <p> Without a word of explanation, according to the woman who was then his wife, he
                  disappeared in <date>1908</date>. The first <persName key="deanetanner">Mrs.
                     Deane-Tanner</persName> now is the wife of <persName key="robins">E. L. C.
                     Robins</persName>, owner of <placeName type="restaurant">Robins
                     Restaurant</placeName> and other hostelries. <persName key="eTanner">Mrs.
                     Robins</persName> gave out a statement yesterday explaining her marriage and
                  the desertion and her subsequent discovery that her former husband had<eventName>
                     popped up in the motion picture colony</eventName> at <placeName key="state"
                     >Hollywood, Cal</placeName>., and became famous the world over as <persName
                     key="taylor">William Desmond Taylor</persName>. She says <eventName
                     key="murder">his murder</eventName> shocked her and the daughter he
                  abandoned.</p>
               <p>"<eventName key="marriage">I married, in December, 1901</eventName>, <persName
                     key="taylor">Mr. William Cunningham Deane-Tanner</persName> of <placeName
                     key="country">Dublin, Ireland</placeName>," the statement said. "<eventName>He
                     disappeared in October, 1908</eventName>. We could assign no reason for his
                  disappearance except possibly aphasia. "In <date>1912</date> I got a decree of
                  divorce in the State of <placeName key="state">New York</placeName>
                  <eventName>and was awarded custody of my only child , now 19.</eventName> "In
                  August, 1914, I married Edward L. C. Robins. <eventName>Two and a half weeks later
                     I discovered that William Desmond Taylor had been Mr. Deane-Tanner</eventName>.
                  I have no further statement which possibly could be of interest. "The news of Mr.
                  Deane-Tanner's death was a great shock to my daughter and me NOrienta <placeName
                     key="town">Point, Mamaroneck</placeName>, last night, <persName key="eTanner"
                     >Mrs. Robins</persName> said she held no resentment for the way <persName
                     key="deaneTanner">Deane-Tanner</persName> treated me."</p>
               <p>At her <placeName>home in ted her</placeName>. She presented excuses for him,
                  saying he suffered lapses of memory during the time they lived together and that
                  not long before he vanished, in <date key="year">1908</date>, he was stricken with
                  facial neuralgia and frequently was in an agony of pain. She does not believe he
                  knew what he was doing the morning he left their <placeName key="residence"
                     >home</placeName> and she supposes that a mental ailment can be held to account
                  for his failure to return.</p>
               <p>Just as dramatic as were many of the chapters in <persName key="taylor"
                     >Deane-Tanner, or William Desmond Taylor's</persName>, life was <eventName>Mrs.
                     Robins's discovery in 1919 that he was still living</eventName>.</p>
               <p>With her daughter <persName key="eTanner">Mrs. Robins</persName> went to a
                     <placeName key="studio">motion picture theater in this city</placeName> one
                  night. They chose <placeName key="theater">the theater</placeName> without knowing
                  what picture it was featuring. For several hundred feet of film it was just a new
                  picture as far as they were concerned, but suddenly the hero appeared. <persName
                     key="robins">Mrs. Robins</persName> sank back in her <objectName
                     key="furniture">seat</objectName> too startled to missing <persName
                     key="deaneTanner">Deane- Tanner</persName> a little changed--somewhat older
                  looking they decided when they finally settled back to wait for the hero's next
                  entry. They sat through the picture and then saw it again and learned that the man
                  whose face they knew was acting and directing movies under the name of <persName
                     key="taylor">William Desmond Taylor</persName>.</p>
               <p><persName key="eTanner">Mrs. Robins</persName> said last night that her daughter
                  would not be satisfied until she had written to <persName key="taylor"
                     >Taylor</persName>. <persName key="taylor">Taylor</persName> answered her
                     <objectName key="document">letter</objectName> and the two continued a
                  correspondence which grew with each month until finally <persName key="taylor"
                     >Taylor</persName> of the movies came back to <placeName key="city">New
                     York</placeName> to try to make some amends for his conduct as <persName
                     key="deaneTaylor">Deane-Tanner</persName>, the negligent father.</p>
               <p><persName key="taylor">Taylor</persName> never explained why he had changed his
                  name. But <persName key="eTanner">Mrs. Robins</persName> said he met her and the
                  daughter on at least one occasion and expressed a desire to try to make good for
                  his failure. He spent <objectName key="money">money</objectName> lavishly on the
                  girl, giving <objectName key="money">money</objectName> and other <objectName
                     key="passage">presents</objectName> to her and encouraging her to study. The
                  love of the beautiful in art that appears to have impressed his Hollywood friends
                  cropped up in his talks with his daughter, and he ultimately prevailed upon her to
                  enter an <placeName key="school">art school in this city</placeName>. She is now
                  studying there.</p>
               <p>
                  <persName key="eTanner">Mrs. Robins</persName> emphatically denied that her former
                  husband ever married after he deserted her. She said she met him <date key="month"
                     >last August</date> and remembers distinctly that he said he never had
                  remarried and never would. His daughter, she quoted him as saying, was the only
                  pal he wanted.</p>
               <p>According to <persName key="eTanner">Mrs. Robins</persName>, <persName
                     key="deaneTanner">Deane-Tanner</persName> was of a family well known in
                     <placeName key="country">Ireland</placeName>--listed among the landed gentry or
                  the peers, she wasn't sure which. His father was a Major in the British army, and
                  he came of a line of men whose names have figured in British history.</p>
               <p>She said he was prepared for the army at one of the great British
                     universities--<placeName key="college">Oxford or Cambridge</placeName>--and
                  that he was about to start for the military school when his health failed. He was
                  sent to the <placeName key="country">United States</placeName>, he told her, so
                  that he might recover. <persName key="eTanner">Mrs. Robins</persName> said she
                  remembers that he told her once he had two sisters and one brother, and she met
                  soon after their marriage a man she supposes was the brother.</p>
               <p>The stories of <objectName key="possession">drugs and drinking</objectName>,
                     <persName key="eTanner">Mrs. Robins</persName> thinks, are untrue, because
                  while <persName key="deaneTanner">Deane-Tanner </persName>was her husband he used
                     <objectName key="possession">liquor</objectName> but sparingly and always
                  criticized those who did not know how to handle it.</p>
               <p>Before her marriage to <persName key="taylor">Taylor--or Deane-Tanner</persName>,
                  as he called himself then--<persName key="etanner">Mrs. Robins was Miss Ethel May
                     Harrison</persName>. No one could be found who could explain fully
                     <persName>Deane-Tanner</persName>'s early movements in <placeName key="city"
                     >New York</placeName>, but it was established that he came from <placeName
                     key="country">Ireland</placeName> with considerable <objectName key="money"
                     >money</objectName> and a habit of spending it freely. He caused some attention
                  in sporting circles, talked about his <objectName key="vehicle"
                     >yachts</objectName> abroad, and eventually, it was said, became a familiar
                  figure on the float of the <placeName key="club">Larchmont Yacht Club</placeName>.
                  He made friends easily and held them. Suddenly he began talking of previous visits
                  here, and it was said yesterday, by men who knew him but do not want their names
                  coupled with his in the murder mystery, that he let it be known he had played in
                  roles opposite <persName key="fanny">Fanny Davenpor</persName>t.</p>
               <p><persName key="eTanner">Mrs. Robins</persName> would not say where she and her
                  first husband made their home or where they were living when he disappeared, but
                  it was established through friends that he dropped out of sight <date>in
                     1908</date> a few weeks after the <placeName key="city">Vanderbilt</placeName>
                  cup races.</p>
               <p>* * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * February 6, 1922
                  NEW YORK DAILY NEWS</p>
               <p><persName key="robins">Edward L. C. Robins</persName>, owner of <placeName
                     key="resturant">Delmonico's</placeName>, who married <persName key="eTanner"
                     >Mrs. Ethel Hamilton Deane Tanner</persName> after she had divorced the
                  romantic Irishman whose murder has stirred the continent, knew <persName
                     key="eTanner">Tanner</persName> well and met <persName key="eTanner">Mrs.
                     Tanner--now Mrs. Robins</persName>--through that friendship.</p>
               <p>But <persName key="robins">Mr. Robins</persName> has not the slightest idea of how
                     <persName key="Tanner">Tanner--known to Hollywood and the movie world as
                     William Desmond Taylor</persName>--came to be murdered. <eventName>Talking with
                     a representative of the Daily News at his home in Mamaroneck last night,
                        <persName key="robins">Mr. Robins</persName> said: "I can't see why the
                     newspapers are paying so much attention to <persName>Mamaroneck</persName>. It
                     seems to me they ought to be trying to solve this mystery out in <placeName
                        key="city">Los Angeles</placeName>, where it happened</eventName>.</p>
               <p>"I knew <persName key="pete">'Pete</persName>,' as we called him, long before
                     <persName>Mrs. Tanner</persName> and I were married. Pictures of him now?
                     <persName key="ethel">Ethel</persName>, have we any pictures of <persName
                     key="pete">Pete</persName>?" <persName key="robins">Mrs. Robins</persName> had
                  been listening in an alcove. When called she appeared promptly. A tall, striking
                  blonde, with big, wide-open eyes, she did not impress one as the cakeyree girl who
                  twenty years ago played in the <placeName>Floradora company</placeName>.</p>
               <p> "No," she answered. "I destroyed all those pictures when we got married. There
                  might be one or two in the <objectName>old trunks</objectName>
                  <placeName key="house">upstairs</placeName>, but I doubt it. Every one I found I
                  tore up long ago."</p>
               <p>With just that much interest is the murder of the man who was her husband accepted
                  by <persName key="robins">Mrs. Robins</persName>. She divorced him ten years ago,
                  under curious circumstances, after he had gone out of her life four years before.
                  Apparently his sudden and unexpected going out from his own life has made only the
                  slightest impression upon <persName key="robinds">Mrs. Robins</persName>.</p>
               <p>But behind all this insouciance there looms some extraordinary mystery. <persName
                     key="robins">Mrs. Robins </persName>cannot imagine any reason why her former
                  husband was shot down in cold blood in his quiet home <placeName key="city">at
                     Hollywood last Wednesday night</placeName>. But she is not surprised,
                  astonished, amazed or--to be brutally frank--very much horror-stricken.</p>
               <p>...<persName>Mrs. Robins</persName> said last night that shortly after their
                  marriage she and Tanner visited his folks in <placeName key="country"
                     >Ireland</placeName>. They were entertained royally and she realized for the
                  first time that the young blood she had married <placeName>off
                     Broadway</placeName> was a veritable sportsman in <placeName key="country"
                     >Ireland</placeName>. His family entertained her at their home in
                     <placeName>Fitzwilliam Square</placeName> and afterward they paid a visit to
                     <placeName>Cork</placeName>, where the old family seat was located.</p>
               <p>"They were the <persName key="taylor">Deane Tanners</persName>," <persName
                     key="robins">Mrs. Robins</persName> explained, "to differentiate them from the
                  other Tanners. The name is rather a familiar one in Ireland, and in England I
                  think it is rather derogatorily applied to some <objectName key="money">small
                     coin</objectName>, a six-pence, I think. His father had been a member of
                  Parliament; his uncle was a justice of the peace. Altogether the family was quite
                  to the front."...</p>
            </div>

            <div type="section" n="2">
               <byline>Edited by Carter Morton</byline>
               <p> Interviews with <persName key="ethel">Ethel Mae Harrison</persName>
                  <date>February 13, 1922</date>
                  <orgName type="newspaper">NEW YORK HERALD</orgName>
               </p>

               <p>...<persName key="ethel">Mrs. Robins</persName>, who married <persName
                     key="Taylor">William Cunningham Deane-Tanner</persName>, or <persName
                     key="Taylor">William Desmond Taylor</persName>, as he was later known, in
                     <date>1902</date>, said her former husband had spent some time on a <placeName
                     type="job">pony ranch</placeName> in <placeName type="region"
                     >southwestern</placeName>
                  <placeName type="state">Kansas</placeName> before <persName key="ethel"
                     >she</persName> met him in <placeName key="city">New York</placeName>. The only
                  information she had ever had was that which <persName key="Taylor"
                     >Deane-Tanner</persName> gave her personally.</p>

               <p>"<persName key="Taylor">Mr. Deane-Tanner</persName> told me that when he arrived
                  here from <placeName type="country">Ireland</placeName> he had gone out to this
                     <placeName type="job">ranch</placeName>," <persName key="ethel">Mrs.
                     Robins</persName> said, "and his family in <placeName type="country"
                     >Ireland</placeName> had <eventName type="investment">bought</eventName> for
                  him a part interest in it. When I met him he keyerred to it and told me a flaw in
                  the <objectName type="document">title</objectName> had forced several of the
                  shareholders, including <persName key="Taylor">himself</persName>, to give up
                  their part, and he then joined the <orgName type="company">Davenport road
                     company</orgName>. After the failure of his venture in
                     <placeName>Kansas</placeName> he returned to his home in <placeName
                     type="country">Ireland</placeName> for a visit.</p>

               <p>"With keyerence to the claim of this <persName key="Taylor">Mr. Taylor</persName>
                  in <placeName key="state">California</placeName> that he is the son of the
                  murdered <persName key="Taylor">director</persName>, I would not like to say
                  flatly that the claim is or is not true, for I knew little of <persName
                     key="Taylor">Mr. Deane-Tanner's</persName> life on the <placeName type="job"
                     >ranch</placeName> in <placeName type="state">Kansas</placeName> and did not
                  find it necessary to catechize him minutely, and he never mentioned anything to me
                  about having been married out there. Perhaps there is some truth in the story, or
                  it may be another of the many persons who come forward whenever there is an
                     <objectName type="money">estate</objectName> to be settled. I have been
                  interested in the number of persons who claim <persName key="Taylor">Mr.
                     Deane-Tanner</persName>, or <persName key="Taylor">Taylor</persName>, was their
                  father. To date he must have had at least six or seven children besides my own
                  daughter, if the stories are all correct. As <persName key="Taylor">Mr.
                     Deane-Tanner</persName> would only be about <time>fifty years</time> old now,
                  that is rather ridiculous, I think."</p>

               <p> keyerring to the criminal end of the case, <persName key="ethel">Mrs.
                     Robins</persName> criticized the work of the <placeName type="city">Los
                     Angeles</placeName> detectives and prosecutors, saying they do not seem to be
                  particularly anxious to solve the mystery of the identity of the murderer.</p>

               <p>"<persName key="ethel">I</persName> have bitterly resented the accounts printed in
                  some of the newspapers here that my daughter and myself are merely interested in
                  the financial part of the affair and are more interested in the <persName
                     key="Taylor">Taylor</persName>
                  <objectName key="money">estate</objectName> than in the identity of the person who
                  killed my former husband. This is absolutely untrue, for, as <persName
                     key="Taylor">Mr. Taylor's</persName> former wife, I am deeply grieved at this
                  terrible affair and am anxious to see the guilty person punished." Returning to
                  the discussion of the claim of the man who says the <persName key="Taylor">movie
                     director</persName> was his <persName key="Taylor">father</persName>, <persName
                     key="ethel">Mrs. Robins</persName> said that it seemed improbable that her
                  first husband ever used the name of <persName key="Taylor">Taylor</persName>
                  before he left <placeName type="city">New York</placeName> in <date>1908</date>.
                     <persName key="ethel">She</persName> said that to old friends who knew him when
                  he first came to <placeName type="country">this country</placeName> and had been
                  in constant touch with him during his stay in <placeName type="state"
                     >Kansas</placeName> nothing was known of any marriage while he was in the
                     <placeName>West</placeName>. After that, and until he <eventName type="leaving"
                     >disappeared</eventName>, <persName key="ethel">Mrs. Robins</persName> said, he
                  never used the name of <persName key="Taylor">Taylor</persName>, or keyerred
                  extensively to his visit to the <placeName type="job">ranch</placeName> in the
                     <placeName type="region">West</placeName>.</p>

               <p>"I never really knew <persName key="Taylor">Mr. Deane-Tanner's</persName> right
                  age," <persName>Mrs. Robins</persName> said, "and I understood that he had been in
                     <placeName type="country">his country</placeName> about eight or nine years,
                  when I <eventName type="marriage">married</eventName> him at the <orgName
                     type="church">Little Church Around the Corner</orgName> in <date>1901</date>.
                  He was a fine, lovable man, and I never had occasion to closely question him about
                  his 'past,' which every one seems trying to <eventName type="investigation">dig
                     up</eventName>."</p>

               <p>No decision whether <persName key="ethel">Mrs. Robins</persName> or her daughter,
                     <persName key="daughter">Ethel</persName>, will go to <placeName type="state"
                     >California</placeName> in connection with the settling of the <objectName
                     type="money">estate</objectName> has been reached. <persName key="frank">Frank
                     E. Schrenseisen</persName> of <placeName type="city">New Rochelle</placeName>,
                  attorney for <persName>Miss Tanner</persName>, said that he was awaiting
                  developments and instructions from the office of the Public <title
                     type="politician">Administrator</title> in <placeName type="city">Los
                     Angeles</placeName>. Another attorney for <persName key="ethel">Miss
                     Tanner</persName> has been engaged in <placeName type="city">Los
                     Angeles</placeName>. Should the <title type="politician">Public
                     Administrator</title> place credence in the story of <persName key="Taylor"
                     >Taylor</persName>, it is probable that <persName key="ethel">Miss
                     Tanner</persName> will accompany her attorney to <placeName type="region">the
                     coast</placeName>.</p>

               <p> "<persName key="Taylor">Mr. Deane-Tanner</persName> told my <persName
                     key="daughter">daughter</persName> that he had made a <objectName
                     type="document">will</objectName> in her favor," <persName key="ethel">Mrs.
                     Robins</persName> said, "and had placed it in his <objectName type="bank">safe
                     deposit box</objectName>. I understand that this is another one of the
                     <objectName type="document">items</objectName> which the <orgName type="law"
                     >police</orgName> say have strangely '<eventName type="disapearnce"
                     >disappeared</eventName>.' What he did with it I have no idea, but I feel that
                  the entire matter will be straightened out. Just at present I am hoping that the
                  murderer of <persName key="Taylor">Mr. Taylor</persName> will be brought to
                  justice for this terrible crime."</p>

               <p><persName key="ethel">Mrs. Robins</persName> commented on the strange
                  disappearance of <persName key="dennis">Dennis Deane- Tanner</persName>, <persName
                     key="dennis">brother</persName> of the murdered <persName key="Taylor"
                     >director</persName>, and said she had never heard a word from him since he
                  left this <placeName type="city">city</placeName> in <date>1912</date>, just
                     <time>four years</time> after her husband <eventName type="disappearance"
                     >disappeared</eventName>. She said the two brothers had been good friends and
                  business associates, and that <persName key="dennis">Dennis</persName> had visited
                  their home at <placeName type="town">Larchmont</placeName> on several occasions,
                  and had met many of their friends. There was never any trouble between the
                  brothers as far as she knew, <persName key="ethel">Mrs. Robins
                  </persName>said.</p>

               <p><date>February 14, 1922</date>
                  <orgName type="newspaper">NEW YORK AMERICAN</orgName></p>

               <p>To the two names suggested in the <orgName type="newspaper">New York
                     American</orgName>
                  <date>yesterday</date>--<persName key="sands">Edward F. Sands</persName> and
                     <persName key="dennis">Dennis Gage Deane-Tanner</persName> as persons whose
                  discovery may furnish a clue to the identity of the slayer of <persName
                     key="Taylor">William Desmond Taylor</persName>--was added
                     <date>yesterday</date> a third.</p>

               <p> The third person is a woman, a fascinating blonde who was the companion of
                     <persName key="Taylor">Taylor</persName> (or <persName key="Taylor">W. C.
                     Deane-Tanner</persName>, as he was then known) on a trip through the <placeName
                     type="region">Adirondacks</placeName> during the <date>Summer of 1908</date>,
                     <date>three months prior</date> to the sudden disappearance of <persName
                     key="Taylor">"Pete" Tanner</persName> in <date>late October, 1908</date>.</p>

               <p>This woman, who had completely enchained the fancy of the aristocratic, handsome
                     <persName key="Taylor">Tanner</persName>, was married. Her identity is said to
                  be known to a few of <persName key="Taylor">Tanner's</persName> associates of the
                  old days when he was a director in the <orgName type="company">A. J. Crawford
                     Company</orgName> firm at <placeName type="address">No. 253 Fifth
                     avenue</placeName>. She was the co-respondent in the divorce <eventName
                     type="divorce">suit</eventName> instituted some two years after <persName
                     key="Taylor">"Pete" Tanner's</persName> disappearance by <persName key="ethel"
                     >Mrs. Ethel May Hamilton Robins</persName>, now the wife of <persName
                     key="robins">Edward L. C. Robins</persName>, managing proprietor of <orgName
                     type="restaurant">Delmonico's</orgName>.</p>

               <p>Does this hitherto hidden episode in the life of the murdered <persName
                     key="Taylor">man</persName> bear any significance upon the crime?</p>

               <p>Was the woman's husband implacably determined to <eventName type="revenge"
                     >avenge</eventName> himself upon the <persName key="Taylor">man</persName> who
                  had won the affections of his wife?</p>

               <p>Was it the hand of the husband that <eventName type="murder">fired</eventName> the
                  fatal <objectName type="bullet">bullet</objectName> (from twelve to fourteen years
                  old, according to the testimony of experts in ballistics) that killed <persName
                     key="Taylor">William Desmond Taylor</persName>?</p>

               <p> ...At her home, <placeName type="house">Orienta Point,</placeName>
                  <placeName type="town">Mamaroneck</placeName>, <persName key="ethel">Mrs.
                     Robins</persName>, former wife of the slain <persName key="Taylor"
                     >director</persName>, <date>yesterday</date> keyused to discuss this episode in
                  the life of her former <persName key="Taylor">husband</persName>. <persName
                     key="ethel">She</persName> keyused to see <persName key="reporter">newspaper
                     men</persName> but told a friend: "<persName key="ethel">I</persName> would do
                  anything in my power to solve the mystery of <persName key="Taylor">Mr.
                     Tanner's</persName> death but I do not think there can be any possible relation
                  between this incident and the crime. It was not until <date>long after</date>
                  <persName key="Taylor">Mr. Tanner's</persName> disappearance that I learned
                  definitely there was another woman in his life. "This information was placed in
                  the hands of my attorney, <persName key="george">Mr. George Thoms</persName>, and
                  he brought a successful <eventName type="divorce">suit</eventName> for divorce
                  against <persName>Mr. Tanner</persName>. This was in <date>the latter part of
                     1918</date> [sic]. At that time I did not know whether <persName key="Taylor"
                     >Mr. Tanner</persName> was dead or alive.</p>

               <p>"It was <date>later</date>, perhaps <date>seven years ago</date>, that I
                     <eventName type="recognize">saw</eventName>
                  <persName key="Taylor">Mr. Tanner</persName> for the first time on the screen. I
                  cannot remember the name of the photoplay in which he appeared. However, it was
                  not until <date>two and one-half years ago</date> that I learned definitely that
                     <persName key="Taylor">William Desmond Taylor</persName> was my former
                  husband."</p>

               <p><date>February 14, 1922</date>
                  <orgName type="newspaper">WASHINGTON TIMES</orgName></p>

               <p>
                  <placeName type="city">New York</placeName>, <date>Feb. 14</date> -- Of the many
                  screen stars he knew, some of whom have been thrown squarely into the spotlight by
                  the unrelenting inquiry into his association with <persName key="Taylor">William
                     Desmond Taylor</persName>, slain director, mentioned but one--<persName
                     key="minter">Mary Miles Minter</persName>--in his letters to his
                  nineteen-year-old <persName key="daughter">daughter</persName>, <persName
                     key="daughter">Miss Ethel Daisy Deane-Tanner</persName>.</p>

               <p> Disclosing this fact to a reporter today, <persName key="daughter">Miss
                     Tanner</persName> and her mother, <persName key="ethel">Mrs. Edward L. C.
                     Robins</persName>, who live in <placeName type="town">Mamaroneck</placeName>,
                  both of whom were <eventName type="abondon">deserted</eventName> by the man of
                  mystery in <date>1908</date>, said that <persName key="minter">Miss
                     Minter's</persName> name was used by the <persName key="Taylor"
                     >director</persName> only in an impersonal way.</p>

               <p><persName key="Taylor">He</persName> keyerred to <persName key="minter"
                     >her</persName> as an actress of ability, and said he had directed <persName
                     key="minter">her</persName> in some of her photoplays. This was one of the last
                  letters written to his daughter by <persName key="Taylor">Taylor</persName> before
                  he was <eventName type="murder">murdered</eventName> in his <placeName type="city"
                     >Los Angeles</placeName>
                  <placeName type="house">bungalow</placeName>. <persName key="ethel">Mrs.
                     Robins</persName> and her <persName key="daughter">daughter</persName>
                  expressly asserted that the name of <persName key="mabel">Mabel
                  Normand</persName>, screen comedienne, and last person to see the director alive,
                  did not appear in <persName key="Taylor">Taylor's</persName> letters to his
                     <persName key="daughter">daughter</persName>, which had been more or less
                  frequent during the <date>last two years</date>.</p>

               <p>Curiously enough, (and one reason why <persName key="ethel">Mrs. Robins</persName>
                  is increasingly inclined to the opinion that her husband's sudden <eventName
                     type="abandon">disappearance</eventName> from <placeName type="city">New
                     York</placeName> was due to loss of memory), her former husband never mentioned
                  her in the letters.</p>

               <p>Another reason for this belief, she declared, was that on the times she and her
                     <persName key="daughter">daughter</persName> lunched here with <persName
                     key="Taylor">Taylor</persName>--after it was definitely established that
                     <persName key="Taylor">Taylor</persName> was in reality <persName key="Taylor"
                     >Deane-Tanner</persName>--he never mentioned the fact that he <eventName
                     type="abandon">deserted</eventName> his <persName key="ethel">wife</persName>
                  and <persName type="ethel">daughter</persName>. On these occasions all three felt
                  the subject was rather delicate and it was never brought up. <persName key="ethel"
                     >Mrs. Robins</persName> said that when <persName type="ethel">she</persName>
                  and her <persName key="daughter">daughter</persName> became convinced <date>two
                     years ago</date>, after seeing pictures of <persName key="Taylor"
                     >Taylor</persName>, that he was the girl's father, <persName key="daughter"
                     >Miss Deane-Tanner</persName> took the initiative and wrote to him. His reply
                  came <time>immediately</time>.</p>

               <p>In it he said he was very glad to hear from her; that he had not heard from he for
                  so <time>long</time> that he thought <persName key="daughter">she</persName> was
                  dead. This is one more reason why <persName key="ethel">Mrs. Robins</persName>
                  believes her former <persName key="Taylor">husband</persName> was a victim of
                  aphasia when he left, after attending the <placeName type="town"
                     >Vanderbilt</placeName> cup races in <date>1908</date>.
                     <persName>Taylor</persName> also, <persName>Mrs. Robins</persName> asserted,
                  was unable to recall friends of their married life, and when their names were
                  mentioned, his face failed to show the slightest signs of remembrance. He did
                  remember, however, favorite dishes of his former wife when he was dining with his
                  daughter, pointing them out to the latter on the menu during their luncheon
                  together. <persName key="ethel">Mrs. Robins</persName> declared that these points
                  proved that his mind, while vague as to consequential facts about <persName
                     key="ethel">her</persName> married life with the <persName key="Taylor"
                     >director</persName>, retained minor details.</p>

               <p> The director's experiences in <placeName type="state">Alaska</placeName> also
                  were set forth in one <objectName type="letter">letter</objectName>. <persName
                     key="Taylor">Taylor</persName> told of how he contracted scurvy, consequently
                  suffering from loss of hair, headaches and neuralgia. Another letter dismissed
                  with a few scornful words <persName key="sands">Sands</persName>, his chauffeur,
                  who is still being sought by <orgName type="law">police</orgName>. The <persName
                     key="Taylor">director</persName> declared <persName key="sands"
                     >Sands</persName> had upset his home and said his name had been forged to
                  checks by his unfaithful servant.</p>

               <p>Signatures <persName key="Taylor">Taylor</persName> used in his letters to his
                     <persName key="daughter">daughter</persName>, for whom he showed deep devotion,
                  were "<persName key="Taylor">Father</persName>" and "<persName key="Taylor">Daddy
                     Pete</persName>." The origin of how <persName key="Taylor">Taylor</persName>
                  came to be known as "<persName key="Taylor">Pete</persName>" was explained by
                     <persName key="ethel">Mrs. Robins</persName>. She said when <persName
                     key="Taylor">Taylor</persName>, or as he was known then, <persName key="Taylor"
                     >Deane-Tanner</persName>, first came to live in <placeName type="city">New
                     York</placeName> he took lodging with several Englishmen.</p>

               <p><persName key="Taylor">Taylor</persName>, always deliberate and calculating in his
                  methods, was nicknamed "<persName key="Taylor">P. D. Q.</persName>," by his
                  roommates, which was quickly shortened to "<persName key="Taylor"
                  >Pete</persName>." The <persName key="Taylor">director's</persName> promise to
                  leave his <objectName type="money">estate</objectName> to his <persName
                     key="daughter">daughter</persName> was contained in a <objectName type="letter"
                     >letter</objectName> written in <date>February, 1920</date>. <persName
                     key="ethel">Mrs. Robins</persName> said her former husband said in this message
                  he thought it would be good policy to leave them both an <objectName type="money"
                     >annuity</objectName>, in addition to telling of his <objectName
                     type="document">will</objectName> bequeathing his <objectName type="money"
                     >estate</objectName> to <persName key="daughter">Ethel Daisy</persName>.</p>

               <p><date>February 7, 1922</date>
                  <orgName type="newspaper">NEW YORK AMERICAN</orgName></p>

               <p> [relating the testimony of <persName key="Taylor">Taylor's</persName>
                  <persName key="ethel">wife</persName> during the divorce <eventName type="divorce"
                     >hearing</eventName> in <date>1911</date>]...<persName key="ethel">Mrs.
                     Tanner</persName>, in her testimony, said she was married on <date>December 7,
                     1901</date>, at the <orgName type="church">Little Church Around the
                     Corner</orgName>. The ceremony was performed by <persName key="reverend">Rev.
                     George C. Houghton</persName>, pastor of the church. Following the marriage the
                  couple went to live at <placeName type="adress">No. 40 Washington Square
                     South</placeName>, and later moved to the <placeName type="hotel">Hotel
                     Colonial</placeName> at <placeName type="street">Columbus Avenue</placeName>
                  and <placeName type="street">Eighty-first street</placeName>, at which time her
                  husband became associated with <orgName type="company">A. J. Crawford &amp;
                     Co.</orgName>, at <placeName type="adress">No. 251 Fifth Avenue</placeName>.
                     <persName key="ethel">Mrs. Deane-Tanner</persName> added:</p>

               <p>"My husband left home at <time>noon</time> on <date>October 23, 1908</date>, and I
                  have never seen him since. The last word received from him was on <date>October
                     26, 1908</date>, when he was stopping at the <placeName>Broadway Central
                     Hotel</placeName>. He sent word to the <orgName type="company">Crawford
                     firm</orgName> asking for a sum of <objectName type="money">money</objectName>.
                  This was sent to him by <persName type="Daniel">Daniel J. Barker</persName>, of
                  the firm. Then he disappeared."</p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
