<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LEAF-VRE/code_snippets/refs/heads/main/CSS/lwc.css"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>HUMN100 FALL 2025: The Murder of William Desmond Taylor</title>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Diane Jakacki</persName>
               <resp>Instructor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Waina Ali</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Jada Alvarez</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Colin Caricato</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>John Cochran</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Lucy DiChristina</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Nick Eisele-Bockelkamp</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Ethan Esclamado</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Spencer Firestone</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Henry Gibbons</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Daniel Hou</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Campbell Killian</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Olivia King</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>William Le</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Charlie Meehleib</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Carter Morton</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Kate Reyen</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Blythe Sena</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Hunter Sloan</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Rylie Smith</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Lily Stein</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Riley Twiss</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Katrina von Behren</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Emma Walkowiak</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Amanda Woertz</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Produced by members of the HUMN100: Introduction to Text Analysis course, Fall
               2025</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>These interviews and statements are gathered from a number of sources, including
               "Taylorology" and Robert Giroux's Deed of Death</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy>
               <category xml:id="actor"/>
               <category xml:id="director"/>
               <category xml:id="studio_employee"/>
               <category xml:id="military"/>
               <category xml:id="law_enforcement"/>
               <category xml:id="legal"/>
               <category xml:id="servant"/>
               <category xml:id="family"/>
               <category xml:id="professional"/>
               <category xml:id="writer"/>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
   </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div type="interview">
            <head>Newspaper Interview with Julia Crawford Ivors</head>
            <byline>Edited by Olivia King</byline>
            <p> April 29, 1922 HONOLULU ADVERTISER Scenario Writer is Seeking Material from Old
               Hawaiian Legends <placeName type="state">Hawaii</placeName> may really find favor in
               the big <placeName type="studio">motion picture studios</placeName> and its wealth of
               legendary lore form the subject of a play or two to be presented to millions of movie
               fans under the name of <persName key="lasky" ref="#writer"> Jesse Lasky</persName>, providing
               <persName key="ivers" ref="#writer">Miss Julia Crawford Ivers</persName>, his foremost scenario
               writer, find the legends and myths appropriate for filming.</p>
            <p><persName key="ivers" ref="#writer">Miss Ivers</persName> arrived on the Matsonia from <placeName
               type="city">Los Angeles</placeName>, accompanied by her secretary, Miss
               Aldrich<persName/>, and although here but three days, she is already delving deep
               into legends and also the history of <placeName type="state">Hawaii</placeName>,
               particularly that relating to old feudal <placeName type="state"
                  >Hawaii</placeName>.</p>
            <p>Whether her readings, her conversations <placeName type="set">with Island</placeName>
               folk acquainted with legends, and her observations, will lead her into the path that
               will eventually open out into the appropriate theme, she does not know, but she has
               hopes.</p>
            <p>To further acquaint herself with <placeName type="set">the Islands</placeName> and to
               absorb the atmosphere of old and new <placeName type="state">Hawaii</placeName>, she
               will visit <placeName type="set">Kauai</placeName> next week, leaving here Monday or
               Tuesday night and remaining a few days on the <placeName type="set">Garden
                  Island</placeName>.</p>
            <p>The following week she will go to <placeName type="set">Hilo</placeName>, taking her
               car, and will motor over to <placeName type="set">Kalapana</placeName>, all through
               <placeName type="set">Puna</placeName>, thence to <placeName type="set">the
                  Volcano</placeName>, and then around to <placeName type="set">Kona</placeName>,
               where she will learn all she can of <placeName type="set">Kealakekua Bay</placeName>,
               the scene of Captain Cook's<persName/> discovery and tragedy; the city of keyuge at
               <placeName type="set">Honaunau</placeName> and may possibly go into <placeName
                  type="set">Kohala</placeName>, which abounds in historic wealth.</p>
            <p><persName key="ivers" ref="#writer">Miss Ivers</persName> says she has been a scenario writer with
               the <persName key="lasky" ref="#writer">Lasky</persName> interest for about eight years and during
               seven years of that time was closely associated in motion <objectName
                  type="possession">picture</objectName> production with <persName key="taylor" ref="#director"
                     >William D. Taylor</persName>, whose tragic death caused a temporary suspension of
               much work planned.</p>
            <p>"<persName key="taylor" ref="#director">Mr. Taylor</persName> was a splendid <objectName
               type="possession">picture</objectName> director," said <persName key="ivers" ref="#writer">Miss
                  Ivers</persName>. "He was a man of fine attainments. He was sympathetic and those
               who worked with and under his direction regarded him as one with whom it was a
               pleasure to be associated.</p>
            <p>"My own work as a scenario writer was pleasurable from the fact that there was
               co-operation. He wanted the best and we desired to give him only the best. He was a
               credit to the motion <objectName type="possession">picture</objectName> service and
               will be a loss to it, for he was of a constructive type, doing the best with the
               highest class of material."</p>
            <p>It was partly because of his death that <persName key="ivers" ref="#writer">Miss Ivers</persName>
               dropped her own activities for a time, superinduced by a cold, resulting in the end
               in a determination to visit <placeName type="state">Hawaii</placeName>, with
               <persName key="lasky" ref="#writer">Mr. Lasky's</persName> injunction that she delve into
               Hawaiian legends and find whether any of them can be filmed.</p>
            <p><persName key="ivers" ref="#writer">Miss Ivers</persName> is at the <placeName type="state">Seaside
               hotel</placeName>. She makes no promises, but is reading much about Hawaii. She is
               dictating morning and afternoon. She is going here and there where details of
               Hawaiian life may be learned.</p>
            <p>If such a motion <objectName type="possession">picture</objectName>play is to be
               written it may not deal entirely with legends, but legends may be woven into a modern
               type of play. The story of the Goddess Pele<persName/>, who dwells in <placeName
                  type="set">Kilauea volcano</placeName>, has attracted much of her attention and
               her own visit to the volcano in a week or so will have that much more interest for
               her. There is a dramatic, tragic, firey element in Pele<persName/> which may be
               converted to the screen, in her opinion.</p>
            <p> Much of <persName key="ivers" ref="#writer">Miss Ivers'</persName> work at the studio in Los
               Angeles is associated directly with literary folk, writers of <objectName
                  type="possession">books</objectName> whose names are known throughout the reading
               world--<persName key="parker" ref="#professional">Sir Gilbert Parker</persName>, <persName
                  key="maugham" ref="#professional">Sydney [sic] Maugham</persName>, <persName key="glyn" ref="#professional">Elinor
                     Glyn</persName> and many others. It is <persName key="ivers" ref="#writer">Miss Ivers</persName>
               who takes their <objectName type="possession">books</objectName> and prepares or
               directs the preparation of scenarios for the director.</p>
            <p>It is this contact between the scenario writer and the authors that counts for
               success or failure in the motion <objectName type="possession">picture</objectName>
               product. If the scenario writer is sympathetic and endeavors to get the soul of the
               author's intent, there are exceptional possibilities. If not, there is more likely to
               be a failure in the interpretation.</p>
            <p> Many <objectName type="possession">books</objectName> to be screened must be ripped
               to pieces. As the story is written it can seldom be filmed. The change is the task of
               the scenario writer.</p>
            <p>Life must have been lived by scenario writers to really interpret a story for the
               screen for the eyes of the millions of theater patrons. Phases of life that are near
               the raw edge of actuality and realism may not be interpreted by the old maid who has
               not seen life and whose first impulse, and probably her last, is to eliminate that
               particular phase. A man of sensual thought may regard that particular phase as one to
               work into a maudlin interpretation which would be offensive.</p>
            <p> Between these two extremes there is the middle course and that path must be taken by
               the writer who understands life and understands the multiplicity of types and
               characters that patronize the theaters.</p>
            <p>
               <persName key="ivers" ref="#writer">Miss Ivers</persName> is a hard worker. She maintains high
               ideals as to <objectName type="possession">picture</objectName> production. Hers is a
               constant study of human nature. Philosophy and psychology are tangible factors with
               her, for both play important parts in decisions as to the worth of stories and the
               filmed product.</p>
            <p>"I must necessarily write in dashes where authors employ sentences and paragraphs,"
               said <persName key="ivers" ref="#writer">Miss Ivers</persName> discussing her method of writing. "I
               cull and cut, where book writers must enlarge and pad."</p>
         </div>
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
