<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>HUMN100 FALL 2025: The Murder of William Desmond taylor</title>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Diane Jakacki</persName>
               <resp>Instructor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Waina Ali</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Jada Alvarez</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Colin Caricato</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>John Cochran</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Lucy DiChristina</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Nick Eisele-Bockelkamp</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Ethan Esclamado</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Spencer Firestone</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Henry Gibbons</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Daniel Hou</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Campbell Killian</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Olivia King</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>William Le</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Charlie Meehleib</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Carter Morton</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Kate Reyen</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Blythe Sena</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Hunter Sloan</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Rylie Smith</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Lily Stein</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Riley Twiss</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Katrina von Behren</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Emma Walkowiak</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Amanda Woertz</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Produced by members of the HUMN100: Introduction to Text Analysis course, Fall
               2025</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>These interviews and statements are gathered from a number of sources, including
               "taylorology" and Robert Giroux's Deed of Death</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy>
               <category xml:id="actor"/>
               <category xml:id="director"/>
               <category xml:id="studio_employee"/>
               <category xml:id="military"/>
               <category xml:id="law_enforcement"/>
               <category xml:id="legal"/>
               <category xml:id="servant"/>
               <category xml:id="family"/>
               <category xml:id="professional"/>
               <category xml:id="writer"/>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="interview">

            <head><title>STATEMENT OF MISS MARY MILES MINTER. G.H BOONE OFFICIAL REPORTER IN THE DISTRICT
               ATTORNEY'S OFFICE, February 7, 1922, at five o'clock P.M.</title></head>

            <p>PRESENT: <persName key="doran" ref="#law_enforcement" role="investigator">Mr. W.C.
                  Doran,</persName> Deputy District Attorney, <persName key="minter" ref="#actor"
                  role="business romantic">Miss Mary Miles Minter,</persName>
               <persName key="mott" ref="#legal" role="investigator">John G. Mott,</persName>
               attorney for Miss Minter, and <persName key="boone" ref="#law_enforcement"
                  role="business">G. H. Boone,</persName> shorthand reporter.</p>
            <div type="section" n="1">

               <byline resp="editor">Section #1 edited by Waina A</byline>

               <p>Questions by <persName key="doran" ref="#law_enforcement" role="investigator">Mr.
                     Doran</persName>: </p>

               <p> DORAN: How long have you known <persName key="taylor">Mr taylor</persName>?</p>

               <p>MINTER: Since <date when="1919-07">July of 1919</date> -- yes, that is correct. </p>

               <p> DORAN: He has been your director in pictures, has he? </p>

               <p> MINTER: Yes we commenced this <orgName type="company">company</orgName> together. </p>

               <p> DORAN: Did you have occasion to call on him at <placeName type="residence">his
                     residence</placeName> within <date type="month"> the last thirty days</date>
                  prior to his death? -- approximately <date type="month"> thirty days?</date>
               </p>

               <p> MINTER: Just a moment, will you --</p>

               <p> DORAN: Let me change the question. When was the last time you called on him at
                     <placeName type="taylorshouse">his residence</placeName>? </p>

               <p> MINTER: On the <date type="murderday">23rd of December.</date>
               </p>
               <p>DORAN: Were you alone at that time or did others accompany you to see him? </p>

               <p> MINTER: I was alone. </p>

               <p> DORAN: Was any one else there?</p>

               <p>MINTER: no, not a soul. </p>

               <p>DORAN: Was <persName key="Sands" ref="#servant" role="employee">his
                     valet</persName>, the colored man, there, do you know?</p>

               <p>MINTER: Not that I know of. </p>

               <p> DORAN: Prior to that time, was it your habit to call on him at his residence or
                  had it been your habit?</p>

               <p>MINTER: I couldn't call it a habit, but <date type="severaloccasions">on several
                     occasions</date> I did call upon him, though never as·1ate as upon this
                  occasion.</p>

               <p>DORAN: Now, on this last occasion, whet time of the day or night was it that you
                  called? </p>

               <p>MINTER: May l tell this in my own way? </p>

               <p>DORAN: Yes, I would rather have you tell it in your own way, if you will.</p>

               <p> MINTER: I am glad to. I am trying to answer as I would in court and 1 don't like
                  to do so. </p>

               <p> DORAN: Just proceed, go ahead and tell it in your own way.</p>

               <p>MINTER: I had gone to <objectName type="furniture">bed</objectName>; I hadn't seen
                     <persName key="taylor">Mr taylor</persName> in <date type="fivemonthsago">five
                     months</date> at the time -- <date>three months,</date> I know; three months,
                  and I just got to thinking about it and I decided I couldn't stand it any longer.
                  I was going to go up and tell him "goodbye. I got up and dressed, went down to my
                     <placeName type="house">grandmother's room</placeName> and I said, <persName
                     key="cshelby">"Mama,</persName> I am going over to say 'goodbye' to Mr taylor,"
                  and she advised me not to do it. She said it was too late: "Do you know it is
                  nearly <time type="12oclock">twelve o'clock?</time>" she said. I said, "Yes, sure,
                  but I just must do so," I said, "I realize that this is not the usual thing and I
                  have never been there so late, but I must do so, Mama. I am going to give him a
                     <objectName type="letter">letter</objectName> in whioh I have told him
                  'goodbye,"' She said, "All right, then, if you must. I would get up and go with
                  you, but I don't feel well enough," Mama often accompanied me on <eventName
                     type="Mary'strips">my trips</eventName>, which were not very many during the
                  entire time that i knew him. So I went over there and arrived at <time
                     type="11:55">five minutes to twelve</time>, I am strange about that, I am
                  rather queer about that, I think of the time; every time I was with him I would
                  say, "Well, this time yesterday I didn't see him and today I am with him," and
                  things like that. So I <time>arrived at five minutes to twelve</time> and left at
                     t<time type="12:40">twenty minutes to one</time>, and-- Do you wish me to tell
                  you all that transpired? </p>
               <p> DORAN: Never mind about that. </p>

               <p> DORAN: Your <persName key="grandmother" ref="family" role="family"
                     >grandmother</persName> didn't accompany you?</p>

               <p> MINTER: No, she did not. </p>

               <p>DORAN: Your <persName key="chaffeur" ref="#servant" role="business"
                     >chauffeur</persName> drove you there? </p>

               <p>MINTER: No, I drove myself in my little <objectName type="car">car</objectName>,
                  little run-about.</p>

               <p> DORAN: That was <date type="Dec23rd">December 23d</date>? </p>

               <p> MINTER: Yes,<date> December 23rd.</date></p>

               <p> DORAN: When was the last time you saw him prior to that? </p>

               <p> MINTER: I couldn't give you the exact date, but I know it was at <date>least
                     three months and a little over; it was over three months.</date></p>

               <p>DORAN: During the three months prior to December 23d, did you ever meet him
                  anywhere.</p>

               <p> MINTER: No. You mean casually or see him really to talk to? I saw him, yes. </p>

               <p>DORAN: See him and meet him, to be with him? </p>
               <p>MINTER: No; no, indeed. I passed him at <placeName type="studio"> Lasky Studio
                  </placeName> when I go over there. Sometimes I have seen <objectName
                     type="vehicle">his car</objectName> go down <placeName type="street"> Western
                     Avenue,</placeName> but I hadn't seen him to speak to in <date
                     type="threemonthsago">three months</date>.</p>

               <p> DORAN: As I understand it, you were sincerely in love with him?</p>

               <p> MINTER: That is true.</p>

               <p> DORAN: Did you convey that feeling to him?</p>

               <p>MINTER: Absolutely.</p>

               <p> DORAN: You told him, did you?</p>

               <p>MINTER: Absolutely. He loved me; he told me so.</p>

               <p>DORAN: Were you engaged to be married?</p>

               <p>MINTER: No, we were not.</p>

               <p> DORAN: <eventName type="timeofdeath">At the time of his death</eventName>, it was
                  --</p>

               <p> MR. MOTT: Right there at that point you might explain about the rising sun, with
                  reference to your engagement. I think that explains the attitude between both of
                  you. </p>

               <p>MINTER: I don't know just which to do, whether to tell you this whole thing, go
                  right along and talk. I can easily do that. </p>

               <p>MR. MOTT: He asked if you were engaged to him. Tell him about the "rising sun"
                  explanation. </p>

               <p> MINTER: I can tell you the whole thing better without being asked.</p>

               <p> MR. DORAN: Yes. Go ahead. and tell us in your own way all about it.</p>

               <p> MINTER: I had always known that this was just<eventName> an exquisite chapter in
                     my life</eventName> that must necessarily be a brief one: I couldn't bear to
                  part with it; it was just a beautiful thing that seldom occurs in the. world today
                  as I see it, as it is forced upon me. It as simply a beautiful white flame; I met
                     <persName key="taylor">him</persName>; I had always been a <persName>reserved,
                     very retiring young girl</persName>, and he was the first man and the only man
                  who ever embodied all the glories of manhood in one private body. He represented
                  that to me. He never by look, by word or by deed gave me any reason to doubt any
                  of my ideals that were placed in him absolutely. At the time our love first
                  formulated he said to me, "Mary, this is not right. You are May and I am December,
                  and this is not right. I know it is best that we must part." This was at the very
                  beginning of it, and I said, "Of course, I don't want to do any immodest or bold
                  thing; I couldn't try to withhold a person's love for me who didn't care for me.""
                  I said, "I know that you are many years older than I, but I couldn't love anybody
                  as I love you. I simply love you. And we did try to part, We tried it again and
                  again, and then he would beoome ill. At one time I had almost resolved to see him
                  no more, and he was taken ill and nobody else cared, [page 6] really cared whether
                  he ate his <objectName>dinner</objectName> or whether he dressed warm1y enough,
                  whether he took care of himself, and I couldn't bear for him to suffer. It was not
                  only a love of sweetheart, but I wanted to be his nurse. I wanted to hold his head
                  when it was aching. I wanted him to tell me his mental troubles, his heart
                  troubles, and let me soothe them away for him as I would for a little child. I
                  forgot the man's age; it meant nothing to me. The only thing I wanted was to serve
                  him as I would have served the Lord or a little child, and then it just passed
                  away; for months at a time I wouldn't see him and I didn't know why. Finally, I
                  decided there was no use; it must come to an end and I went there on the night of
                  the 23d to give him this letter telling him "goodbye." I had reason to believe, in
                  the awful vernacular of the day, that it was over anyway, but I went there to say
                  "goodbye" myself. He said, "It is rather late, isn't it, Mary?" when he opened the
                  door. I said, "Yes, but don't you realize that I had to come to see you? You know
                  Mama has been sick for three months and you have been ill and I have been
                  frightfully worried and you haven't even had the kindness to call me to tell me
                  that you were i11 and that I must not expect to see you to tell mo that things are
                  all right." </p>

               <p> I said, "I don't care if you don't wish to see me, because it hurts me, but it
                  wouldn't have hurt one-millionth as much if you had just explained to me and not
                  leave me in the dark." He said, "Mary, I couldn't help it; I couldn't help it and
                  I can't explain it to you." Oh, I don't know! I have told this thing so many
                  times, Mr Doran, that the words just - I can't tell it even as it is; I can't even
                  express it to you as it really is. There is so much more to it.</p>
               <p> </p>
               <p>MR DORAN: At that time, on <date type="Dec23rd">December 23d,</date> let's see, he
                  was killed on <date ref="Feb1st">February 1st</date>. Who was directing you then? </p>
               <p>MINTER: Why, no one was. I had finished a picture.</p>

               <p> DORAN: Who directed the last one?</p>
            </div>

            <div type="section" n="2">
               <byline resp="editor">Section #2 edited by Jada Alvarez</byline>
               <p>MINTER: My last director was <persName key="urson" ref="#director" role="business"
                     >Frank Urson</persName>. <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">Mr.
                     Taylor</persName> so often, often made the remark to me that he wished tbat he
                  were younger; he wanted to be younger. We undoubtedly would have been married
                  today bnd he been younger. <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">He</persName>
                  explained our not. being engaged in that way. I knew we never could be married; I
                  also knew I never would love for another human being in the way I cared for him.
                  So he would say, "You know, <persName key="minter" ref="#actor" role="romantic"
                     >Mary</persName>, to me you are the morning sun, bright, beaut1ful, and with
                  the world and a futune before you, and I am the setting sun, and don't you see, my
                  dear, it simply cannot be. I hope tbat doesn't give you the impression that I
                  begged him to marry me. I never did in my life. I couldn't do that. I never even
                  called him <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">"Billie"</persName> in my life.
                  The man was too wonderful for that. He was wonderful. I don't care what anybody
                  says or what they prove against him. I knew him as the finest thing in the world. </p>

               <p> MR MOTT: <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">He</persName> as the embodyment
                  of your ideal? </p>

               <p>MINTER: Yes, and I can aay now that I can't truthfully -- I don't know any of
                  those ugly things which have been aaid about him. I never found him so. He was
                  glorious to me. </p>

               <p> MR DORAN: I read in the <objectName type="document">paper</objectName> where you
                  had been <eventName type="major">engaged</eventName> to some other man.</p>

               <p>MINTER: To <persName key="dickson" ref="#professional" role="uknown">Mr
                     Dickson</persName>. That is not entirely true.</p>

               <p>DORAN: What is his first name?</p>

               <p> MINTER: <persName key="dickson" ref="#professional" role="uknown">Thomas
                     Dickson</persName>.</p>

               <p>DORAN: Someone besides him, a director in the movies.</p>

               <p>MINTER: <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business">Marshall
                     Neilan</persName>, <eventName type="major">engaged</eventName> to him?</p>

               <p>DORAN: Yes, <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business">Marshall
                     Neilan</persName>. Didn't I read in the <objectName type="document"
                     >papers</objectName> that you had been engaged to him and the <eventName
                     type="major">engagement</eventName> had been broken off? </p>

               <p>MINTER: That is not true. <persName key="dickson" ref="#professional"
                     role="uknown">Mr Dickson</persName> is the only one to whom I have been even
                  remotely engaged, and that was a freak of despondency.</p>

               <p>DORAN: What about <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business">Marshall
                     Neilan</persName>? Were you engaged to him?</p>

               <p>MINTER: No.</p>

               <p>DORAN: Had you been going with <persName key="neilan" ref="#director"
                     role="business">Marshall Neilan</persName> during, say the last <date>thirty or
                     sixty days prior</date> to <persName key="taylor">Taylor's</persName>
                  death?</p>

               <p>MINTER: Going with <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">him</persName>?</p>

               <p>DORAN: Had you been out anywhere with <persName key="taylor" ref="#director"
                     >him</persName>? </p>

               <p>MINTER: Yes; he had been to see me; I had been out with <persName key="taylor"
                     ref="#director">him</persName>; I am not sure whether it was within the
                     <date>thirty days</date> or not, but in the <date>last two months</date>, yes
                  sir; but going with him no more than I had for years off and on. <persName
                     key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business">Mr Neilan's</persName> traits
                  [page 9] are well known; he comes to see you, and we are always glad to receive
                  him, but we never know how long he is going to stay with us or how long he was
                  going to stay with this one or that one. He flits here and there like a swallow.
                  We are all charmed with his personality, but don't take him seriously. </p>
               <p>DORAN: Has <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">he</persName> proposed to
                  you?</p>

               <p>MINTER: Must I answer that? Yes, he did.</p>

               <p>DORAN: Do you recall approximately when it was?</p>

               <p>MINTER: About <date>two months ago</date>.</p>

               <p>DORAN: That would take it to <date>December 1st</date>, approximately or in the
                  middle of December?</p>

               <p>MINTER: Well, I think it was after that, Yes -- No, let me see, <date>December
                     1st</date> -- I wish I could tell you.</p>

               <p>DORAN: With keyerence to this <date>December 23d</date> that you called on
                     <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">Taylor</persName>, when was it?</p>

               <p>MINTER: It as before the <date>1st of December</date>, I think.</p>

               <p>DORAN: Q. Before the <date>1st of December</date>?</p>

               <p>MINTER: Yes; about the <date>last of November</date>. </p>

               <p>DORAN: And you, of course, rejected im, I suppose?</p>

               <p>MINTER: Yes; that is, I didn't exactly say, "No, I will not marry you." I didn't
                  take him seriously. I joked with <persName key="taylor" ref="#director"
                     >him</persName> at the time.</p>

               <p>DORAN: Did <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">he</persName> seem to be
                  serious?</p>

               <p>MINTER: You never know. I couldn't say whether ee was serious or not. I thought
                  possibly he was joking, or had a few <objectName type="consumable"
                     >cocktails</objectName>.</p>

               <p>DORAN: How many times after that did <persName key="taylor" ref="#director"
                     >he</persName> mention the subject to you?</p>

               <p>MINTER: He didn't mention the subject. "May I marry you" again; he didn't say
                  that, but he has been on very friendly terms with me and then suddenly go away to
                     <placeName type="city">San Francisco</placeName>. and I wouldn't hear from him
                  and I would remark, "Isn't that just like <persName key="neilan" ref="#director"
                     role="business">Marshall?</persName>" and thought no more of it. </p>
               <p>DORAN: Well, but along toward the last <date>thirty days</date> prior to <persName
                     key="taylor" ref="#director">Taylor's</persName>
                  <eventName type="major">death</eventName>, he seemed to be quite devoted to you,
                  did <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">he</persName> not?</p>

               <p>MINTER: No; I can't really say that he did. As for being with him, wasn't with
                     <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">him</persName> very much.</p>

               <p>DORAN: Didn't you observe in him some jealousy?</p>

               <p>MINTER: Oh, no; No, I can't say that. He was not jealous of me. He is the least
                  jealous man I ever met. He takes life too much -- </p>
               <p>DORAN: Did <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">he</persName> ever say anything
                  to you about <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">Taylor</persName>?</p>

               <p>MINTER: Yes, we have discussed him many times; he loved him. <persName
                     key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business">Marshall Neilan</persName> loved
                     <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">Mr Taylor</persName>.</p>

               <p>DORAN: Did he ever bring any tales to you for which <persName key="taylor"
                     ref="#director">Taylor</persName> was supposed to have been responsible!</p>

               <p>MINTER: Not until recently.</p>

               <p>DORAN: When was that?</p>

               <p>MINTER: <date>Last Friday night</date>; whereupon we had a severe quarrel. I
                  didn't believe him.</p>

               <p>DORAN: <date>Friday night</date>
                  <time>after</time> the <eventName type="major">killing</eventName>?</p>

               <p>MINTER: Yes.</p>

               <p>DORAN: Or <time>before</time> the <eventName type="major">killing</eventName>?</p>

               <p>MINTER: No; after.</p>

               <p>DORAN: Did he ever say anything like that to you <time>before</time> the
                     <eventName type="major">killing</eventName>?</p>

               <p>MINTER: No, indeed he did not; he knew that I loved <persName key="taylor"
                     ref="#director">Mr Taylor</persName> and he had known it.</p>

               <p>DORAN: Did he ever comment on that relation between you and <persName key="taylor"
                     ref="#director">Taylor</persName>?</p>

               <p>MINTER: No, <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">he</persName> did not; I
                  wouldn't have permitted him to; and I didn't comment on his.</p>

               <p>DORAN: I will use the word "quarrel," but that may be exaggerated; did you ever
                     <eventName type="fight">quarrel</eventName> with <persName key="neilan"
                     ref="#director" role="business">Neilan</persName> over <persName key="taylor"
                     ref="#director">Taylor</persName>? </p>
               <p>MINTER: Absolutely not; absolutely not. <persName key="neilan" ref="#director"
                     role="business">Marshall</persName> is the typification of the happy-go-lucky
                  Irish spirit and tempera­ment. <persName key="taylor" ref="#director"
                     >He</persName> does perfectly terrible things to everybody, but everybody loves
                  him. They are always glad to see him again. As to harboring any deep-seated
                  malice, I don't believe <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">he</persName> is
                  capable of it. </p>
               <p>DORAN: Could he have assumed at any time you and <persName key="taylor"
                     ref="#director">he</persName>, you and <persName key="neilan" ref="#director"
                     >Marshall Neilan</persName> -- I am speaking of <persName key="neilan"
                     ref="#director" role="business">Marshall Neilan</persName> now -- Could he have
                  assumed at any time that <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">he</persName>
                  might be or was engaged to you by reason of your relations wtth him? </p>
               <p>MINTER: Could <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business">Marshall
                     Neilan</persName> have assumed that <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">Mr
                     Taylor</persName> and I were engaged?</p>

               <p>DORAN: No, no; that you and <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business"
                     >Marshall Neilan</persName> were enqaged?</p>

               <p>MINTER: No.</p>

               <p>DORAN: Did you ever give <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">him</persName> the
                  impression that he might some day be successful in his effort to marry you?</p>

               <p>MINTER: Not in my own knowledge. If I have, it was more or less of a joking way. I
                  think I have at times said, "Well, <persName key="neilan" ref="#director"
                     role="business">Marshall</persName>, when are we going all around the world on
                  our honey-moon?" exactly in the same manner as I took him to say, "Now, when you
                  are my wedded bride we will do" so-and­-so. <persName key="neilan" ref="#director"
                     role="business">Marshall</persName> has done that time after time. </p>
               <p>DORAN: Might he not have taken you seriously? </p>

               <p>MINTER: I don't think so.</p>

               <p>DORAN: Do you know <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">he</persName> did
                  not?</p>

               <p>MINTER: No, I don't know that <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">he</persName>
                  did not.</p>

               <p>DORAN: Don't you know that <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">he</persName>
                  was really -- Don't you feel that <persName key="taylor" ref="#director"
                     >he</persName> was really in love with you?</p>

               <p>MINTER: I can't truthfully answer "Yes" or "no" to that, beoause I don't know; I
                  am not sure enough of <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business">Mr
                     Neilan's</persName> nature. While I have known him a great many years, well, I
                  will say I have known him <date>several years</date>, he is the type who flits
                  back and forth, you know. - When you really think you know him he turns to
                  something else, and I don't know, so I have never permitted myself to form any
                  conclusions on his character; I don't know whether he has ever taken me seriously
                  or not. I always treated <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">him</persName>
                  more or less in a joking manner. </p>

            </div>

            <div type="section" n="3">
               <byline>Section #3 edited by Johnny Cochran</byline>
               <p> DORAN: I understand the <date type="dark">night of the murder</date> you were
                  with <persName key="neilan" ref="#professional" role="social">Mr
                  Neilan</persName>. </p>

               <p>MINTER: No, I was not. I was at <placeName type="residence">home</placeName> with
                  my <persName key="miles" ref="#family" role="unknown">grandmother</persName> and
                     <persName key="sister" ref="#family" role="unknown">sister</persName>. </p>

               <p> DORAN: I mean after the <eventName type="death">murder</eventName>, after you
                  learned of the <eventName type="death">murder</eventName>.</p>

               <p> MINTER: Yes, <date type="end">Friday</date>. </p>

               <p> DORAN: The next <date type="dark">night</date>, was it?</p>

               <p> MINTER: No, it was the <date type="friday">night after Thursday</date>. <persName
                     key="neilan" ref="#professional" role="business">Mr Neilan</persName> -- I mean
                     <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">Mr Taylor</persName> was found dead
                     <date type="early">Thursday morning</date>, was he not? </p>

               <p> DORAN: Yes.</p>

               <p> MINTER: <date>Thursday</date> was such a long day. <time>Friday night</time> I
                  saw <persName key="neilan" ref="#professional" role="business">Mr.
                     Neilan</persName>.</p>

               <p> DORAN: Did he. communicate w1 th you or you with him? </p>

               <p> MINTER: Why, he communicated with me; he tried to, but it was because of me he
                  did that. On <time>Thuraday night</time> I was worried about <persName
                     key="taylor" ref="#director">Mr Taylor</persName>; I was worried about
                     <persName key="neilan" ref="#professional" role="business">Mr Neilan</persName>
                  and called <persName key="mother" ref="#family" role="unknown">Marshall's
                     mother</persName>.</p>

               <p> DORAN: This was after the <eventName type="death">murder</eventName>?</p>

               <p> A Yes, this vas <time>Thursday night</time> after the <eventName type="murder"
                     >murder</eventName>. I said, "Please tell <persName key="mickey" ref="#family"
                     role="uknown">Mickey</persName> not to drive that <objectName type="vehicle"
                     >green car</objectName> so reckless; I am so afraid that he, too, will fall
                  into trouble. And she thanked me and said, "I will tell him. That is just exactly
                  what I havebeen thinking lately myself, and I want to see you soon, <persName
                     key="minter" ref="#actor" role="business">Mary</persName>." With that I thought
                  no more about it. In fact, I didn't even think [page 14] <persName key="neilan"
                     ref="#professional" role="business">Marshall</persName> would call me. He had
                  not caled me in three week or more. 1 thought no more about it and I was surprised
                  the <date>next day</date> to learn -- yes, <date>Friday</date> -- that he had
                  tried to get me at <time>five-thirty</time>. My <persName key="sister"
                     ref="#family" role="uknown">sister</persName> was at our old <placeName
                     type="residence">home</placeName> where there is a <objectName
                     type="communication">telephone</objectName>. The present <placeName
                     type="residence">home</placeName> has no <objectName type="communication"
                     >telephone</objectName>, and when he happened to call there she was there.</p>

               <p> DORAN: At <time>five-thirty</time> of what day? </p>

               <p> MINTER: <date>Friday</date>; and he ea1d he ms very anxious to see me. She knew I
                  had left and wass driving with <persName key="scarborough" ref="#law_enforcement"
                     role="social">George Scarborough</persName>, and she said she didn't know what
                  time 1 would be back. He said well, he wanted me to come to see him before
                     <time>ten o'clock</time>, but after <time>ten o'clock</time> he would be on
                  location. He didn't say the <placeName type="station">Salt Lake
                     Station</placeName>, but he was very anxious to get hold of me before <time>ten
                     o'clock</time>. I came in after <time>ten</time> and they all told me l had
                  better call <persName key="neilan" ref="#professional" role="business"
                     >Marshall</persName>; he seemed very anxious to get hold of me. I didn't· know
                  where to call him; I thought possibly he would come to the <placeName
                     type="residence">house</placeName>. I I were you I would call him up or at
                  1east call <persName key="mother" ref="#family" role="unknown">his
                     mother</persName> and find out where he is." I called the <placeName
                     type="studio">studio</placeName> and the <persName key="watchman">night
                     watchman</persName> immediately said, "<persName key="neilan"
                     ref="#professional" role="business">Mr Neilan</persName> is not here; is this
                     <persName key="minter" ref="#actor">Miss Minter</persName>?" I said, "Yes."</p>

               <p> And he said, "<persName key="neilan" ref="#professional"> Mr Neilan</persName> ia
                  at the <placeName type="station">Salt Lake Station</placeName>." <persName
                     key="scarborough" ref="#law_enforcement">Mr Scarborough</persName> and l drove
                  down there in my runabout. He was very hard at work and had been all
                     <time>night</time>, it seemed he had [page 15] been working all night for four
                  nights past. They were all just dead tired. <time>Night and day</time> they had
                  been working. He finished about <time>two-thirty</time>, and then there were
                  several in the party, <persName key="swanson" ref="#professional" role="social"
                     >Gloria Swanson</persName>, <persName key="jpickford" ref="#professional"
                     role="social">Jack Pickford</persName>, <persName key="urson"
                     ref="#professional">Frank Urson</persName> -- <persName key="urson">Mr Frank
                     Urson</persName> is now associated with <persName key="neilan">Mr
                     Neilan</persName> as <persName key="director">director</persName> -- and
                     <persName key="neilan" ref="#professional" role="business">Marshall</persName>
                  and myself. We went to his <placeName type="residence">mother's home</placeName>
                  where he lives with <persName key="mother">his mother</persName> and we tried to
                  make <objectName type="eggs">eggs</objectName> and things. It was very amusing; we
                  only had four <objectName type="eggs">eggs</objectName>, and I tried to fry two of
                  them and ruined the <objectName type="things">things</objectName>, adn we didn't
                  have enough to go around and we made so much noise <persName key="mother"
                     ref="#family" role="unknown">his mother</persName>, who was ill <placeName
                     type="location">upstairs</placeName>, told us we must behave ourselves.
                     <persName key="neilan" ref="#professional">Marshall</persName> said, "There is
                  only one thing to do; I have got to talk to you. We have had all of this
                  foolishness, and I have got something very important to say to you, <persName
                     key="minter" ref="#actor" role="romantic business">Mary</persName>. Let's drive
                  to the <placeName type="studio">studio</placeName> where we can talk." We drove
                  down to the <placeName type="studio">Hollywood studio</placeName> and we sat there
                  in the <placeName type="office">office</placeName>, the <objectName type="lights"
                     >lights</objectName> burning and the <persName key="watchman" ref="#military"
                     role="unknown">watchman</persName> was there and the <persName
                     key="property man" ref="#military" role="unknown">property man</persName> was
                  not around. He was outside. We talked until <time>dawn</time>; it was
                     <time>dawn</time> when we came out of the <placeName type="office"
                     >place</placeName>.</p>

               <p> DORAN: What were you talking about?</p>

               <p> MINTER: About <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">Mr taylor</persName> and
                  letters <persName key="neilan" ref="#professional" role="business">Marshall
                     Neilan</persName> had tried to get for me.</p>

               <p> DORAN: Who had tried to get for you?</p>

               <p> MINTER: <persName key="neilan" ref="#professional">Marshall</persName> had tried
                  to get for me, which was the first inkling I knew of his knowledge of my
                     <objectName type="document">letters</objectName>, that I had written any to
                     <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">Mr taylor</persName>. He told me certain
                  very, very [page 16]ghastly things have since been proven absolutely true. He told
                  them to me in my interest, but they made me very furious at the time, and we left
                  more or less in a quarrel.</p>

               <p> DORAN: Will you please tell us everything that he told you there?</p>

               <p> MINTER: Yes, indeed. He first said, "<persName key="minter" ref="#actor"
                     >Mary</persName>, sit down. I have something very importnat to tell you." I sat
                  down, and he said, "You know this <eventName type="death">murder</eventName> of
                     <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">Bill</persName> is going to be the
                  greatest nine-days wonder" or "nineteen-days wonder that we have ever had,
                  certainly that <placeName type="city">Los Angeles</placeName> ever had. You don't
                  know what a terrible thing it is going to be." I said, "Yes, I do. It is awful!"
                  He said, "Now, <persName key="minter" ref="#actor" role="romantic business"
                     >Mary</persName>, I tried to get your <objectName type="document"
                     >letters</objectName>" --</p>

               <p> DORAN: May I interrupt you a moment? What time did you arrive at his <placeName
                     type="studio">studio</placeName>?</p>

               <p> MINTER: We left location, he worked down at the <placeName type="station">Salt
                     Lake Station</placeName>, about <time>two-thirty to a quarter to three</time>,
                  we left there and went to his <placeName type="residence">house</placeName>. How
                  long we were there I couldn't say; I didn't have a <objectName type="watch"
                     >watch</objectName>; I imagine we were there about an hour or maybe more, and
                  then we went on down to the <placeName type="studio">studio</placeName> and we
                  stayed until <time>dawn</time>, whatever time that is. We then came on back to my
                     <objectName type="residence">house</objectName>. <persName key="mother"
                     ref="#family" role="unknown">Mother</persName> was waiting for us and we got
                  out and explained to her. <persName key="mother" ref="#family">Mother</persName>
                  knew he had had a verious talk and she felt sure <persName key="neilan"
                     ref="#professional" role="business">Marhsall</persName> would try to come to
                  our aid. My <persName key="mother">mother</persName> is very fond of <persName
                     key="neilan" ref="#professional" role="business">Mr Neilan</persName> and the
                  whole family. He said he was just dead tired. The man took his hours when hee
                  needed sleep to tell me these things. He was going to be up at <time>eight
                     o'clock</time> that morning and he didn't even go to bed that night. He just
                  sat up in his clothes and went out to work again at <time>eight o'clock</time>.
                  Anyway, he said, "I tried to get your <objectName type="document"
                     >letters</objectName> for you. You know they are a very important factor in the
                     <eventName type="case">case</eventName>, if they get hold of them." I was
                  shocked to find that he knew of my <objectName type="document"
                     >letters</objectName>. I said that I wrote some, and he said something about
                  going to a newspaper or getting hold of <persName key="person">some
                     body</persName> in <placeName type="city">Pasadena</placeName> to get me the
                     <objectName type="letters">letters</objectName>. That part is not clear in my
                  mind. I think I was so tired at the time I couldn't understand him. I haven't seen
                  him since or I would have questioned him again about the <objectName
                     type="document">letters</objectName> just what he did. He told me I should have
                  received them that <date>day</date>. He asked me if I had gotten them and I said,
                  "No, I haven't received the <objectName type="document">letters</objectName>
                  <date>today</date>." He said, "Well, I sent them to the <placeName type="studio"
                     >studio</placeName>, and I believe the studio," the <placeName type="studio"
                     >Realart Studio</placeName> where I had last worked. He said, "They are in
                     <persName key="eyton" ref="#studio_employee">Charley Eyton's</persName> hands
                  now." He either said <persName key="eyton" ref="#studio_employee" role="business"
                     >Charley Eyton</persName> or <persName key="carbut" ref="#studio_employee"
                     role="business">Mr Carbut</persName>, but I can't state this acutally because I
                  was so tired at the time I could hardly hear him and I was desperately interested
                  to hear what he said about the <objectName type="document">letter</objectName>,
                  and I strained all my nerves to hear, but instead it came back and forth; it was
                  hazy. I don't know the exact words he spoke. Anyway, I remember saying, "Well,
                  there is nothing in the <objectName type="document">letters</objectName> that the
                  world can't read except that it is horribly painful to me to have them read my
                     <objectName>letters</objectName> to him." He said, "You loved
                     <persName>Billie</persName>, didn't you?" I said, "Yes, <persName key="neilan"
                     ref="#professional" role="business">Marshall</persName>, I loved him deeply and
                  sincerely." And he said, "Did you ever want to marry him?" Whereupon I replied, I
                  said, "No, no; I know it couldn't have been. It was not meant to be." Then we
                  talked about -- Oh, yes. Then he said, "Now, <persName key="minter" ref="#actor"
                     role="romantic business">Mary</persName>, I am going to tell you some very
                  important thing; they are going to hurt you, going to shock you, but before I say
                  a word I want you to consider <persName key="taylor" ref="#director"
                     >Billie</persName> was just as crazy as a March hare months before his death."
                  He said, "I am going to recite a few instances that <persName key="taylor"
                     ref="#director">Bill</persName> told me about, things irrelevant to you, to
                  show he didn't do this only to you but to others of his very <persName
                     key="person">best friends</persName>." </p>

               <p>
                  <persName key="neilan" ref="#professional" role="business">Marshall</persName> and
                     <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">Mr taylor</persName> were extremely good
                  friends. I don't think they saw each other often, but they were most
                  affectionately fond of each other. He said, "On several occasions <persName
                     key="taylor" ref="#director">Bill</persName>" -- he spoke of him as '<persName
                     key="taylor" ref="#director">Bill</persName>' -- "has confessed to me that --
                  Oh, I am so tired I can't think how I am trying­ to say it. He came up to my
                     <placeName type="house">room in the club</placeName> one day and he said, "Oh,
                  I know something about you, <persName key="neilan" ref="#professional"
                     role="business">Marshall</persName>, and those <objectName type="cigarettes"
                     >gold-tipped cigarettes</objectName> I found of yours." Whereupon <persName
                     key="neilan" ref="#professional" role="business">Marshall</persName> said he
                  replied, "Well, you needn't say anything, <persName key="taylor" ref="#director"
                     >Bill</persName>" -- l don't know what it was, a <objectName type="cigar"
                     >cigar</objectName> or something of some personal nature that he recognized of
                     <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">Mr taylor's</persName> at somebody's
                     <placeName type="residence">house</placeName>. I don't know whose <placeName
                     type="residence">house</placeName>. He said, "That makes us Elks. Don't you say
                  anything about me, what I have been doing in a joking, friendly manner." <persName
                     key="taylor" ref="#director">Mr taylor</persName>, he said, suddenly stood up
                  and looked at him very seriously, soberly, and said, "<persName key="taylor"
                     ref="#director">Marshall</persName>, I am surprised at the things you are doing
                  now-a-days." <persName key="neilan" ref="#professional" role="business"
                     >Marshall</persName> said, "Just what do you mean by that?" and he said, "Why,
                  what you said to your <persName key="wife" ref="#family" role="unknown"
                     >wife</persName> the other night at <placeName type="hotel">Sunset
                     Inn</placeName> about poor little <placeName key="swanson" ref="#professional"
                     role="social">Gloria Swanson</placeName>."</p>

               <p> I may be getting some of those words mixed; maybe he didn't say "poor little
                     <persName key="swanson" ref="#professional" role="social">Gloria
                     Swanson</persName>." Maybe <persName key="neilan" ref="#professional"
                     role="business">Marshall</persName> didn't tell me that. This is my impression.
                     <persName key="neilan" ref="#professional" role="business">Marshall</persName>
                  said, "What do you mean?" And he said, "Don't you remember the night we were at
                     <placeName type="hotel">Sunset Inn</placeName> and you were sitting here and
                     <persName key="swanson" ref="#professional" role="social">Miss
                     Swanson</persName> was sitting there and your former wife, <persName
                     key="bambrick" ref="#professional" role="unknown">Gertrude Banbrick</persName>,
                  came in and said, 'Hello, <persName key="gloria" ref="#professional" role="social"
                     >Gloria</persName>, how are you?' and <persName key="swanson"
                     ref="#professional" role="social">Gloria</persName> replied pleasantly, and you
                  turned to <persName key="bambrick" ref="#professional" role="unknown">Gertrude
                     Bambrick</persName> and said, 'How dare you speak to this girl?' pointing to
                     <persName key="swanson" ref="#professional">Gloria</persName>, the <persName
                     key="person">lady</persName> he was with, 'How dare you speak to her? Don't you
                  ever dare to speak to her again,'" And <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">Mr
                     taylor</persName> was telling <persName key="neilan" ref="#professional"
                     role="business">Marshall Neilan</persName>. <persName key="neilan"
                     ref="#professional" role="business">Marshall</persName> said he looked at him
                  and said, "What's the matter with you, <persName key="taylor" ref="#director"
                     >Bill</persName>? Are you drunk?" He said, I haven't had a <objectName
                     type="consumable">drink</objectName>," <persName key="taylor" ref="#director"
                     >Mr taylor</persName> said, and he said, "The funny part of it was he wasn't
                  drunk." He couldn't detect it on his breath. "But he looked quite as serious and
                  sober as I do this minute." He said, "Why, tell me what day you think this was."
                  He said it was on a <date>certain day</date> -- I don't know if <persName
                     key="neilan" ref="#professional" role="business">Marshall</persName> told me
                  the day or not. He said, on a <date>certain day</date> at <placeName type="hotel"
                     >Sunset Inn</placeName> recently. <persName key="neilan" ref="#professional"
                     role="business">Marshall</persName> said, "Why, <persName key="taylor"
                     ref="#director">Bill</persName>, at that time l I was in <placeName type="city"
                     >New York City</placeName> and was not in <placeName type="city">Los
                     Angeles</placeName> nor <placeName type="state">California</placeName>."</p>

               <p>
                  <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">Mr taylor</persName> and he had quite a
                  friendly argument over it, and he said, "I know it is so; I was there myself and
                  heard what you said upon this greeting between those two <persName key="girls"
                     >girls</persName>." <persName key="neilan" ref="#professional" role="business"
                     >Marshall</persName> said he thought perhaps he had lost his mind. The next day
                  he called up, haVing that in mind, <persName key="swanson">Miss Swanson</persName>
                  and he said, "<persName key="swanson" ref="#professional" role="social"
                     >Gloria</persName>, am I going crazy? Have I lost my mind? Do you remember of
                  ever being at <placeName type="hotel">Sunset Inn</placeName> with me when
                     <persName key="bambrick" ref="#professional" role="unknown">Gertrude
                     Bambrick</persName> passed our <placeName type="table">table</placeName> and
                  spoke to us pleasantly and railed at my <persName key="ex" ref="#family"
                     role="unknown">former wife</persName> for having spoken to you pleasantly and
                  told her not to speak to you again?" And she said, "What on earth are you talking
                  about? What is this? I don't understand you," And he said, "Do you ever remember
                  seeing <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">Bill taylor</persName> there near us
                  at any time on any such occasion?" And she said, "Certainly not, !the oniy time I
                  ever saw <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">William taylor</persName> at
                     <placeName type="hotel">Sunset Inn</placeName> was the <date>night</date> I was
                  with" -- I don't know his name, some <persName key="person">friend of
                     hers</persName> -- "and <persName>Bill taylor</persName> was sitting away over
                  on the other side by the <placeName>wall</placeName> and we were by the <placeName
                     type="musical">orchestra</placeName> on this side." He said, "Was I there?" And
                  she said, "No. Don't you remember you were in <placeName type="city">New
                     York</placeName> at the time?" He said, "That is one instance, <persName
                     key="minter" ref="#actor" role="business romantic">Mary</persName>, of
                     <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">Bill</persName>'s failing mind, I have
                  never cleared that up. <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">Bill</persName> and
                  I have discussed it many times since, and I have always gone away puzzled, amazed,
                  that he still stuck to his version of my having spoken to my <persName key="ex"
                     ref="#family">former wife</persName> as I did. I didn't see her neither
                     <persName key="swanson" ref="#professional" role="social">Miss
                     Swanson</persName> saw her on that occasion." Then he said, "On another
                     <eventName type="occasion">occasion</eventName>
                  <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">Bill</persName> told me he had received a
                     <objectName type="letter">letter</objectName> from <persName key="sweet"
                     ref="#professional" role="social">Blanche Sweet</persName>; that she told
                     <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">Mr taylor</persName> that she was
                  grieved he was sick;" that <persName key="neilan">Marshell Neilan</persName> was
                  calling on me and she intended to sue him. <persName key="neilan"
                     ref="#professional" role="business">Marshall</persName> said that sounded so
                  unlike <persName key="sweet" ref="#professional" role="social">Miss
                     Sweet</persName> that he went to her and questioned her, and he said,
                     "<persName key="sweet" ref="#professional" role="social">Blanche</persName>,
                  have you writtn to <persName key="taylor" ref="#professional">Bill</persName>
                  lately?" She said, "Why, yes, I wrote him a little <objectName>note</objectName>
                  not so long ago thanking him for some <objectName type="flowers"
                     >poinsettias</objectName> he sent me <date>Christmas</date>." He aa1d, "Did you
                  say anything else?" She said, "No, not that I can remember." He said, "Did you
                  ever say that you regretted my going about with <persName key="minter"
                     ref="#actor" role="business romantic">Miss Minter</persName> and that you
                  intended to sue me?" She said, "Perfectly ridiculous. What do you mean? I
                  certainly did not say any such thing."</p>

               <p>
                  <persName key="neilan" ref="#professional" role="business">Marshall</persName> at
                  that time said to me, "And you know <persName key="sweet" ref="#professional"
                     role="social">Blanche</persName> doesn't lie. She certainly doesn't lie; tbat
                  is her reputation all over the world, over the picture game. I have heard that
                  hundreds of times myself; I am pretty sure it is so." He said, "Now, that is
                  another instance of poor <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">Bill</persName>'s
                  insanity. Now, <persName key="minter" ref="#actor" role="business romantic"
                     >Mary</persName>, here is the ghastly thing I have to tell you." He said, "One
                  time" -- I don't know whether he said in his <placeName>room</placeName> or the
                     <placeName type="club">club</placeName>, he was somewhere, I think in one of
                  his own <placeName type="house">rooms</placeName>, he, <persName key="neilan"
                     ref="#professional" role="business">Marshall Nieilan</persName>, and <persName
                     key="hoyt" ref="#professional" role="social">Arthur Hoyt</persName>, <persName
                     key="robinson" ref="#professional">Cap Robinson</persName> -- He said
                     "<persName key="robinson" ref="#professional" role="social">Cap
                     Robinson</persName>"; maybe he meant "Captain"; I don't know; I don't know how
                  he is; I know <persName key="hoyt" ref="#professional" role="social"
                     >Arthur</persName> well. He said, "We were all standing around there talking
                  pleasantly" -- I think he said <persName key="moreno" ref="#professional"
                     role="social">Antonio Moreno</persName> was there. He said, "We were all
                  talking pleasantly and <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">Mr taylor</persName>
                  suddenly started talking about you, and the talk grew finally more and more
                  personal and finally he said -- and this is terrible -- 'presently he said you had
                  been over in the last two weeks" -- I should say this is within at least three
                  weeks of <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">Mr taylor</persName>'s
                     <eventName>death</eventName>; I think <persName key="neilan"
                     ref="#professional" role="business">Marshall</persName> told me at the time,
                  but I have forgotten the time. -- "within the last two weeks, that you were
                  undressed in his <placeName type="residence">apartments</placeName>; that you
                  beseeched him for his love; that he resisted you, and finally persuaded you to
                  leave his <placeName type="residence">apartments</placeName>."</p>
            </div>

            <div type="section" n="4">
               <byline>Edited by Lucy DiChristina</byline>
               <p><persName key="neilan" ref="#director">Marshall</persName> said that to me, and
                  looked right at me. I could feel myself grow red. I said, "Is that all you have to
                  tell me about <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">Mr Taylor</persName>?" He
                  said, "Well, I could recite some more instances about <persName key="taylor"
                     ref="#director">Bill's</persName> seeming insanity." He said, "I am certain he
                  was insane. He stood up and told those things as <eventName type="sober"
                     >soberly</eventName> as I am talking to you now." </p>
               <p> MR MOTT: Excuse me. Did he keyer to <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">Mr
                     Taylor's</persName> physical condition? </p>
               <p> MINTER: Yes, he said he was <eventName type="drunk">drunk</eventName> at the
                  time. <persName key="neilan" ref="#director">Marshall</persName> has told ma on
                  several occasions, sometimes long ago and sometimes recently that he always hated
                  to see <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">Bill</persName> drink because he
                  said, "You wouldn't know the man; he changes so; he gets maudlin and silly, smiles
                  in a foolish manner and wobbles and talks, oh, just the silly, foolish things." He
                  said, "None of his friends like to see him drink." At this time he was <eventName
                     type="drunk">intoxicated</eventName> and he talked on and on and on about this
                  thing." <persName key="neilan" ref="#director">Marshall</persName> said he got up
                  and he told <persName key="taylor" ref="#director"> Bill</persName>, "You are
                  insane; something 1s the matter with your mind. I would certainly take more
                  vengeance on you if I didn't think you were crazy," and that was tbe opinion of
                     <persName key="hoyt" ref="#director">Arthur Hoyt</persName> and <persName
                     key="robinson" ref="#law_enforcement">Cap Robinson</persName> and everybody.
                  They were perfectly amazed that a man of <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">Mr
                     Taylor's</persName> lovable, sweet, considerate, gentlemanly disposition all
                  through life should suddenly turn around and say this about not only a woman, but
                  about me, whom they all knew he admired and respected. </p>
               <p> When I heard of this thing, l just looked to <persName key="neilan"
                     ref="#director">Marshall</persName> and said, "Is that all you have to tell me
                  about <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">Mr Taylor</persName>?" And he said,
                  "Yes, that is all. That 1s the ghastly thing. I know you are going to hear this
                  from somebody and I wanted you to hear it from me, and want to find out what you
                  knew about the <eventName type="murder">murder</eventName> of this man." </p>
               <p> By this time I was getting -- Oh, how can I can I express it? -- just exhausted
                  with shock, one shock after another and of all the shocks I had received, this
                  coming from hlm who I had no reason to doubt his word, I couldn't believe it; not
                  as I knew <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">Mr Taylor</persName>, I couldn't
                  believe for an instant he had ever said these things to anybody, yet there
                     <persName key="neilan" ref="#director">Marshall</persName> giving me names,
                  dates and places. The thing was too much for me. I got furious; and I said, "I
                  don't believe you! I think you are lying! How dare you say this about him to me! I
                  never want to see you again?" He got up and walked around the room for a minute
                  and I was just broiling; I was just furious; and he turned around and he said,
                  "Well, <persName key="minter" ref="#actor">Mary</persName>, some day you will
                  realize that I certainly am not saying this for any personal reason. It hurts me
                  as it must hurt you. I am simply telling you because you are bound to know it; it
                  is the truth and I wanted to be the one to tell you. </p>
               <p> Well, I didn't have any more to say to him. I was just furious; I was furious
                  with him; and finally he talked and he said, more, more, more personal things
                  about, "You know <persName key="minter" ref="#actor">Mary</persName> that I care
                  for you." </p>
               <p> DORAN: He told you he loved you, did he? </p>
               <p>MINTER: Yes; he did on <date type="friday">Friday</date> night. He said, "You know
                  I care for you deeply." </p>
               <p> I said, "I don't care; I don't want you to care for me; I don't want <persName
                     key="jones">John Jones</persName> to care for me or anybody; I don't want ever
                  to be in <eventName type="love">love</eventName> again as long as I <eventName
                     type="life">live</eventName>; I don't want to see any man; I hate men." I
                  probably raved on. </p>
               <p> I dont know what more I can tell you. I was so tired, exhausted; I had been
                  sitting up all <time type="night">night</time>. This conversation didn't come as
                  quickly as I am te11ing it to you. It came with long pauses; he would get up and
                  walk around with his <objectName type="posession">cigarette</objectName> smoking
                  and come back again and go out and talk to the property man, go out of the
                     <placeName>office</placeName>, and I would sit there alone and I tore a piece
                  of paper, I was so tired, and suggested that we go <placeName type="residence"
                     >home</placeName>. I said, "Why keep sitting up? </p>
               <p> You have got to get up at <time type="morning">eight o'clock</time> in the <time
                     type="morning">morning</time> and it is nearly <time type="morning"
                  >dawn</time>." He aaid, "I am worried about this thing; I want to find out what
                  you know about this <eventName type="murder">murder</eventName>." Then it
                  developed that <persName key="neilan" ref="#director">Marshall</persName> thought
                  I knew something about it, and he looked at me and he said, "Now, <persName
                     key="minter" ref="#actor">Mary</persName>" -- he got a little profane, he said,
                  "Now, <persName key="minter" ref="#actor">Mary</persName>, for God's sake, if you
                  know anything about the <eventName type="murder">murder</eventName> of <persName
                     key="taylor" ref="#director">Bill</persName> tell it to me now." He said,
                  "Don't withhold anything." This was too much; not only had he been telling me
                  these things about <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">Mr Taylor</persName>,
                  but there he sat evidently believing that I knew someth1ng. I said, "Do you think
                  that I <eventName type="murder">killed</eventName>
                  <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">Mr Taylor</persName>?" He said, "Oh, no;
                  don't be silly. Now is no time to talk things like that. " He said, "I am just
                  trying to find something out about this. This is going to be an awful <eventName
                     type="affair">affair</eventName>." I said, "I didn't <eventName type="murder"
                     >kill</eventName>
                  <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">William Desmond Taylor</persName> and I
                  don't know who <eventName type="murder">murdered</eventName> him." He said, "You
                  don't? You don't know anything?" He said, "Of course, you didn't <eventName
                     type="murder">kill</eventName> him; of course, you didn't put anybody on to do
                  it, But" he said, "don't you know somebody, don't you know some inti­mate details
                  that other people might not know? Can't you rack your brain and think who would
                  have a motive for <eventName type="murder">killing</eventName> him?" </p>
               <p> Then he sat there and we said words about pro and con, trying to think, and I
                  thought over everyrody I knew and I said this, more or less in a humourous way, I
                  said, "The only person I know who could have had a possible motive for <eventName
                     type="murder">killing</eventName> him would be <persName key="ivers">Mrs. Julia
                     Crawford Ivers</persName>." I was not serious when I said that. I was more or
                  less humorous. She is a lady I feel I ought to explain about, who has never done
                  me a wrong thing in her life and I have never done her a wrong thing, either, but
                  she is a <persName key="ivers">Christian Science lady</persName> who has been
                  associated with him as a <orgName type="writer">scenario writer</orgName> for
                     <time type="years">many years</time>; she is quite a trusted, lovely woman, I
                  am sure; a very honorable respectable woman, but we don't like eaeh other. There
                  is no reason, but we don't like each other. Every time I wanted to see him,
                  somehow she would be there and she had a strange way of treating me. She would
                  say, Oh yes, there is little <persName key="minter">Mary</persName>. Here she
                  comes." She would go on in this manner, "Oh, there is little <persName
                     key="minter">Mary</persName> again, Oh, there she is; wbat can she be want1ng
                  this time? Oh, yes, uh huh." Quite a strange attitude, She just riled me. </p>
               <p> DORAN: Bow old a woman was she? </p>
               <p> MINTER: She must have been 50. Her son was <persName key="taylor">Mr
                     Taylor's</persName>
                  <orgName type="job">camera man</orgName>. <persName key="Jimmy">Jimmy</persName>
                  was my <orgName type="job">camera man</orgName>, <persName key="Jim">Jim
                     Vantrees</persName>. I don't hate the woman, but she annoys me. She is one of
                  the few people in the world I dislike to see. In fact, the irony of fate it was
                  when I was in <placeName type="country">France</placeName> after looking at the
                  beautifUl Venus de Milo in <placeName type="city">Paris</placeName> at the
                     <placeName type="meusam">Louvre</placeName>, and after I had walked a few steps
                  done a long hall, thinking of this excellent statue, who should I see but
                     <persName key="ivers">Julia Crawford Ivers</persName>, a very, fat, large
                  woman. She did some more of these Christian Science things, and she had a very
                  unpleasant habit of whenever she would be with me and <persName key="taylor">Mr
                     Taylor</persName>, she would always come and twit my chin. So I said, in really
                  a joking manner -- I don't want to accuse the woman, because I don't think she had
                  anything to do with the matter -- I said "I don't know anyone who would kill him
                  but <persName key="ivers" ref="#director">Ju1ia Crawford Ivers</persName>." "I
                  always suspected the woman of being in love with him herself or she might have
                     <eventName type="murder">killed</eventName> him tor that reason." He said, "My
                  goodness! You mustn't say that out loud; somebody w111 believe you." I said, "I
                  don't care if they do." I was in such a wild mood, Then, -- What else did we talk
                  about? Oh! He talked about his <orgName type="production">productions</orgName>
                  and said, "I certainly have a terrible time, working <time type="day">day</time>
                  and <time type="night">night</time> and a great deal depended upon <date
                     type="saturday">Saturday</date> and we must get certain work finished <date
                     type="friday">Friday</date>." We talked of <date type="friday">Friday</date>
                  <time type="night">night</time> and that he had to get up at <time type="morning"
                     >eight o'clock</time>; he wasn't going to bed at all; that the boys were
                  calling for him at <time type="morning">eight o'clock</time>, he said, and he knew
                  if they didn't call he would never get up out of his <eventName type="sleep"
                     >slumbers</eventName>. They were going somewhere <placeName type="set">on
                     location</placeName>, I understood, possibly at the <placeName type="studio"
                     >studio</placeName>. He was just going <placeName type="residence"
                     >home</placeName> and take a <eventName type="bathe">shower</eventName>, get a
                     <eventName type="bathe">shave</eventName> if he felt like it, and go on back
                  and <eventName type="work">work</eventName> some more. He said, "I am dog tired. I
                  was never so exhausted, just <eventName type="dead">dead</eventName>." Finally I
                  said, "Do you rea1ize this looks awful, being here all this time?" And he said, "I
                  can't help it if it does. I had to tell you these things and wanted to find out
                  what you knew about this case. That I know you knew <persName key="taylor"
                     ref="#director">Bill</persName> very well, probably better than any of us and"
                  -- Oh, yes. He also asked me to tel1 him my feelings toward <persName key="taylor"
                     ref="#director">Mr Taylor</persName>, exactly what everybody has been asking
                  me, and I told him as I have been telling you, I loved him deeply, sincerely and
                  absolutely; that I <eventName type="love">loved</eventName> him truly, <eventName
                     type="love">loved</eventName> him in an all-around way, I cared for his health;
                  his health came before my happiness and when he was ill -- and he didn't like to
                  see anyone when he was <eventName type="sick">ill</eventName>-- my natural impulse
                  was to go to him and be with him and sit up <time type="night">night</time> after
                     <time type="night">night</time> with him, if necessary. l didn't do it; I didn
                  t even attempt to, because he didn't want me to, and although I had sat in the
                  dark, not knowing anything and worrying about it, I did that rather than intrude
                  myself upon him when he didn't want me. </p>
               <p> DORAN: What time of <time type="night">night</time> dld you first meet -- What is
                  this man's name? </p>
               <p> MINTER: <persName key="neilan" ref="#director">Mr Neilan</persName>? </p>
               <p> DORAN: <persName key="neilan" ref="#director">Mr Neilan</persName>, this
                  particular night. </p>
               <p> MINTER: We went down to the <placeName type="station">Salt Lake
                     station</placeName> after <time type="night">one</time>. </p>
               <p> DORAN: And you arrived at your <placeName type="residence">home</placeName>, was
                  it, or his <placeName type="residence">home</placeName> or whose <placeName
                     type="residence">home</placeName> was it where you were frying the eggs? </p>
               <p> MINTER: His <placeName type="residence">home</placeName>, <date type="friday"
                     >Friday</date>
                  <time type="night">night</time>; it was really <date type="saturday"
                     >Saturday</date>
                  <time type="morning">morning</time>, wasn't it? I call lt <date type="friday"
                     >Friday</date>
                  <time type="night">night</time>, because it was still <time type="night"
                     >nighttime</time>. The five of us arrived there, oh, I don't know, he didn't
                  finish <eventName type="work">work</eventName> until between <time type="morning"
                     >two-thirty and three o'c1ock</time>, maybe after three; I didn't have a
                     <objectName type="jewelry">watch</objectName> at that time. </p>
               <p> DORAN: Row long approximatey do you suppose you spent talking in the <placeName
                     type="studio">studio</placeName>? </p>
               <p> MINTER: Now, let me see, we stayed at <persName key="neilan" ref="#director"
                     >Marshall's</persName>
                  <placeName type="residence">house</placeName> wtth the eggs and things at least an
                     <time type="hours">hour</time>, maybe<time type="hours"> two hours</time>; I am
                  not certain of that at all; I don't think much more than an <time type="hours"
                     >hour</time>. Then we went right on to the <placeName type="studio"
                     >studio</placeName>, </p>
               <p> DORAN: Do you suppose you spent a <time type="hours">couple of hours</time> down
                  there? </p>
               <p> MINTER: I think maybe we spent a <time type="hours">couple of hours</time>; maybe
                     <time type="hours">three hours</time>; it takes a good while to go from
                     <placeName type="station">Salt Lake station</placeName> up to <persName
                     key="neilan" ref="#director">Marshall's</persName>
                  <placeName type="residence">home</placeName> on <placeName type="street">Sunset
                     Boulevard</placeName>. It would take at least <time type="hours">forty-five
                     minutes</time>, I think. Then it takes some time to go from his <placeName
                     type="residence">home</placeName> to the <placeName type="studio"
                     >studio</placeName>, way out on <placeName type="street">Santa Monica
                     Boulevard</placeName>. </p>
               <p> DORAN: Where was the <placeName type="studio">studio</placeName>? </p>
               <p> MINTER: On <placeName type="street">Santa Monica Boulevard</placeName>, the
                     <placeName type="studio">Hollyood Studios</placeName>. </p>
               <p> DORAN: Did you suggest that you go down there with him? </p>
               <p> MINTER: He said, "Let's go on down" -- No, the first thing he said was "Let's get
                  out of here. I am burning up alive." It was very cold when we came in the
                     <placeName type="residence">house</placeName> and we put on steam and then he
                  got terribly hot. I don't know what was the matter with me, I wouldn't take off my
                     <objectName type="clothing">coat</objectName>. He said, "If you are going to
                  stay there and burn, let's go out and talk." We got in the <objectName
                     type="vehicle">car</objectName> and drove around for a while. No, it is not a
                  fact that he said in the <placeName type="residence">house</placeName>, "We must
                  go to the <placeName type="studio">studio</placeName> and talk." I think I said
                  that at first; it is not so. He said, "Let's go out and talk." Then it was very
                  bitterly cold <placeName type="outside">outside</placeName>, freez1ng ocld. </p>
               <p> DORAN: You left the rest of the party at the house? </p>
               <p> MINTER: No; <persName key="swanson" ref="#actor">Miss Swanson</persName> and
                     <persName key="jpickford" ref="#actor">Mr Pickford</persName> got in <persName
                     key="jpickford" ref="#actor">Mr Pickford's</persName>
                  <objectName type="vehicle">Locomobile</objectName> and he said he ms going to take
                  her <placeName type="residence">home</placeName>. She was very anxious to get to
                     <placeName type="bed">bed</placeName> as she had to get up early and <eventName
                     type="work">work</eventName>. </p>
               <p> DORAN: Then, you and <persName key="neilan" ref="#director">Marshall
                     Neilan</persName>
                  <eventName type="drive">drove</eventName> around <time type="hours">awhile</time>
                  and finally wound up in the <placeName type="studio">studio</placeName>? </p>
               <p> MINTER: Yes; we <eventName type="drive">drove</eventName> around, went out
                     <placeName type="street">Sunset Boulevard</placeName> and went up -- We went
                  along <placeName type="street">Hollywood Boulevard</placeName> for a while, </p>
               <p> DORAN: What did you discuss while you were <eventName type="drive"
                     >riding</eventName> around in the <placeName type="vehicle"
                  >machine</placeName>? </p>
               <p> MINTER: Why, about this thing about<persName key="taylor" ref="#director"> Mr
                     Taylor</persName> and then also I was rather peeved na <persName key="neilan"
                     ref="#director">Marshall</persName> at the time because I hadn't heard from him
                  in weeks. "Peeved" is hardly the word. That sounds more as if I am interested in
                     <persName key="neilan" ref="#director">Marshall</persName>, and I am; I like
                  him, but l wasn't caring particularly; I simply said, "Well, <persName
                     key="neilan" ref="#director">Marshall</persName>, it was not a very nice thing
                  the way you ran off the last time. I understood they were going out to <eventName
                     type="dinner">dinner</eventName> and you were coming to my <placeName
                     type="residence">house</placeName> to <eventName type="dinner"
                     >dinner</eventName> and suddenly you went to <placeName type="city">San
                     Francisco</placeName> without so much as a fare-thee-well."' He said, "You know
                  I do those things." I said, "Yes, you do those things, and it ts very annoying,
                  but your friends love you and love you yet in spite of those funny little tricks
                  you do, darting here and there. I don't know, I am in no mood to take thia
                  foolishness; I want good wholesome friendship, but I want to know when you are
                  going to appear." Many times a whole <eventName type="dinner">dinner</eventName>
                  has gotten cold waiting for him. When we had a <eventName type="dinner">dinner
                     party</eventName> at our <placeName type="residence">house</placeName>, or
                  other people have given <eventName type="party">parties</eventName>, they have
                  waited on <persName key="neilan" ref="#director">Marshall</persName> for <time
                     type="hours">two or three hours</time> and he finally would come along smiling
                  sweetly at everybody and they couldn't scold him. I was more or less taking him to
                  task for his 1ife in general, saying he should not do those things; it was very
                  annoying and I was not going to put up with it. He was sweet and Irish and said,
                  "You wouldn't be angry with me?" And I said, "No, I wouldn't be." That is the way
                  we got out of that. There was nothing serious in the talk, Just the way we always
                  talked. </p>
               <p> DORAN: Then you finally went to the <placeName type="studio">studio</placeName>? </p>
               <p> MINTER: Finally he said, "Now, I have got something very important to tell you,
                  something that is going to hurt your feelings terribly, but I must tell you; we
                  wi11 go in the <placeName type="studio">studio</placeName> and talk." Our teeth
                  were chatter1ng with cold and we went in there and he turned on the steam and I
                  sat in this <objectName type="clothing">fur coat</objectName> in a <objectName
                     type="furniture">wicker chair</objectName>, and he said, "This is going to b, a
                  nine or "nineteen-days talk of the world" Then he told me all the things I have
                  been telling you. There may have been some more, and some thlngs I have said may
                  not be exactly accurate, but the gist of the thing is entirely accurate. </p>
               <p> DORAN: Did he declare his <eventName type="love">love</eventName> for you, whi1e
                  rid1ng around in the <objectName type="vehicle">machine</objectName>? </p>
               <p> MINTER: No, he did not. </p>
               <p> DORAN: Not until you reached the <placeName type="studio">studio</placeName> did
                  he do tha that? </p>
               <p> MINTER: Not until after we had been there a long time at the <placeName
                     type="studio">studio</placeName>. </p>
               <p> DORAN: Was it before or after he told you about this instance in connection with
                     <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">Taylor</persName> -- </p>
               <p> MINTER: It was afterwards. I don't know yet whether he really meant it; maybe he
                  was as sincere as he could be, and he can be very sincere, I am sure. I am sure he
                  can. </p>
            </div>

            <div>
               <byline>Edited by Nick Eisele</byline>
               <p>DORAN: This was the second time that <persName key="neilan" ref="#director"
                     role="business">he</persName> had declared love for you. On one occasion
                     <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business">he</persName> proposed
                  to <persName key="minter" ref="#actor" role="romantic business"
                  >you</persName>?</p>

               <p>MINTER: Yes.</p>

               <p>DORAN: <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business">He</persName> asked
                     <persName key="minter" ref="#actor" role="romantic business">you</persName> to
                  marry <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business">him</persName>?</p>

               <p>MINTER: Yes, and then <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business"
                     >he</persName> would dart away again. I mean <persName key="neilan"
                     ref="#director" role="business">he</persName> would call me up -- <persName
                     key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business">He</persName> can't call me up,
                  because I have no telephone; <persName key="neilan" ref="#director"
                     role="business">he</persName> would send me <objectName type="decoration"
                     >flowers</objectName>, too, and suddenly I would not hear from <persName
                     key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business">him</persName> for <time>two or
                     three weeks</time>. As I said to <persName key="neilan" ref="#director"
                     role="business">him</persName> in the <objectName type="vehicle"
                     >car</objectName>, not particularly about that but about other things, about
                     <eventName type="love">dinner engagements</eventName>, about appointments, I
                  said, "You know, <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business"
                     >Marshall</persName>, I never know when l am going to see <persName
                     key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business">you</persName> and when I am not
                  going to see <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business"
                  >you</persName>, and just what <persName key="neilan" ref="#director"
                     role="business">you</persName> are going to do, and I am in no mood to go on
                  like that at all; I don't care much about it."</p>

               <p>DORAN: When did <persName key="minter" ref="#actor" role="romantic business"
                     >you</persName> tell <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business"
                     >him</persName> that?</p>

               <p>MINTER: I told <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business"
                     >him</persName> that when we were driving the <objectName type="vehicle"
                     >car</objectName>.</p>

               <p>DORAN: How old a <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business"
                     >man</persName> is <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business"
                     >Marshall Neilan</persName>?</p>

               <p>MINTER: Just thirty.</p>

               <p>DORAN: Has <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business">he</persName>
                  ever been <eventName type="marriage">married</eventName>?</p>

               <p>MINTER: Yes, <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business">he</persName>
                  has been married once for <time>a few days</time>. <persName key="neilan"
                     ref="#director" role="business">He</persName> remained married to <persName
                     key="neilanWife">his wife</persName> for a long time, for <time>seven
                     years</time>, I think, but <persName key="neilan" ref="#director"
                     role="business">he</persName> was actually only married a few days. I think
                     <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business">he</persName> married
                  when <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business">he</persName> was
                  twenty or nineteen.</p>

               <p>DORAN: Have <persName key="minter" ref="#actor" role="romantic business"
                     >you</persName> seen <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business"
                     >him</persName> since <time>this Friday night</time>?</p>

               <p>MINTER: No, I have not.</p>

               <p>DORAN: Have you talked with <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business"
                     >him</persName> over the <objectName type="communication"
                     >telephone</objectName>?</p>

               <p>MINTER: It was really <time>Saturday morning</time>.</p>

               <p>DORAN: Has <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business">he</persName>
                  called you up on the <objectName type="communication">telephone</objectName>?</p>

               <p>MINTER: No; <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business">he</persName>
                  may have called me at the <placeName type="residence">New Hampshire
                     house</placeName> and I wouldn't know.</p>

               <p>DORAN: <persName key="minter" ref="#actor" role="romantic business">You</persName>
                  haven't talked with <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business"
                     >him</persName> over the <objectName type="communication"
                     >telephone</objectName>?</p>

               <p>MINTER: I haven't seen <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business"
                     >him</persName> or talked to <persName key="neilan" ref="#director"
                     role="business">him</persName> or come in touch with <persName key="neilan"
                     ref="#director" role="business">him</persName> in any way</p>

               <p>DORAN: You haven't received any <objectName type="document">letters</objectName>
                  from <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business">him</persName>?</p>

               <p>MINTER: No.</p>

               <p>DORAN: Did you part friendly or unfriendly?</p>

               <p>MINTER: We did part more or less friendly, as I always did with <persName
                     key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business">Marshall</persName>, no matter how
                  angry I would become with <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business"
                     >him</persName>, somehow you can't bear malice against that <persName
                     key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business">boy</persName>.</p>

               <p>DORAN: <persName key="minter" ref="#actor" role="romantic business">You</persName>
                  have become angry with <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business"
                     >him</persName> on <date>other occasions</date>?</p>

               <p>MINTER: Yes. This night for the time being, I was furious [missing page] [...]
                     <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business">Mr Neilan</persName> --
                     <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">Taylor's</persName>, and at the time of
                     <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">Mr Taylor</persName>'s <eventName
                     type="murder">death</eventName>, <persName key="harry" ref="#director"
                     >Harry</persName> was the assistant director in <persName key="taylor"
                     ref="#director">Mr Taylor's</persName>
                  <orgName type="company">companies</orgName> there, and he had said <persName
                     key="harry" ref="#director" role="business">Harry</persName> had been in
                     <placeName type="room">the room</placeName> looking over the effects -- Just a
                  minute. I wonder if <persName key="maigne" ref="#director">Charles
                     Maigne</persName> told me this. I think <persName key="neilan">Mr
                     Neilan</persName> told me this, too, that <persName key="harry" ref="#director"
                     >Harry</persName> bad gotten the <objectName type="document"
                     >letters</objectName> and taken <objectName type="document">them</objectName>
                  to <persName key="vantrees" role="unknown">Jim Vantrees</persName>, <persName
                     key="vantrees" ref="studio_employee" role="business">the camera man</persName>,
                  whereupon I remarked, "I will bet <persName key="ivers" ref="writer"
                     role="unknown">Mrs Ivers</persName> had them," and I think <persName
                     key="vantrees" ref="#studio_employee" role="business">he</persName> said,
                     "<persName key="vantrees" ref="#director" role="business">Jim</persName> gave
                     <objectName type="document">them</objectName> to <persName key="eyton"
                     ref="#director" role="business">Mr Eyton</persName>," and that <persName
                     key="eyton" ref="#director" role="business">Mr Eyton</persName> turned some of
                     <objectName type="document">them</objectName> over to the <persName
                     key="examiner" ref="#professional" role="unknown">Examiner</persName>. I am so
                  afraid l am telling things that are not so here, <persName key="doran"
                     ref="#writer" role="unknown">Mr Doran</persName>; I don't mean to, but I
                  couldn't get all of it. That is as clear as I can make it. Anyway, I do remember
                  this part, <persName key="eyton" ref="#director" role="business">he</persName>
                  said <persName key="eyton" ref="#director" role="business">he</persName> heard
                  about <objectName type="document">them</objectName>, and I don't know how
                     <persName key="eyton" ref="#director" role="business">he</persName> heard about
                     <objectName type="document">them</objectName>, and that <persName key="eyton"
                     ref="#director" role="business">he</persName> went down, I believe, to the
                     <persName key="examiner" ref="#professional" role="unknown"
                  >Examiner</persName>, to get ahold of <objectName type="document"
                     >them</objectName> and <persName key="eyton" ref="#director" role="business"
                     >he</persName> had something to do with <placeName type="city"
                     >Pasadena</placeName>, a man, he did tell me the man's name. I don't remember
                  his name, but I believe it be­gan with "S", and this <persName key="neilan"
                     ref="#director" role="business">man</persName>, <persName key="neilan"
                     ref="#director" role="business">Marshall</persName> said he was the <persName
                     key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business">big man</persName> over the entire
                     <orgName type="group">Examiner force</orgName>, told <persName key="neilan"
                     ref="#director" role="business">him</persName> to go down and take the
                     <objectName type="document">letters</objectName>. <persName key="neilan"
                     ref="#director" role="business">He</persName> said, "Of course, if <persName
                     key="minter" ref="#actor" role="romantic business">you</persName> breathe this
                  it wi11 just about throw <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business"
                     >me</persName> in jail for the rest of <persName key="neilan" ref="#director"
                     role="business">my</persName> life," but I don't believe it will. Then
                     <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business">he</persName> said,
                  "Didn't <persName key="minter" ref="#actor" role="romantic business"
                     >you</persName> get <objectName type="document">them</objectName> today?" I
                  said, "<persName key="minter" ref="#actor" role="romantic business">I</persName>
                  did not." As well as I remember, <persName key="neilan" ref="#director"
                     role="business">Marshall</persName> said, "I then sent <objectName
                     type="document">them</objectName> to the <placeName type="studio">Realart
                     Studio</placeName> and they ought to be in <persName key="charley"
                     ref="#studio_employee" role="unknown">Charley</persName>'s hands now or
                     <persName key="garbut" ref="#studio_employee" role="unknown">Mr
                     Garbut</persName>." This whole <time>Friday night</time> is most hasy in my
                  recollection.</p>

               <p>DORAN: This <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business">man</persName>
                  knew before <persName key="minter" ref="#actor" role="romantic business"
                     >you</persName> were in love with <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">Mr
                     Taylor</persName>?</p>

               <p>MINTER: Oh, yes.</p>

               <p>DORAN: <persName key="minter" ref="#actor" role="romantic business">You</persName>
                  had told <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business">him</persName>
                  that, had <persName key="minter" ref="#actor" role="romantic business"
                     >you</persName> not?</p>

               <p>MINTER: No; in fact, I had never said to <persName key="neilan" ref="#director"
                     role="business">Marshall</persName> "<persName key="minter" ref="#director"
                     >I</persName> am in love with <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">William
                     Desmond Taylor</persName>." I never had.</p>

               <p>DORAN: How did <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business"
                     >he</persName> find it out, then?</p>

               <p>MINTER: <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business">He</persName> knew
                  about it, because we had been friends a long time. Before this <persName
                     key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business">Marshall</persName> had come to
                     <placeName type="residence">my house</placeName> very despondent and said, "I
                  think <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business">I</persName> will go
                  out in <placeName type="landscape">the garden</placeName> and eat wooly worms." I
                  said, "Don't feel that way; there are plenty of us who feel the same way." I am
                  certain <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business">he</persName> knew
                  about <eventName type="love">this thing</eventName>. I made no secret of
                     <eventName type="love">it</eventName>, but I didn't promenade it about.</p>

               <p>DORAN: Don't <persName key="minter" ref="#actor" role="romantic business"
                     >you</persName> have a recollection of having told <persName key="neilan"
                     ref="#director" role="business">him</persName>, <persName key="neilan"
                     ref="#director" role="business">Marshall Neilan</persName>, that you were fond
                  of <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">Taylor</persName>?</p>

               <p>MINTER: No. Many times I said, "I admire <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">Mr
                     Taylor</persName>; I respect <persName key="taylor" ref="#director"
                     >him</persName>; <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business"
                     >you</persName> know I respect his opinion; what a <persName key="taylor"
                     ref="#director">wonderful man</persName> I consider <persName key="taylor"
                     ref="#director">him</persName> to be." <persName key="neilan" ref="#director"
                     role="business">He</persName> knew I regarded <persName key="taylor"
                     ref="#director">him</persName> most highly.</p>

               <p>DORAN: Do you remember if <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business"
                     >he</persName> asked you at the time <persName key="neilan" ref="#director"
                     role="business">he</persName>
                  <eventName type="love">pro­posed</eventName> to you if you were in love with any
                  one else?</p>

               <p>MINTER: No, <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business">he</persName>
                  didn't ask me that at all.</p>

               <p>DORAN: Did you have any admirers who might have been jealous of <persName
                     key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business">him</persName>?</p>

               <p>MINTER: There was only one possible <persName key="dickson" role="unknown"
                     >admirer</persName>, and that was <persName key="dickson" role="unknown">Mr
                     Dickson</persName>.</p>

               <p>DORAN: Any besides <persName key="dickson" role="unknown">Mr
                  Dickson</persName>?</p>

               <p>MINTER: No; in fact, if I may say so, neither <persName key="dickson"
                     role="unknown">Mr Dickson</persName> nor <persName key="neilan" ref="#director"
                     role="business">Mr Neilan</persName> has been with me constantly enough, or I
                  feel really care enough for me to do any such thing in my behalf, I mean such as
                     <eventName type="murder">commit murder</eventName>. In my own mind I am
                  absolutely convinced that I know they would not.</p>

               <p>DORAN: <persName key="minter" ref="#actor" role="romantic business">You</persName>
                  think they are incapable, in other words?</p>

               <p>MINTER: I absolutely do.</p>

               <p>DORAN: What kind of <objectName key="cigarette">cigarettes</objectName> was
                     <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business">Neilan</persName>
                  smoking <time>the night</time> at the <placeName type="studio"
                  >studio</placeName>?</p>

               <p>MINTER: <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business">He</persName>
                  smokes two kinds of <objectName type="posession">cigarettes</objectName>.
                     <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business">He</persName> smokes a
                  gold tipped called <objectName type="posession">"Dimi"</objectName> something from
                     <placeName type="country">Egypt</placeName>, I forget the name, <objectName
                     type="posession">"D" something</objectName>; I noticed <objectName
                     type="posession">it</objectName> comes from <placeName type="city"
                     >Cairo</placeName>; then <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business"
                     >he</persName> smokes <objectName type="posession">Chesterfield
                     cigarettes</objectName>. At least, I have seen <persName key="neilan"
                     ref="#director" role="business">him</persName> smoking <objectName
                     type="posession">Chesterfield cigarettes</objectName>. I remember that much,
                  because I have always admired the face of the <objectName type="advertisement"
                     >Chesterfield boy</objectName> on that <objectName type="advertisement">red
                     back sign</objectName>, you know, that <objectName type="advertisement"
                     >laughing boy</objectName> in the light hair that says, "Gee"! <objectName
                     type="posession">They</objectName> satisfy!"</p>

               <p>DORAN: Did <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business"
                     >Neilan</persName> take <persName key="minter" ref="#actor"
                     role="romantic business">you</persName> home then <time>that morning</time>
                  from the <placeName type="studio">studio</placeName> or did <persName key="minter"
                     ref="#actor" role="romantic business">you</persName> go back in <placeName
                     type="vehicle">your own car</placeName>?</p>

               <p>MINTER: No; my <objectName type="vehicle">car</objectName> had been driven back to
                  its <placeName type="house">garage</placeName> by <persName key="chauffeur"
                     role="unknown">Mr Neilan's chauffeur</persName> with my <persName
                     key="scarborough" role="unknown">friend</persName>
                  <persName key="scarborough" role="unknown">Mr Scarborough</persName> in it. Poor
                     <persName key="scarborough" role="unknown">Mr Scarborough</persName> had been
                  driving around with me <time>all evening</time>. I hadn't been able to sleep and
                  that was why I ws_ out. <persName key="scarborough" role="unknown">He</persName>
                  said if I didn't mind <persName key="scarborough" role="unknown">he</persName>
                  would just go on back home, now that I was in safe hands, and get some sleep.
                     <persName key="scarborough" role="unknown">He</persName> was pretty near dead
                  tired. <persName key="scarborough" role="unknown">He</persName> isn't a very
                  strong man.</p>

               <p>DORAN: So <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business">Neilan</persName>
                  took <persName key="minter" ref="#actor" role="romantic business">you</persName>
                  <placeName type="residence">home</placeName> then</p>

               <p>MINTER: Yes; right straight <placeName type="residence">home</placeName>.</p>

               <p>DORAN: Did <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business">he</persName>
                  ask you to keep in confidence the <eventName type="conversation"
                     >conversation</eventName> you had had with <persName key="neilan"
                     ref="#director" role="business">him</persName>? Did <persName key="neilan"
                     ref="#director" role="business">he</persName> tell you not to say anything
                  about <eventName type="conversation">it</eventName>?</p>

               <p>MINTER: l don't remember <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business"
                     >him</persName> saying to me, "You must keep this all in secret oonfidenoe";
                  no, I do not, because when we got <placeName type="residence">home</placeName> we
                  discussed some of the things with <persName key="cshelby" ref="#family"
                     role="social">mother</persName>, with the whole family, in fact; <persName
                     key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business">he</persName> discussed the
                  seriousness of the <eventName type="conversation">conversation</eventName> and
                  told me not to do anything without my <persName key="legal" ref="#legal"
                     role="unknown">at­torneys</persName>.</p>

               <p>DORAN: <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business">He</persName> told
                  you <eventName type="conversation">that</eventName>?</p>

               <p>MINTER: Yes; <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business">he</persName>
                  said, "<persName>You</persName> mustn't make any move without your <persName
                     key="legal" ref="#legal" role="unknown">attorneys</persName>." <persName
                     key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business">He</persName> spoke of <persName
                     key="mott" role="unknown">Mr Mott</persName> and said <persName key="mott"
                     role="unknown">Mr Mott</persName> was very able and that <persName key="mott"
                     >he</persName> would tell me the right thing to do and not to <eventName
                     type="legal">make a move</eventName> without <persName key="neilan"
                     ref="#director" role="business">him</persName>.</p>

               <p>DORAN: Did <persName key="minter" ref="#actor" role="romantic business"
                     >you</persName> comment on <persName key="neilan" ref="#director"
                     role="business">his</persName> concern?</p>

               <p>MINTER: No.</p>

               <p>DORAN: Did <persName key="minter" ref="#actor" role="romantic business"
                     >you</persName> say anything to <persName key="neilan" ref="#director"
                     role="business">him</persName>, for instance to this effect: "Why should
                     <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business">you</persName> be so
                  concerned about <persName key="minter" ref="#actor" role="romantic business"
                     >me</persName>? Why should <persName key="minter" ref="#actor"
                     role="romantic business">I</persName> consult <persName key="legal"
                     ref="#legal">attorneys</persName> in connection with <eventName type="legal"
                     >this affair</eventName>?" or anything like that?</p>

               <p>MINTER: No, I did not, because at the time, when I asked <persName key="neilan"
                     ref="#director" role="business">him</persName> if <persName key="neilan"
                     ref="#director" role="business">he</persName> suspected me of <eventName
                     type="murder">killing</eventName>
                  <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">Mr Taylor</persName>, we had that out;
                     <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business">he</persName> assured me
                     <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business">he</persName> didn't
                  suspect any such thing, but <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business"
                     >he</persName> was very much impressed with the gravity of the situation. In
                  fact, evidently <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business"
                     >he</persName> knew at that time exactly how these things were going to turn
                  out. I mean that they would drag everybody's name into it; that the <orgName
                     type="publishing">papers</orgName> could get hold of for the notoriety of it.
                     <persName key="neilan" ref="#director" role="business">He</persName> said,
                  "This involves <orgName type="job">picture people</orgName> and you know how
                     <persName key="hearst" role="business">Hearst</persName> hates the <orgName
                     type="job">picture people</orgName>. <persName key="hearst" role="business"
                     >Hearst</persName> would do anything <persName key="hearst">he</persName> could
                  if <persName key="hearst" role="business">he</persName> thought you did know
                     <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">Mr Taylor</persName>," "There are lots
                  of prominent people in the <orgName type="job">profession</orgName> who knew
                     <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">him</persName> and loved <persName
                     key="taylor" ref="#director">him</persName>. They are certainly going to drag
                  your name into it."</p>

               <p>DORAN: <persName key="minter" ref="#actor" role="romantic business">You</persName>
                  didn't <eventName type="conversation">telephone</eventName>
                  <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">Taylor</persName> on <eventName
                     type="murder">the night he was murdered</eventName>?</p>

               <p>MINTER: No.</p>

               <p>DORAN: Where did <persName key="minter" ref="#actor" role="romantic business"
                     >you</persName> happen to be <eventName type="murder">that
                  night</eventName>?</p>

               <p>MINTER: I was at home reading the <objectName type="posession">Cruise of the
                     Kewa</objectName>. It is a <objectName type="posession">humorous
                     book</objectName>; it is really a travesty of <objectName type="posession"
                     >Frederick O'Brien's stories</objectName> of the South Seas. It is very funny,
                  and I laid there laughing all the <time>evening</time>. I was very -- right while
                  I was laying on the <objectName type="furniture">couch</objectName> reading aloud
                  to <persName key="cshelby" ref="#family" role="social">mother</persName> and
                  sister and we were all laughing heartily at that time, and at the same time
                     <persName key="taylor" ref="#director">Mr Taylor</persName> was <eventName
                     type="murder">being murdered</eventName>. It seems very horrible to me.</p>

               <p>DORAN: <persName key="minter" ref="#actor" role="romantic business">You</persName>
                  had no company at <placeName type="residence">home</placeName>
                  <eventName type="murder">that night</eventName>?</p>

               <p>MINTER: Let me see. I don't remember any. Possibly <persName key="stockdale"
                     role="unknown">Mr Stockdale</persName>, he generally did, or maybe somebody
                  dropped in. I don't just remember. Usually every evening somebody drops in. I know
                  they were not there at the time I was reading <objectName type="lit">the
                     book</objectName>.</p>

               <p>DORAN: Your <objectName type="vehicle">automobiles</objectName> were all
                     <placeName type="residence">home</placeName>?</p>

               <p>MINTER: Yes, unless I put my <objectName type="vehicle">car</objectName> in the
                     <placeName type="house">garage</placeName> called the <placeName
                     type="business">Standard Garage</placeName>. I leave it there sometimes, the
                     <placeName type="business">Standard Garage</placeName> on <placeName
                     type="street">Hollywood Boulevard and Western Avenue</placeName>. Sometimes
                  when my girl friends stop with me and have her <objectName type="vehicle"
                     >car</objectName>, I would move out and put it in this <placeName type="house"
                     >garage</placeName> and maybe wouldn't call for it for <time>several
                     days</time>. I haven't been feeling well for some time; I have had bronchitis.
                  I hadn't gotten well when this awful shock came to me, and I haven't used the
                  little <objectName type="vehicle">car</objectName> very much.</p>

               <p>DORAN: Do you have a <persName key="chaucy" ref="#servant" role="unknown"
                     >chauffeur</persName>?</p>

               <p>MINTER: Yes; faithful old <persName key="chaucy" ref="#servant" role="unknown"
                     >Chauncy</persName>. <persName key="chaucy" ref="#professional" role="unknown"
                     >Chauncy</persName> is just as concerned about this thing as <persName
                     key="cshelby" role="social">my mother</persName> is.</p>

               <p>DORAN: Well, I don't think of anything else I care to inquire about now.</p>

               <p>MINTER: <persName key="doran" ref="#writer" role="unknown">Mr Doran</persName>, if
                  I can be of any possible help in any way, it is true I don't know any more than I
                  have told you; if I can, please call on me the first thing, won't you?</p>

               <p>DORAN: Thank you, very much. You may think of little things of which you may not
                  appreciate the imporance, <persName key="mott" role="unknown">Mr
                  Mott</persName>.</p>

               <p>MINTER: As I told <persName key="mott" role="unknown">Mr Mott</persName> today, I
                  remember saying to <persName key="mott" role="unknown">Mr Mott</persName>, "I am
                  so tired I am like a little child. I speak words mechanically. I sit, sleep, get
                  up, walk and dress, and I don't see exactly what I am doing."</p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
