<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>HUMN100 FALL 2025: The Murder of William Desmond Taylor</title>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Diane Jakacki</persName>
               <resp>Instructor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Waina Ali</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Jada Alvarez</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Colin Caricato</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>John Cochran</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Lucy DiChristina</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Nick Eisele-Bockelkamp</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Ethan Esclamado</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Spencer Firestone</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Henry Gibbons</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Daniel Hou</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Campbell Killian</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Olivia King</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>William Le</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Charlie Meehleib</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Carter Morton</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Kate Reyen</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Blythe Sena</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Hunter Sloan</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Rylie Smith</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Lily Stein</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Riley Twiss</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Katrina von Behren</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Emma Walkowiak</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Amanda Woertz</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Produced by members of the HUMN100: Introduction to Text Analysis course, Fall 2025</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>These interviews and statements are gathered from a number of sources, including "Taylorology" and Robert Giroux's Deed of Death</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="interview">
            <head>Statement by Mary Miles Minter</head>
            <byline resp="editor">Waina A</byline>
            <p>
               STATEMENT OF 
               MISS MARY MILES MINTER.
               G.H BOONE
               OFFICIAL REPORTER
               IN THE DISTRICT ATTORNEY'S OFFICE, February 7, 
               1922, at five o'clock P.M. 
               [Section 1] </p>
               
               <p>PRESENT: <persName ref="Doran">Mr. W.C. Doran,</persName> Deputy District Attorney, 
               <persName ref="MaryMilesMinter">Miss Mary Miles Minter,</persName > <persName ref="Mott">John G. Mott,</persName> attorney for Miss 
               Minter, and <persName ref="Boone">G. H. Boone,</persName> shorthand reporter.</p>
               
               <p>STATEMENT OF MISS MARY MILES MINTER</p>
               
               <p>Questions by <persName ref="Doran">Mr. Doran</persName>: </p>
               
              <p> DORAN:  How long have you known <persName ref="Taylor">Mr Taylor</persName>?</p> 
               
               <p>MINTER:  Since <date when="1919-07">July of 1919</date> -- yes, that is correct. </p>
               
              <p> DORAN:  He has been your director in pictures, has he? </p>
               
              <p> MINTER:  Yes we commenced this <orgName type="company">company</orgName> together. </p>
               
              <p> DORAN:  Did you have occasion to call on him at <placeName type ="Taylorshouse">his residence</placeName> within <date type = "month" > the last thirty days</date> prior to his death? -- approximately <date type = "month" >  thirty days?</date> </p>
               
              <p> MINTER:  Just a moment, will you --</p>
               
             <p>  DORAN:  Let me change the question. When was the last time you called on him at <placeName type="Taylorshouse">his residence</placeName>? </p>
               
              <p> MINTER:  On the <date type = "murderday" >23rd of December.</date>
               </p>
               <p>DORAN:  Were you alone at that time or did others accompany you to see him? </p>
               
              <p> MINTER:  I was alone. </p>
               
             <p>  DORAN:  Was any one else there?</p>
               
               <p>MINTER:  no, not a soul. </p>
               
               <p>DORAN:  Was <persName ref ="Sands">his valet</persName>, the colored man, there, do you know?</p>
               
               <p>MINTER:  Not that I know of. </p>
               
             <p>  DORAN:  Prior to that time, was it your habit to call on him at his residence or had it been your habit?</p>
               
               <p>MINTER:  I couldn't call it a habit, but <date type = "severaloccasions"  >on several occasions</date> I did call upon him, though never as·1ate as upon this occasion.</p>
               
               <p>DORAN:  Now, on this last occasion, whet time of the day or night was it that you called? </p>
               
               <p>MINTER:  May l tell this in my own way? </p>
               
               <p>DORAN:  Yes, I would rather have you tell it in your own way, if you will.</p>
               
              <p> MINTER:  I am glad to. I am trying to answer as I would in court and 1 don't like to do so. </p>
               
              <p> DORAN:  Just proceed, go ahead and tell it in your own way.</p>
               
               <p>MINTER:  I had gone to <objectName type="bed">bed</objectName>; I hadn't seen <persName ref="Taylor">Mr Taylor</persName> in <date type = "fivemonthsago" >five months</date> at the time -- <date>three months,</date> I know; three months, and I just got to thinking about it and I decided I couldn't stand it any longer. I was going to go up and tell him "goodbye. I got up and dressed, went down to my <placeName type ="grandmother'sroom">grandmother's room</placeName> and I said, <persName ref ="CharlotteShelby">"Mama,</persName> I am going over to say 'goodbye' to Mr Taylor," and she advised me not to do it. She said it was too late: "Do you know it is nearly 
               <time type = "12oclock" >twelve o'clock?</time>" she said. I said, "Yes, sure, but I just must do so," I said, "I realize that this is not the usual thing and I have never been there so late, but I must do so, Mama. I am going to give him a <objectName type="letter">letter</objectName> in whioh I have told him 'goodbye,"' She said, "All right, then, if you must. I would get up and go with you, but I don't feel well enough," Mama often accompanied me on <eventName type ="Mary'strips">my trips</eventName>, which were not very many during the entire time that  i knew him. So I went over there and arrived at <time type = "11:55" >five minutes to twelve</time>, I am strange about that, I am rather queer about that, I think of the time; every time I was with him I would say, "Well, this time yesterday I didn't see him and today I am with him," and things like that. So I <time>arrived at five minutes to twelve</time> and left at t<time type = "12:40" >twenty minutes to one</time>, and-- Do you wish me to tell you all that transpired?
               </p>
              <p> DORAN:  Never mind about that. </p>   
               
              <p> DORAN:  Your <persName ref="grandmother">grandmother</persName> didn't accompany you?</p> 
               
              <p> MINTER:  No, she did not. </p>
               
               <p>DORAN:  Your <persName ref="chaffeur">chauffeur</persName> drove you there? </p>
               
               <p>MINTER:  No, I drove myself in my little <objectName type="car">car</objectName>, little run-about.</p>
               
              <p> DORAN:  That was <date type = "Dec23rd" >December 23d</date>? </p>
               
              <p> MINTER:  Yes,<date> December 23rd.</date></p>
               
              <p> DORAN:  When was the last time you saw him prior to that? </p>
               
              <p> MINTER:  I couldn't give you the exact date, but I know it was at <date>least three months and a little over; it was over three months.</date></p> 
               
               <p>DORAN:  During the three months prior to December 23d, did you ever meet him anywhere.</p>
               
              <p> MINTER:  No. You mean casually or see him really to talk to? I saw him, yes. </p>
               
               <p>DORAN:  See him and meet him, to be with him? 
               </p>
               <p>MINTER:  No; no, indeed. I passed him at <placeName type ="LaskyStudio">Lasky Studio</placeName> when I go over there. Sometimes I have seen <objectName type="Taylor'scar">his car</objectName> go down <placeName type ="WesternAvenue"> Western Avenue,</placeName> but I hadn't seen him to speak to in <date type = "threemonthsago" >three months</date>.</p>
               
              <p> DORAN:  As I understand it, you were sincerely in love with him?</p>
               
             <p>  MINTER:  That is true.</p>
               
              <p> DORAN:  Did you convey that feeling to him?</p>
               
               <p>MINTER:  Absolutely.</p>
               
              <p> DORAN:  You told him, did you?</p>
               
               <p>MINTER:  Absolutely. He loved me; he told me so.</p>
               
               <p>DORAN:  Were you engaged to be married?</p>
               
               <p>MINTER:  No, we were not.</p>
               
              <p> DORAN:  <eventName type="timeofdeath">At the time of his death</eventName>, it was --</p>
               
              <p> MR. MOTT: Right there at that point you might explain about the rising sun, with reference to your engagement. I think that explains the attitude between both of you. </p>
               
               <p>MINTER:  I don't know just which to do, whether to tell you this whole thing, go right along and talk. I can easily do that. </p>
               
               <p>MR. MOTT: He asked if you were engaged to him. Tell him about the "rising sun" explanation. </p>
               
              <p> MINTER:  I can tell you the whole thing better without being asked.</p>
               
              <p> MR. DORAN:  Yes. Go ahead. and tell us in your own way all about it.</p>
               
              <p> MINTER:  I had always known that this was just<eventName>an exquisite chapter in my life</eventName> that must necessarily be a brief one: I couldn't bear to part with it; it was just a beautiful thing that seldom occurs in the. world today as I see it, as it is forced upon me. It as simply <objectName type ="whiteflame">a beautiful white flame</objectName>; I met <persName ref="Taylor">him</persName>; I had always been a <persName>reserved, very retiring young girl</persName>, and he was the first man and the only man who ever embodied all the glories of manhood in one private body. He represented that to me. He never by look, by word or by deed gave me any reason to doubt any of my ideals that were placed in him absolutely. At the time our love first formulated he said to me, "Mary, this is not right. You are May and I am December, and this is not right. I know it is best that we must part." This was at the very beginning of it, and I said, "Of course, I don't want to do any immodest or bold thing; I couldn't try to withhold a person's love for me who didn't care for me."" I said, "I know that you are many years older than I, but I couldn't love anybody as I love you. I simply love you. And we did try to part, We tried it again and again, and then he would beoome ill. At one time I had almost resolved to see him no more, and he was taken ill and nobody else cared, [page 6] really cared whether he ate his <objectName>dinner</objectName> or whether he dressed warm1y enough, whether he took care of himself, and I couldn't bear for him to suffer. It was not only a love of sweetheart, but I wanted to be his nurse. I wanted to hold his head when it was aching. I wanted him to tell me his mental troubles, his heart troubles, and let me soothe them away for him as I would for a little child. I forgot the man's age; it meant nothing to me. The only thing I wanted was to serve him as I would have served the Lord or a little child, and then it just passed away; for months at a time I wouldn't see him and I didn't know why. Finally, I decided there was no use; it must come to an end and I went there on the night of the 23d to give him this letter telling him "goodbye." I had reason to believe, in the awful vernacular of the day, that it was over anyway, but I went there to say "goodbye" myself. He said, "It is rather late, isn't it, Mary?" when he opened the door. I said, "Yes, but don't you realize that I had to come to see you? You know Mama has been sick for three months and you have been ill and I have been frightfully worried and you haven't even had the kindness to call me to tell me that you were i11 and that I must not expect to see you to tell mo that things are all right." </p>
               
             <p>  I said, "I don't care if you don't wish to see me, because it hurts me, but it wouldn't have hurt one-millionth as much if you had just explained to me and not leave me in the dark." He said, "Mary, I couldn't help it; I couldn't help it and I can't explain it to you."
               Oh, I don't know! I have told this thing so many times, Mr Doran, that the words just - I can't tell it even as it is; I can't even express it to you as it really is. There is so much more to it.</p>
               <p>
               </p><p>MR DORAN:   At that time, on <date type="Dec23rd">December 23d,</date> let's see, he was killed on <date ref = "Feb1st" >February 1st</date>. Who was directing you then? 
               </p>
               <p>MINTER:  Why, no one was. I had finished a picture.</p>
               
              <p> DORAN:  Who directed the last one?</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
