<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>HUMN100 FALL 2025: The Murder of William Desmond Taylor</title>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Diane Jakacki</persName>
               <resp>Instructor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Waina Ali</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Jada Alvarez</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Colin Caricato</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>John Cochran</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Lucy DiChristina</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Nick Eisele-Bockelkamp</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Ethan Esclamado</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Spencer Firestone</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Henry Gibbons</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Daniel Hou</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Campbell Killian</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Olivia King</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>William Le</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Charlie Meehleib</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Carter Morton</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Kate Reyen</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Blythe Sena</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Hunter Sloan</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Rylie Smith</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Lily Stein</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Riley Twiss</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Katrina von Behren</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Emma Walkowiak</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Amanda Woertz</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Produced by members of the HUMN100: Introduction to Text Analysis course, Fall
               2025</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>These interviews and statements are gathered from a number of sources, including
               "Taylorology" and Robert Giroux's Deed of Death</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="interview">
            <head>Interview with Mary Miles Minter</head>
            <byline>Jada Alvarez</byline>

            <p>STATEMENT OF MISS MARY MILES MINTER. G.H BOONE OFFICIAL REPORTER IN THE DISTRICT
               ATTORNEY'S OFFICE, February 7, 1922, at five o'clock P.M. [Section 2]</p>

            <p>MINTER: My last director was <persName ref="urson">Frank Urson</persName>. <persName ref="taylor">Mr.
                  Taylor</persName> so often, often made the remark to me that he wished tbat he
               were younger; he wanted to be younger. We undoubtedly would have been married today
               bnd he been younger. <persName ref="taylor">He</persName> explained our not. being engaged in that
               way. I knew we never could be married; I also knew I never would love for another
               human being in the way I cared for him. So he would say, "You know,
                  <persName ref="minter">Mary</persName>, to me you are the morning sun, bright, beaut1ful, and
               with the world and a futune before you, and I am the setting sun, and don't you see,
               my dear, it simply cannot be. I hope tbat doesn't give you the impression that I
               begged him to marry me. I never did in my life. I couldn't do that. I never even
               called him <persName ref="taylor">"Billie"</persName> in my life. The man was too wonderful for that. He was wonderful.
               I don't care what anybody says or what they prove against him. I knew him as the
               finest thing in the world. </p>

            <p> MR MOTT: <persName ref="taylor">He</persName> as the embodyment of your ideal? </p>

            <p>MINTER: Yes, and I can aay now that I can't truthfully -- I don't know any of those
               ugly things which have been aaid about him. I never found him so. He was glorious to
               me. </p>

            <p> MR DORAN: I read in the <objectName type="document">paper</objectName> where you had been
                  <eventName type="major">engaged</eventName> to some other man.</p>

            <p>MINTER: To <persName ref="dickson">Mr Dickson</persName>. That is not entirely true.</p>

            <p>DORAN: What is his first name?</p>

            <p> MINTER: <persName ref="dickson">Thomas Dickson</persName>.</p>

            <p>DORAN: Someone besides him, a director in the movies.</p>

            <p>MINTER: <persName ref="neilan">Marshall Neilan</persName>, <eventName type="major">engaged</eventName> to
               him?</p>

            <p>DORAN: Yes, <persName ref="neilan">Marshall Neilan</persName>. Didn't I read in the
                  <objectName type="document">papers</objectName> that you had been engaged to him and the
                  <eventName type="major">engagement</eventName> had been broken off? </p>

            <p>MINTER: That is not true. <persName ref="dickson">Mr Dickson</persName> is the only one to whom I
               have been even remotely engaged, and that was a freak of despondency.</p>

            <p>DORAN: What about <persName ref="neilan">Marshall Neilan</persName>? Were you engaged to him?</p>

            <p>MINTER: No.</p>

            <p>DORAN: Had you been going with <persName ref="neilan">Marshall Neilan</persName> during, say the
               last <date>thirty or sixty days prior</date> to <persName ref="taylor">Taylor's</persName>
               death?</p>

            <p>MINTER: Going with <persName ref="taylor">him</persName>?</p>

            <p>DORAN: Had you been out anywhere with <persName ref="taylor">him</persName>? </p>

            <p>MINTER: Yes; he had been to see me; I had been out with <persName ref="taylor">him</persName>; I
               am not sure whether it was within the <date>thirty days</date> or not, but in the
                  <date>last two months</date>, yes sir; but going with him no more than I had for
               years off and on. <persName ref="neilan">Mr Neilan's</persName> traits [page 9] are well known; he
               comes to see you, and we are always glad to receive him, but we never know how long
               he is going to stay with us or how long he was going to stay with this one or that
               one. He flits here and there like a swallow. We are all charmed with his personality,
               but don't take him seriously. </p>
            <p>DORAN: Has <persName ref="taylor">he</persName> proposed to you?</p>

            <p>MINTER: Must I answer that? Yes, he did.</p>

            <p>DORAN: Do you recall approximately when it was?</p>

            <p>MINTER: About <date>two months ago</date>.</p>

            <p>DORAN: That would take it to <date>December 1st</date>, approximately or in the
               middle of December?</p>

            <p>MINTER: Well, I think it was after that, Yes -- No, let me see, <date>December
                  1st</date> -- I wish I could tell you.</p>

            <p>DORAN: With reference to this <date>December 23d</date> that you called on <persName ref="taylor">Taylor</persName>,
               when was it?</p>

            <p>MINTER: It as before the <date>1st of December</date>, I think.</p>

            <p>DORAN: Q. Before the <date>1st of December</date>?</p>

            <p>MINTER: Yes; about the <date>last of November</date>. </p>

            <p>DORAN: And you, of course, rejected im, I suppose?</p>

            <p>MINTER: Yes; that is, I didn't exactly say, "No, I will not marry you." I didn't take
               him seriously. I joked with <persName ref="taylor">him</persName> at the time.</p>

            <p>DORAN: Did <persName ref="taylor">he</persName> seem to be serious?</p>

            <p>MINTER: You never know. I couldn't say whether ee was serious or not. I thought
               possibly he was joking, or had a few <objectName type="consumable">cocktails</objectName>.</p>

            <p>DORAN: How many times after that did <persName ref="taylor">he</persName> mention the subject to
               you?</p>

            <p>MINTER: He didn't mention the subject. "May I marry you" again; he didn't say that,
               but he has been on very friendly terms with me and then suddenly go away to
                  <placeName type="city">San Francisco</placeName>. and I wouldn't hear from him and I would
               remark, "Isn't that just like <persName ref="neilan">Marshall?</persName>" and thought no more of
               it. </p>
            <p>DORAN: Well, but along toward the last <date>thirty days</date> prior to
                  <persName ref="taylor">Taylor's</persName>
               <eventName type="major">death</eventName>, he seemed to be quite devoted to you, did
                  <persName ref="taylor">he</persName> not?</p>

            <p>MINTER: No; I can't really say that he did. As for being with him, wasn't with
                  <persName ref="taylor">him</persName> very much.</p>

            <p>DORAN: Didn't you observe in him some jealousy?</p>

            <p>MINTER: Oh, no; No, I can't say that. He was not jealous of me. He is the least
               jealous man I ever met. He takes life too much -- </p>
            <p>DORAN: Did <persName ref="taylor">he</persName> ever say anything to you about
                  <persName ref="taylor">Taylor</persName>?</p>

            <p>MINTER: Yes, we have discussed him many times; he loved him. <persName ref="neilan">Marshall
                  Neilan</persName> loved <persName ref="taylor">Mr Taylor</persName>.</p>

            <p>DORAN: Did he ever bring any tales to you for which <persName ref="taylor">Taylor</persName> was supposed to have been
               responsible!</p>

            <p>MINTER: Not until recently.</p>

            <p>DORAN: When was that?</p>

            <p>MINTER: <date>Last Friday night</date>; whereupon we had a severe quarrel. I didn't
               believe him.</p>

            <p>DORAN: <date>Friday night</date>
               <time>after</time> the <eventName type="major">killing</eventName>?</p>

            <p>MINTER: Yes.</p>

            <p>DORAN: Or <time>before</time> the <eventName type="major">killing</eventName>?</p>

            <p>MINTER: No; after.</p>

            <p>DORAN: Did he ever say anything like that to you <time>before</time> the
                  <eventName type="major">killing</eventName>?</p>

            <p>MINTER: No, indeed he did not; he knew that I loved <persName ref="taylor">Mr Taylor</persName>
               and he had known it.</p>

            <p>DORAN: Did he ever comment on that relation between you and
                  <persName ref="taylor">Taylor</persName>?</p>

            <p>MINTER: No, <persName ref="taylor">he</persName> did not; I wouldn't have permitted him to; and I didn't comment on
               his.</p>

            <p>DORAN: I will use the word "quarrel," but that may be exaggerated; did you ever
               <eventName type="fight">quarrel</eventName> with <persName ref="neilan">Neilan</persName> over <persName ref="taylor">Taylor</persName>? </p>
            <p>MINTER: Absolutely not; absolutely not. <persName ref="neilan">Marshall</persName> is the
               typification of the happy-go-lucky Irish spirit and tempera­ment. <persName ref="taylor">He</persName> does perfectly
               terrible things to everybody, but everybody loves him. They are always glad to see
               him again. As to harboring any deep-seated malice, I don't believe <persName ref="taylor">he</persName> is capable of
               it. </p>
            <p>DORAN: Could he have assumed at any time you and <persName ref="taylor">he</persName>, you and <persName ref="neilan">Marshall Neilan</persName> -- I am
               speaking of <persName ref="neilan">Marshall Neilan</persName> now -- Could he have assumed at any time that <persName ref="taylor">he</persName> might be
               or was engaged to you by reason of your relations wtth him? </p>
            <p>MINTER: Could <persName ref="neilan">Marshall Neilan</persName> have assumed that <persName ref="taylor">Mr Taylor</persName> and I were engaged?</p>

            <p>DORAN: No, no; that you and <persName ref="neilan">Marshall Neilan</persName> were enqaged?</p>

            <p>MINTER: No.</p>

            <p>DORAN: Did you ever give <persName ref="taylor">him</persName> the impression that he might some day be successful in
               his effort to marry you?</p>

            <p>MINTER: Not in my own knowledge. If I have, it was more or less of a joking way. I
               think I have at times said, "Well, <persName ref="neilan">Marshall</persName>, when are we going all around the world
               on our honey-moon?" exactly in the same manner as I took him to say, "Now, when you
               are my wedded bride we will do" so-and­-so. <persName ref="neilan">Marshall</persName> has done that time after time. </p>
            <p>DORAN: Might he not have taken you seriously? </p>

            <p>MINTER: I don't think so.</p>

            <p>DORAN: Do you know <persName ref="taylor">he</persName> did not?</p>

            <p>MINTER: No, I don't know that <persName ref="taylor">he</persName> did not.</p>

            <p>DORAN: Don't you know that <persName ref="taylor">he</persName> was really -- Don't you feel that <persName ref="taylor">he</persName> was really in love
               with you?</p>

            <p>MINTER: I can't truthfully answer "Yes" or "no" to that, beoause I don't know; I am
               not sure enough of <persName ref="neilan">Mr Neilan's</persName> nature. While I have known him a great many years,
               well, I will say I have known him <date>several years</date>, he is the type who flits back and
               forth, you know. - When you really think you know him he turns to something else, and
               I don't know, so I have never permitted myself to form any conclusions on his
               character; I don't know whether he has ever taken me seriously or not. I always
               treated <persName ref="taylor">him</persName> more or less in a joking manner. </p>


         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
