<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>HUMN100 FALL 2025: The Murder of William Desmond Taylor</title>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Diane Jakacki</persName>
               <resp>Instructor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Waina Ali</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Jada Alvarez</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Colin Caricato</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>John Cochran</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Lucy DiChristina</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Nick Eisele-Bockelkamp</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Ethan Esclamado</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Spencer Firestone</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Henry Gibbons</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Daniel Hou</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Campbell Killian</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Olivia King</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>William Le</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Charlie Meehleib</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Carter Morton</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Kate Reyen</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Blythe Sena</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Hunter Sloan</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Rylie Smith</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Lily Stein</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Riley Twiss</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Katrina von Behren</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Emma Walkowiak</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Amanda Woertz</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Produced by members of the HUMN100: Introduction to Text Analysis course, Fall
               2025</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>These interviews and statements are gathered from a number of sources, including
               "Taylorology" and Robert Giroux's Deed of Death</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="interview">
            <head>Interview with Leslie Henry</head>
            <byline>John Cochran</byline>
            <p> STATEMENT OF MISS MARY MILES MINTER. G.H BOONE OFFICIAL REPORTER IN THE DISTRICT
               ATTORNEY'S OFFICE, February 7, 1922, at five o'clock P.M. [Part 3] </p>

            <p> DORAN: I understand the <date type="dark">night of the murder</date> you were with <persName ref="neilan">Mr Neilan</persName>. </p>

            <p>MINTER: No, I was not. I was at <placeName type="residence">home</placeName> with my <persName ref="miles">grandmother</persName> and <persName ref="sister">sister</persName>. </p>

            <p> DORAN: I mean after the <eventName type="death">murder</eventName>, after you learned of the <eventName type="death">murder</eventName>.</p>

            <p> MINTER: Yes, <date type="end">Friday</date>. </p>

            <p> DORAN: The next <date type="dark">night</date>, was it?</p>

            <p> MINTER: No, it was the <date type="friday">night after Thursday</date>. <persName ref="neilan">Mr Neilan</persName> -- I mean <persName ref="taylor">Mr Taylor</persName> was found
               dead <date type="early">Thursday morning</date>, was he not? </p>

            <p> DORAN: Yes.</p>

            <p> MINTER: <date>Thursday</date> was such a long day. <time>Friday night</time> I saw <persName ref="neilan">Mr. Neilan</persName>.</p>

            <p> DORAN: Did he. communicate w1 th you or you with him? </p>

            <p> MINTER: Why, he communicated with me; he tried to, but it was because of me he did
               that. On <time>Thuraday night</time> I was worried about <persName ref="taylor">Mr Taylor</persName>; I was worried about <persName ref="neilan">Mr Neilan</persName>
               and called <persName ref="mother">Marshall's mother</persName>.</p>

            <p> DORAN: This was after the <eventName type="death">murder</eventName>?</p>

            <p> A Yes, this vas <time>Thursday night</time> after the <eventName type="murder">murder</eventName>. I said, "Please tell <persName ref="mickey">Mickey</persName> not to
               drive that <objectName type="vehicle">green car</objectName> so reckless; I am so afraid that he, too, will fall into
               trouble. And she thanked me and said, "I will tell him. That is just exactly what I
               havebeen thinking lately myself, and I want to see you soon, <persName ref="minter">Mary</persName>." With that I
               thought no more about it. In fact, I didn't even think [page 14] <persName ref="neilan">Marshall</persName> would call
               me. He had not caled me in three week or more. 1 thought no more about it and I was
               surprised the <date>next day</date> to learn -- yes, <date>Friday</date> -- that he had tried to get me at
               <time>five-thirty</time>. My <persName ref="sister">sister</persName> was at our old <placeName type="residence">home</placeName> where there is a <objectName type="communication">telephone</objectName>. The present
               <placeName type="residence">home</placeName> has no <objectName type="communication">telephone</objectName>, and when he happened to call there she was there.</p>

            <p> DORAN: At <time>five-thirty</time> of what day? </p>

            <p> MINTER: <date>Friday</date>; and he ea1d he ms very anxious to see me. She knew I had left and
               wass driving with <persName ref="scarborough">George Scarborough</persName>, and she said she didn't know what time 1 would
               be back. He said well, he wanted me to come to see him before <time>ten o'clock</time>, but after
               <time>ten o'clock</time> he would be on location. He didn't say the <placeName type="station">Salt Lake Station</placeName>, but he was
               very anxious to get hold of me before <time>ten o'clock</time>. I came in after <time>ten</time> and they all
               told me l had better call <persName ref="neilan">Marshall</persName>; he seemed very anxious to get hold of me. I
               didn't· know where to call him; I thought possibly he would come to the <placeName type="residence">house</placeName>. I
               I were you I would call him up or at 1east call <persName ref="mother">his mother</persName> and find out where he is."
               I called the <placeName type="studio">studio</placeName> and the <persName ref="watchman">night watchman</persName> immediately said, "<persName ref="neilan">Mr Neilan</persName> is not here;
               is this <persName ref="minter">Miss Minter</persName>?" I said, "Yes."</p>

            <p> And he said, "<persName ref="neilan" > Mr Neilan</persName> ia at the <placeName type="station">Salt Lake Station</placeName>." <persName ref="scarborough">Mr Scarborough</persName> and l drove
               down there in my runabout. He was very hard at work and had been all <time>night</time>, it seemed
               he had [page 15] been working all night for four nights past. They were all just dead
               tired. <time>Night and day</time> they had been working. He finished about <time>two-thirty</time>, and then
               there were several in the party, <persName ref="swanson">Gloria Swanson</persName>, <persName ref="jpickford">Jack Pickford</persName>, <persName ref="urson">Frank Urson</persName> -- <persName ref="urson">Mr
               Frank Urson</persName> is now associated with <persName ref="neilan">Mr Neilan</persName> as <persName ref="director">director</persName> -- and <persName ref="neilan">Marshall</persName> and myself.
               We went to his <placeName type="residence">mother's home</placeName> where he lives with <persName ref="mother">his mother</persName> and we tried to make <objectName type="eggs">eggs</objectName>
               and things. It was very amusing; we only had four <objectName type="eggs">eggs</objectName>, and I tried to fry two of
               them and ruined the <objectName type="things">things</objectName>, adn we didn't have enough to go around and we made so
               much noise <persName ref="mother">his mother</persName>, who was ill <placeName type="location">upstairs</placeName>, told us we must behave ourselves.
               <persName ref="neilan">Marshall</persName> said, "There is only one thing to do; I have got to talk to you. We have had
               all of this foolishness, and I have got something very important to say to you, <persName ref="minter">Mary</persName>.
               Let's drive to the <placeName type="studio">studio</placeName> where we can talk." We drove down to the <placeName type="studio">Hollywood studio</placeName>
               and we sat there in the <placeName type="office">office</placeName>, the <objectName type="lights">lights</objectName> burning and the <persName ref="watchman">watchman</persName> was there and the
               <persName ref="property man">property man</persName> was not around. He was outside. We talked until <time>dawn</time>; it was <time>dawn</time> when
               we came out of the <placeName type="office">place</placeName>.</p>

            <p> DORAN: What were you talking about?</p>

            <p> MINTER: About <persName ref="taylor">Mr taylor</persName> and letters <persName ref="neilan">Marshall Neilan</persName> had tried to get for me.</p>

            <p> DORAN: Who had tried to get for you?</p>

            <p> MINTER: <persName ref="neilan">Marshall</persName> had tried to get for me, which was the first inkling I knew of his
               knowledge of my <objectName type="document">letters</objectName>, that I had written any to <persName ref="taylor">Mr taylor</persName>. He told me certain
               very, very [page 16]ghastly things have since been proven absolutely true. He told
               them to me in my interest, but they made me very furious at the time, and we left
               more or less in a quarrel.</p>

            <p> DORAN: Will you please tell us everything that he told you there?</p>

            <p> MINTER: Yes, indeed. He first said, "<persName ref="minter">Mary</persName>, sit down. I have something very importnat
               to tell you." I sat down, and he said, "You know this <eventName type="death">murder</eventName> of <persName ref="taylor">Bill</persName> is going to be
               the greatest nine-days wonder" or "nineteen-days wonder that we have ever had,
               certainly that <placeName type="city">Los Angeles</placeName> ever had. You don't know what a terrible thing it is going
               to be." I said, "Yes, I do. It is awful!" He said, "Now, <persName ref="minter">Mary</persName>, I tried to get your
               <objectName type="document">letters</objectName>" --</p>

            <p> DORAN: May I interrupt you a moment? What time did you arrive at his <placeName type="studio">studio</placeName>?</p>

            <p> MINTER: We left location, he worked down at the <placeName type="station">Salt Lake Station</placeName>, about <time>two-thirty
               to a quarter to three</time>, we left there and went to his <placeName type="residence">house</placeName>. How long we were there I
               couldn't say; I didn't have a <objectName type="watch">watch</objectName>; I imagine we were there about an hour or maybe
               more, and then we went on down to the <placeName type="studio">studio</placeName> and we stayed until <time>dawn</time>, whatever time
               that is. We then came on back to my <objectName type="residence">house</objectName>. <persName ref="mother">Mother</persName> was waiting for us and we got out
               and explained to her. <persName ref="mother">Mother</persName> knew he had had a verious talk and she felt sure
               <persName ref="neilan">Marhsall</persName> would try to come to our aid. My <persName ref="mother">mother</persName> is very fond of <persName ref="neilan">Mr Neilan</persName> and the
               whole family. He said he was just dead tired. The man took his hours when hee needed
               sleep to tell me these things. He was going to be up at <time>eight o'clock</time> that morning
               and he didn't even go to bed that night. He just sat up in his clothes and went out
               to work again at <time>eight o'clock</time>. Anyway, he said, "I tried to get your <objectName type="document">letters</objectName> for
               you. You know they are a very important factor in the <eventName type="case">case</eventName>, if they get hold of
               them." I was shocked to find that he knew of my <objectName type="document">letters</objectName>. I said that I wrote some,
               and he said something about going to a newspaper or getting hold of <persName ref="person">some body</persName> in
               <placeName type="city">Pasadena</placeName> to get me the <objectName type="letters">letters</objectName>. That part is not clear in my mind. I think I was so
               tired at the time I couldn't understand him. I haven't seen him since or I would have
               questioned him again about the <objectName type="document">letters</objectName> just what he did. He told me I should have
               received them that <date>day</date>. He asked me if I had gotten them and I said, "No, I haven't
               received the <objectName type="document">letters</objectName> <date>today</date>." He said, "Well, I sent them to the <placeName type="studio">studio</placeName>, and I believe
               the studio," the <placeName type="studio">Realart Studio</placeName> where I had last worked. He said, "They are in
               <persName ref="eyton">Charley Eyton's</persName> hands now." He either said <persName ref="eyton">Charley Eyton</persName> or <persName ref="carbut">Mr Carbut</persName>, but I can't
               state this acutally because I was so tired at the time I could hardly hear him and I
               was desperately interested to hear what he said about the <objectName type="document">letter</objectName>, and I strained all
               my nerves to hear, but instead it came back and forth; it was hazy. I don't know the
               exact words he spoke. Anyway, I remember saying, "Well, there is nothing in the
               <objectName type="document">letters</objectName> that the world can't read except that it is horribly painful to me to have
               them read my <objectName>letters</objectName> to him." He said, "You loved <persName>Billie</persName>, didn't you?" I said, "Yes,
               <persName ref="neilan">Marshall</persName>, I loved him deeply and sincerely." And he said, "Did you ever want to marry
               him?" Whereupon I replied, I said, "No, no; I know it couldn't have been. It was not
               meant to be." Then we talked about -- Oh, yes. Then he said, "Now, <persName ref="minter">Mary</persName>, I am going
               to tell you some very important thing; they are going to hurt you, going to shock
               you, but before I say a word I want you to consider <persName ref="taylor">Billie</persName> was just as crazy as a
               March hare months before his death." He said, "I am going to recite a few instances
               that <persName ref="taylor">Bill</persName> told me about, things irrelevant to you, to show he didn't do this only to
               you but to others of his very <persName ref="person">best friends</persName>." </p>

            <p> <persName ref="neilan">Marshall</persName> and <persName ref="taylor">Mr taylor</persName> were extremely good friends. I don't think they saw each
               other often, but they were most affectionately fond of each other. He said, "On
               several occasions <persName ref="taylor">Bill</persName>" -- he spoke of him as '<persName ref="taylor">Bill</persName>' -- "has confessed to me that --
               Oh, I am so tired I can't think how I am trying­ to say it. He came up to my <placeName type="house">room in
               the club</placeName> one day and he said, "Oh, I know something about you, <persName ref="neilan">Marshall</persName>, and those
               <objectName type="cigarettes">gold-tipped cigarettes</objectName> I found of yours." Whereupon <persName ref="neilan">Marshall</persName> said he replied, "Well,
               you needn't say anything, <persName ref="taylor">Bill</persName>" -- l don't know what it was, a <objectName type="cigar">cigar</objectName> or something of
               some personal nature that he recognized of <persName ref="taylor">Mr taylor's</persName> at somebody's <placeName type="residence">house</placeName>. I don't
               know whose <placeName type="residence">house</placeName>. He said, "That makes us Elks. Don't you say anything about me, what
               I have been doing in a joking, friendly manner." <persName ref="taylor">Mr taylor</persName>, he said, suddenly stood
               up and looked at him very seriously, soberly, and said, "<persName ref="taylor">Marshall</persName>, I am surprised at
               the things you are doing now-a-days." <persName ref="neilan">Marshall</persName> said, "Just what do you mean by that?"
               and he said, "Why, what you said to your <persName ref="wife">wife</persName> the other night at <placeName type="hotel">Sunset Inn</placeName> about
               poor little <placeName ref="swanson">Gloria Swanson</placeName>."</p>

            <p> I may be getting some of those words mixed; maybe he didn't say "poor little <persName ref="swanson">Gloria
               Swanson</persName>." Maybe <persName ref="neilan">Marshall</persName> didn't tell me that. This is my impression. <persName ref="neilan">Marshall</persName> said,
               "What do you mean?" And he said, "Don't you remember the night we were at <placeName type="hotel">Sunset Inn</placeName>
               and you were sitting here and <persName ref="swanson">Miss Swanson</persName> was sitting there and your former wife,
               <persName ref="bambrick">Gertrude Banbrick</persName>, came in and said, 'Hello, <persName ref="gloria">Gloria</persName>, how are you?' and <persName ref="swanson">Gloria</persName> replied
               pleasantly, and you turned to <persName ref="bambrick">Gertrude Bambrick</persName> and said, 'How dare you speak to this
               girl?' pointing to <persName ref="swanson">Gloria</persName>, the <persName ref="person">lady</persName> he was with, 'How dare you speak to her? Don't
               you ever dare to speak to her again,'" And <persName ref="taylor">Mr taylor</persName> was telling <persName ref="neilan">Marshall Neilan</persName>.
               <persName ref="neilan">Marshall</persName> said he looked at him and said, "What's the matter with you, <persName ref="taylor">Bill</persName>? Are you
               drunk?" He said, I haven't had a <objectName type="consumable">drink</objectName>," <persName ref="taylor">Mr taylor</persName> said, and he said, "The funny part
               of it was he wasn't drunk." He couldn't detect it on his breath. "But he looked quite
               as serious and sober as I do this minute." He said, "Why, tell me what day you think
               this was." He said it was on a <date>certain day</date> -- I don't know if <persName ref="neilan">Marshall</persName> told me the
               day or not. He said, on a <date>certain day</date> at <placeName type="hotel">Sunset Inn</placeName> recently. <persName ref="neilan">Marshall</persName> said, "Why,
               <persName ref="taylor">Bill</persName>, at that time l I was in <placeName type="city">New York City</placeName> and was not in <placeName type="city">Los Angeles</placeName> nor
               <placeName type="state">California</placeName>."</p>

            <p> <persName ref="taylor">Mr taylor</persName> and he had quite a friendly argument over it, and he said, "I know it is
               so; I was there myself and heard what you said upon this greeting between those two
               <persName ref="girls">girls</persName>." <persName ref="neilan">Marshall</persName> said he thought perhaps he had lost his mind. The next day he called
               up, haVing that in mind, <persName ref="swanson">Miss Swanson</persName> and he said, "<persName ref="swanson">Gloria</persName>, am I going crazy? Have I
               lost my mind? Do you remember of ever being at <placeName type="hotel">Sunset Inn</placeName> with me when <persName ref="bambrick">Gertrude
                  Bambrick</persName> passed our <placeName type="table">table</placeName> and spoke to us pleasantly and railed at my <persName ref="ex">former wife</persName> for
               having spoken to you pleasantly and told her not to speak to you again?" And she
               said, "What on earth are you talking about? What is this? I don't understand you,"
               And he said, "Do you ever remember seeing <persName ref="taylor">Bill taylor</persName> there near us at any time on
               any such occasion?" And she said, "Certainly not, !the oniy time I ever saw <persName ref="taylor">William
                  taylor</persName> at <placeName type="hotel">Sunset Inn</placeName> was the <date>night</date> I was with" -- I don't know his name, some <persName ref="person">friend
               of hers</persName> -- "and <persName>Bill taylor</persName> was sitting away over on the other side by the <placeName>wall</placeName> and
               we were by the <placeName type="musical">orchestra</placeName> on this side." He said, "Was I there?" And she said, "No.
               Don't you remember you were in <placeName type="city">New York</placeName> at the time?" He said, "That is one instance,
               <persName ref="minter">Mary</persName>, of <persName ref="taylor">Bill</persName>'s failing mind, I have never cleared that up. <persName ref="taylor">Bill</persName> and I have discussed
               it many times since, and I have always gone away puzzled, amazed, that he still stuck
               to his version of my having spoken to my <persName ref="ex">former wife</persName> as I did. I didn't see her;
               neither <persName ref="swanson">Miss Swanson</persName> saw her on that occasion." Then he said, "On another <eventName type="occasion">occasion</eventName>
               <persName ref="taylor">Bill</persName> told me he had received a <objectName type="letter">letter</objectName> from <persName ref="sweet">Blanche Sweet</persName>; that she told <persName ref="taylor">Mr taylor</persName>
               that she was grieved he was sick;" that <persName ref="neilan">Marshell Neilan</persName> was calling on me and she
               intended to sue him. <persName ref="neilan">Marshall</persName> said that sounded so unlike <persName ref="sweet">Miss Sweet</persName> that he went to
               her and questioned her, and he said, "<persName ref="sweet">Blanche</persName>, have you writtn to <persName ref="taylor">Bill</persName> lately?" She
               said, "Why, yes, I wrote him a little <objectName>note</objectName> not so long ago thanking him for some
               <objectName type="flowers">poinsettias</objectName> he sent me <date>Christmas</date>." He aa1d, "Did you say anything else?" She said,
               "No, not that I can remember." He said, "Did you ever say that you regretted my going
               about with <persName ref="minter">Miss Minter</persName> and that you intended to sue me?" She said, "Perfectly
               ridiculous. What do you mean? I certainly did not say any such thing."</p>

            <p> <persName ref="neilan">Marshall</persName> at that time said to me, "And you know <persName ref="sweet">Blanche</persName> doesn't lie. She certainly
               doesn't lie; tbat is her reputation all over the world, over the picture game. I have
               heard that hundreds of times myself; I am pretty sure it is so." He said, "Now, that
               is another instance of poor <persName ref="taylor">Bill</persName>'s insanity. Now, <persName ref="minter">Mary</persName>, here is the ghastly thing I
               have to tell you." He said, "One time" -- I don't know whether he said in his <placeName>room</placeName> or
               the <placeName type="club">club</placeName>, he was somewhere, I think in one of his own <placeName type="house">rooms</placeName>, he, <persName ref="neilan">Marshall Nieilan</persName>,
               and <persName ref="hoyt">Arthur Hoyt</persName>, <persName ref="robinson">Cap Robinson</persName> -- He said "<persName ref="robinson">Cap Robinson</persName>"; maybe he meant "Captain"; I
               don't know; I don't know how he is; I know <persName ref="hoyt">Arthur</persName> well. He said, "We were all
               standing around there talking pleasantly" -- I think he said <persName ref="moreno">Antonio Moreno</persName> was
               there. He said, "We were all talking pleasantly and <persName ref="taylor">Mr taylor</persName> suddenly started
               talking about you, and the talk grew finally more and more personal and finally he
               said -- and this is terrible -- 'presently he said you had been over in the last two
               weeks" -- I should say this is within at least three weeks of <persName ref="taylor">Mr taylor</persName>'s <eventName>death</eventName>; I
               think <persName ref="neilan">Marshall</persName> told me at the time, but I have forgotten the time. -- "within the
               last two weeks, that you were undressed in his <placeName type="residence">apartments</placeName>; that you beseeched him for
               his love; that he resisted you, and finally persuaded you to leave his
               <placeName type="residence">apartments</placeName>."</p>

         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
