<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>HUMN100 FALL 2025: The Murder of William Desmond Taylor</title>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Diane Jakacki</persName>
               <resp>Instructor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Waina Ali</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Jada Alvarez</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Colin Caricato</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>John Cochran</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Lucy DiChristina</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Nick Eisele-Bockelkamp</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Ethan Esclamado</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Spencer Firestone</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Henry Gibbons</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Daniel Hou</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Campbell Killian</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Olivia King</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>William Le</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Charlie Meehleib</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Carter Morton</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Kate Reyen</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Blythe Sena</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Hunter Sloan</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Rylie Smith</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Lily Stein</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Riley Twiss</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Katrina von Behren</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Emma Walkowiak</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Amanda Woertz</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Produced by members of the HUMN100: Introduction to Text Analysis course, Fall 2025</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>These interviews and statements are gathered from a number of sources, including "Taylorology" and Robert Giroux's Deed of Death</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="interview">
            <head>Interview with Charles Eyton</head>
            <byline>Ethan Esclamado</byline>
                           
               <p>Coroner's Inquest Transcript</p>
               
               <p>The following is the transcript of the shorthand notes taken at the Coroner's inquest held on the body of William Desmond Taylor at Ivy H. Overholtzer [Mortuary] at Los Angeles, California on the 4th day of February, 1922 at 10:00 a.m.</p>
               
               <p>CHARLES EYTON: NANCE, Coroner Charles Eyton, being first duly sworn, testified as follows:</p>
               
               <p>BY THE CORONER:</p>
               
               <p>NANCE: 	Please state your name.</p>
               
               <p>EYTON: 	Charles Eyton.</p>
               
               <p>NANCE: 	Where do you reside?</p>
               
               <p>EYTON: 	1920 Vine Street, Hollywood.</p>
               
               <p>NANCE: 	What is your occupation?</p>
               
               <p>EYTON: 	General Manager, Famous Players-Lasky Corporation.</p> 
               
               <p>NANCE: 	Mr. Eyton, have you seen the remains of the deceased in the adjoining room?</p> 
               
               <p>EYTON: 	Yes, sir.</p>
               
               <p>NANCE: 	Do you recognize them as one you knew in life?</p>
               
               <p>EYTON: 	Yes, sir.</p>
               
               <p>NANCE:	Who was it.</p>
               
               <p>EYTON: 	William Desmond Taylor.</p>
               
               <p>NANCE:	Where was he born?</p>
               
               <p>EYTON: 	He was born in Ireland, to the best of my knowledge. He told me so.</p>
               
               <p>NANCE:	What was his age?</p>
               
               <p>EYTON: 	Forty-four, I should judge. [He was forty-nine.]</p>
               
               <p>NANCE:	Was he married, single or a widower?</p>
               
               <p>EYTON: 	He was married. [He was divorced as of 1916.]</p>
               
               <p>NANCE:	When did he die?</p>
               
               <p>EYTON: 	Thursday morning or Wednesday night. I saw the body first on Thursday morning.</p>
               
               <p>NANCE:	Last Thursday?</p>
               
               <p>EYTON: 	Yes, sir.</p>
               
               <p>NANCE:	Do you recall that date?</p>
               
               <p>EYTON: 	It was the 2nd.</p>
               
               <p>NANCE:	February 2nd?</p>
               
               <p>EYTON: 	February 2nd.</p>
               
               <p>NANCE:	Where did he die?</p>
               
               <p>EYTON: 	EYTON: the EYTON: Apartment "B," South Alvarado Street, 404 I think it was.</p>
               
               <p>NANCE: 	What was the cause of his death, if you know?</p>
               
               <p>EYTON: 	Well, Mr. Taylor's assistant [Harry Fellows] rang me up at my residence about, I should judge, eight o'clock, and told me Mr. Taylor had died suddenly; so I immediately went over to his residence, and he was lying on the floor on his back. Detective Ziegler was there and he had called the doctor, he told me, previous to my arrival; and the doctor told me Mr. Taylor had died from hemorrhage of the stomach. Mr. Maclean - Douglas Maclean - had told me that he had thought he had heard a shot the night before, and his wife also thought she had heard a shot - and he wanted the body turned over; they didn't want to turn it over until the coroner came. The deputy coroner came after a while, and he told us he had died of hemorrhage of the stomach, and I told him he had better turn the body over to make sure, and he put his hand under Mr. Taylor's body, and found a little - when he pulled his hand out, it had a little blood on his hand. Douglas asked him what that was, and he said it evidently had run down from his [Taylor's] mouth, but I noticed that there was no trail of blood-Mr. Taylor's head was in a pool of blood - there was no trail of blood running down.
               </p>
               <p>NANCE:	There was a pool of blood under his head?</p>
               
               <p>EYTON: 	Under his head, yes, a little pool of blood. I immediately opened up Mr. Taylor's vest, and looked, and looked on the right-hand side, and there was no mark. I looked on the left-hand side and saw some blood, and then I told the Deputy Coroner that I thought that evidence enough to turn his body over to see what would happen. I sent for a pillow to put under Mr. Taylor's head, and we turned him over - the Deputy Coroner and myself - and we pulled his shirt and his vest up, and we found the bullet wound.
               </p>
               <p>NANCE:	Mr. Eyton, was his body stone cold at that time?</p>
               
               <p>EYTON: 	Stone cold and very stiff and rigid.</p>
               
               <p>NANCE:	Indicating that it had been dead for some time?</p>
               
               <p>EYTON: 	Yes.</p>
               
               <p>NANCE:	Where was the body lying with reference to the front entrance to his home?</p>
               
               <p>EYTON: 	It was lying right in front of a little desk with the head pointed east and the feet pointed west. I should judge the feet were three or four feet from the door - the front entrance.
               </p>
               <p>NANCE:	Who were present when you was there?</p>
               
               <p>EYTON: 	When I came in, the first man I noticed was Detective Ziegler, whom I have known for a number of years, and Douglas Maclean; Charles Maigne; the landlord [E. C. Jessurun]; and Harry Fellows, Mr. Taylor's assistant director.
               </p>
               <p>NANCE:	Did all of these persons live there in this neighborhood?</p>
               
               <p>EYTON: 	That I could not tell you. Mr. MacLean did, I know, because he showed me where his apartment was.
               </p>
               <p>NANCE:	The place Mr. Taylor lived was in a court?</p>
               
               <p>EYTON: 	In a court, yes.</p>
               
               <p>NANCE:	These other buildings were nearby?</p>
               
               <p>EYTON: 	There are several apartments in this court, all the way around.</p>
               
               <p>NANCE:	Did Mr. and Mrs. MacLean, or either of them, tell you about the hour that they heard the gunshot?</p>
               
               <p>EYTON: 	Yes, Mr. Maclean told me it was about eight or a quarter after eight, and Mrs. Maclean thought it was a little later. [This is not correct.]
               </p>
               <p>NANCE:	That night?</p>
               
               <p>EYTON: 	Yes, the night before.</p>
               
               <p>NANCE:	You didn't make any definite measurements as to the position of the body?</p>
               
               <p>EYTON: 	No, sir.</p>
               
               <p>NANCE:	So that what you testified to is only an estimate, and nothing definite about it.</p>
               
               <p>EYTON: 	Yes.</p>
               
               <p>NANCE:	Now, how long has Mr. Taylor lived in this place?</p>
               
               <p>EYTON: 	That I could not tell you. He lived in it before he went to the war, I believe.</p>
               
               <p>NANCE:	When did you last see him alive?</p>
               
               <p>EYTON: 	The same day - Wednesday.</p>
               
               <p>NANCE:	Now, did he have any fire-arms of his own?</p>
               
               <p>EYTON: 	I believe he had a revolver; I believe the revolver was in the upper drawer upstairs; in fact, I know there was, because Detective Ziegler and myself went up there and saw it.
               </p>
               <p>NANCE:	When you were called to this place, did you see any fire-arms in this room where he was?</p>
               
               <p>EYTON: 	No.</p>
               
               <p>NANCE:	What is the name of his valet, or attendant there?</p>
               
               <p>EYTON: 	Harry Peavey, the colored cook. I never knew him or saw him.</p>
               
               <p>NANCE:	Was he the one who called you?</p>
               
               <p>EYTON: 	Harry Fellows, his assistant director, was the one who called me.</p>
               
               <p>NANCE:	You have no independent knowledge of the manner in which he met his death?</p>
               
               <p>EYTON: 	No, sire.</p>
               
               <p>THE CORONER: Have you any questions, gentlemen?</p> 
               
               <p>NANCE:	(By a Juror) Was his clothing ruffled in any way, showing any violence?</p>
               
               <p>EYTON: 	No, absolutely none; it looked like he just walked in the door and was shot in the back; that is the way it looked. It didn't show evidence in the room when I got there- neither the room or the body showed any evidence of a struggle. He had on the same suit as when I seen him the day before when he talked to me.
               </p>
               <p>THE CORONER:	Is there any other questions? That is all, you may be excused.</p>
               
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
