<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>HUMN100 FALL 2025: The Murder of William Desmond Taylor</title>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Diane Jakacki</persName>
               <resp>Instructor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Waina Ali</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Jada Alvarez</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Colin Caricato</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>John Cochran</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Lucy DiChristina</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Nick Eisele-Bockelkamp</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Ethan Esclamado</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Spencer Firestone</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Henry Gibbons</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Daniel Hou</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Campbell Killian</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Olivia King</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>William Le</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Charlie Meehleib</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Carter Morton</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Kate Reyen</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Blythe Sena</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Hunter Sloan</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Rylie Smith</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Lily Stein</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Riley Twiss</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Katrina von Behren</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Emma Walkowiak</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Amanda Woertz</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Produced by members of the HUMN100: Introduction to Text Analysis course, Fall
               2025</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>These interviews and statements are gathered from a number of sources, including
               "Taylorology" and Robert Giroux's Deed of Death</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="interview">
            <head>Interview With Julia C. Ivers</head>
            <byline>Liv King</byline>
            <p> Interviews with <persName ref="ivers">Julia Crawford Ivers</persName>
            </p>
            <p>
               <persName ref="ivers">Julia Crawford Ivers</persName> was closely associated with
                  <persName ref="taylor"> Taylor</persName> for over six years and wrote the
               scenarios for most of his <orgName type="company">Paramount</orgName> films. After
                  <persName ref="taylor"> Taylor's </persName> murder, her career soon faded.</p>
            <p><persName ref="minter">When Mary Miles Minter</persName> was interrogated by Deputy
               District Attorney William Doran<persName/>, on February 7, 1922, <persName
                  ref="minter">Minter</persName> recalled a conversation with <persName ref="neilan"
                  > Marshall Neilan</persName> in which <persName ref="minter">Minter</persName>
               stated that the only person she could think of who might have killed <persName
                  ref="taylor">Taylor</persName> was <persName ref="ivers"> Julia Crawford
                  Ivers</persName>. But <persName ref="ivers">Ivers</persName> was never seriously
               considered a suspect.</p>
            <p>Reticent and shy of personal publicity, she gave very few interviews throughout her
               career. [17] The following are some isolated exceptions:</p>

            <p> October 16, 1920 Giebler MOVING PICTURE WORLD I had the pleasure of making the
               acquaintance of <persName ref="ivers">Julia Crawford Ivers</persName>, of the
                  <placeName type="setting">scenario department</placeName>, a lady who occupies a
               large and closely written page in the "Who's Who and Why, and What and When, and
               Where, and How Come" of <placeName type="studio">Filmland</placeName>.</p>
            <p><persName ref="ivers">Miss Ivers</persName> says she has done almost everything
               around a <placeName type="setting">studio</placeName> but sweep <objectName
                  type="floor">the floor</objectName>. She was six years at the <placeName
                  type="studio">Morosco studio</placeName> before coming to the <placeName
                  type="company">Lasky plant</placeName>, where she held every position from film
               cutter and editor to superintendent of the plant. [<persName ref="ivers"
                  >Ivers</persName> also directed several films.] <persName ref="ivers">Miss
                  Ivers</persName> has a large number of original stories and adaptations to her
               credit, including Tom Sawyer, Huck and Tom, The Furnace, The Soul of Youth, two
               stories as yet unnamed to be produced by <persName ref="minter">Mary Miles
                  Minter</persName>, and The Witching Hour, now being made by <persName ref="taylor"
                  >William D. Taylor</persName>; and in addition to this, she has published
                  <objectName type="document">stories and articles </objectName>in many of the
               leading <objectName type="document">magazines</objectName>. She is a person of
               decided opinions as to the writer and his relation to the finished film.</p>
            <p> "The writer is only a helper," she says, "and sometimes very poor help. More stories
               have been spoiled than made by writers who tried to put them in <objectName
                  type="possession">picture</objectName> form, and if many of the writers who are
               yelping for credit on the screen should be debited with the lack of imagination and
               lack of vision they display, they would have no more to say."</p>



            <p> February 7, 1922 LOS ANGELES EXAMINER <persName ref="ivers">Julia Crawford
                  Ivers</persName>, scenarist for the late <persName ref="taylor">William D.
                  Taylor</persName>, yesterday gave out the following statement:</p>
            <p> "Today the friends of <persName ref="taylor">William D. Taylor</persName>, and they
               are legion, will gather to pay the last tribute to the man they love, to one who as
               man, director and friend measured 100 per cent. </p>
            <p> "I have worked side by side with this man for seven years. We have solved many
               difficult problems together, sometimes pleasant, sometimes unpleasant: always hard,
               trying nerve-wracking. And during all these years of close association I have never
               known him to do one unkind, one ungenerous act, but I have known hundreds of
               instances of open-handed generosity and in most cases the beneficiary never knew whom
               to thank.</p>
            <p>"This man whose loyalty and honor were without question, who takes with him the
               undying gratitude of the thousands to whom he has lent a helping hand--this man who
               stood for everything that was fine and clean in <objectName type="possession"
                  >picture</objectName>, who is known to have declared that if it were necessary to
               his success to produce unclean <objectName type="possession">picture</objectName> he
               would go back to the white, clean snows of <placeName type="state">Alaska</placeName>
               and dig his living out of the ground--this man was shot in the back by a cowardly
               assassin. He was given no opportunity to defend himself and <persName ref="taylor"
                  >William D. Taylor</persName> would have defended himself, for he did not know the
               meaning of the word fear. And more cowardly than the <objectName type="gun"
                  >assassin's bullet</objectName>, lodged in<objectName type="bodyPart"> the
                  heart</objectName> of this dear man, is the tongue of scandal, which safely
               sheltered behind his <objectName type="body">dead body</objectName>, is striking at
               his reputation--more cowardly for he is powerless to defend himself.</p>
            <p>"His friends know that when it is all over the character of <persName ref="taylor"
                  >Mr. Taylor</persName> will stand, as it always has stood, for everything that is
               fine and worth while.</p>
            <p>"<objectName type="possession">The good book</objectName> says, 'Let him who is
               without sin cast the first stone.' And it is recorded that no stones were cast."</p>


            <p> April 29, 1922 HONOLULU ADVERTISER Scenario Writer is Seeking Material from Old
               Hawaiian Legends <placeName type="state">Hawaii</placeName> may really find favor in
               the big <placeName type="studio">motion picture studios</placeName> and its wealth of
               legendary lore form the subject of a play or two to be presented to millions of movie
               fans under the name of <persName ref="lasky"> Jesse Lasky</persName>, providing
                  <persName ref="ivers">Miss Julia Crawford Ivers</persName>, his foremost scenario
               writer, find the legends and myths appropriate for filming.</p>
            <p><persName ref="ivers">Miss Ivers</persName> arrived on the Matsonia from <placeName
                  type="city">Los Angeles</placeName>, accompanied by her secretary, Miss
               Aldrich<persName/>, and although here but three days, she is already delving deep
               into legends and also the history of <placeName type="state">Hawaii</placeName>,
               particularly that relating to old feudal <placeName type="state"
               >Hawaii</placeName>.</p>
            <p>Whether her readings, her conversations <placeName type="set">with Island</placeName>
               folk acquainted with legends, and her observations, will lead her into the path that
               will eventually open out into the appropriate theme, she does not know, but she has
               hopes.</p>
            <p>To further acquaint herself with <placeName type="set">the Islands</placeName> and to
               absorb the atmosphere of old and new <placeName type="state">Hawaii</placeName>, she
               will visit <placeName type="set">Kauai</placeName> next week, leaving here Monday or
               Tuesday night and remaining a few days on the <placeName type="set">Garden
                  Island</placeName>.</p>
            <p>The following week she will go to <placeName type="set">Hilo</placeName>, taking her
               car, and will motor over to <placeName type="set">Kalapana</placeName>, all through
                  <placeName type="set">Puna</placeName>, thence to <placeName type="set">the
                  Volcano</placeName>, and then around to <placeName type="set">Kona</placeName>,
               where she will learn all she can of <placeName type="set">Kealakekua Bay</placeName>,
               the scene of Captain Cook's<persName/> discovery and tragedy; the city of refuge at
                  <placeName type="set">Honaunau</placeName> and may possibly go into <placeName
                  type="set">Kohala</placeName>, which abounds in historic wealth.</p>
            <p><persName ref="ivers">Miss Ivers</persName> says she has been a scenario writer with
               the <persName ref="lasky">Lasky</persName> interest for about eight years and during
               seven years of that time was closely associated in motion <objectName
                  type="possession">picture</objectName> production with <persName ref="taylor"
                  >William D. Taylor</persName>, whose tragic death caused a temporary suspension of
               much work planned.</p>
            <p>"<persName ref="taylor">Mr. Taylor</persName> was a splendid <objectName
                  type="possession">picture</objectName> director," said <persName ref="ivers">Miss
                  Ivers</persName>. "He was a man of fine attainments. He was sympathetic and those
               who worked with and under his direction regarded him as one with whom it was a
               pleasure to be associated.</p>
            <p>"My own work as a scenario writer was pleasurable from the fact that there was
               co-operation. He wanted the best and we desired to give him only the best. He was a
               credit to the motion <objectName type="possession">picture</objectName> service and
               will be a loss to it, for he was of a constructive type, doing the best with the
               highest class of material."</p>
            <p>It was partly because of his death that <persName ref="ivers">Miss Ivers</persName>
               dropped her own activities for a time, superinduced by a cold, resulting in the end
               in a determination to visit <placeName type="state">Hawaii</placeName>, with
                  <persName ref="lasky">Mr. Lasky's</persName> injunction that she delve into
               Hawaiian legends and find whether any of them can be filmed.</p>
            <p><persName ref="ivers">Miss Ivers</persName> is at the <placeName type="state">Seaside
                  hotel</placeName>. She makes no promises, but is reading much about Hawaii. She is
               dictating morning and afternoon. She is going here and there where details of
               Hawaiian life may be learned.</p>
            <p>If such a motion <objectName type="possession">picture</objectName>play is to be
               written it may not deal entirely with legends, but legends may be woven into a modern
               type of play. The story of the Goddess Pele<persName/>, who dwells in <placeName
                  type="set">Kilauea volcano</placeName>, has attracted much of her attention and
               her own visit to the volcano in a week or so will have that much more interest for
               her. There is a dramatic, tragic, firey element in Pele<persName/> which may be
               converted to the screen, in her opinion.</p>
            <p> Much of <persName ref="ivers">Miss Ivers'</persName> work at the studio in Los
               Angeles is associated directly with literary folk, writers of <objectName
                  type="possession">books</objectName> whose names are known throughout the reading
                  world--<persName ref="parker">Sir Gilbert Parker</persName>, <persName
                  ref="maugham">Sydney [sic] Maugham</persName>, <persName ref="glyn">Elinor
                  Glyn</persName> and many others. It is <persName ref="ivers">Miss Ivers</persName>
               who takes their <objectName type="possession">books</objectName> and prepares or
               directs the preparation of scenarios for the director.</p>
            <p>It is this contact between the scenario writer and the authors that counts for
               success or failure in the motion <objectName type="possession">picture</objectName>
               product. If the scenario writer is sympathetic and endeavors to get the soul of the
               author's intent, there are exceptional possibilities. If not, there is more likely to
               be a failure in the interpretation.</p>
            <p> Many <objectName type="possession">books</objectName> to be screened must be ripped
               to pieces. As the story is written it can seldom be filmed. The change is the task of
               the scenario writer.</p>
            <p>Life must have been lived by scenario writers to really interpret a story for the
               screen for the eyes of the millions of theater patrons. Phases of life that are near
               the raw edge of actuality and realism may not be interpreted by the old maid who has
               not seen life and whose first impulse, and probably her last, is to eliminate that
               particular phase. A man of sensual thought may regard that particular phase as one to
               work into a maudlin interpretation which would be offensive.</p>
            <p> Between these two extremes there is the middle course and that path must be taken by
               the writer who understands life and understands the multiplicity of types and
               characters that patronize the theaters.</p>
            <p>
               <persName ref="ivers">Miss Ivers</persName> is a hard worker. She maintains high
               ideals as to <objectName type="possession">picture</objectName> production. Hers is a
               constant study of human nature. Philosophy and psychology are tangible factors with
               her, for both play important parts in decisions as to the worth of stories and the
               filmed product.</p>
            <p>"I must necessarily write in dashes where authors employ sentences and paragraphs,"
               said <persName ref="ivers">Miss Ivers</persName> discussing her method of writing. "I
               cull and cut, where book writers must enlarge and pad."</p>



            <p> October 3, 1922 HONOLULU STAR-BULLETIN A dramatic love story with all the gripping
               beauty of the <placeName type="set">Hawaiian islands</placeName> as a background is
               what <persName ref="ivers">Mrs. Julia Crawford Ivers</persName>, scenario writer and
               director for the <orgName type="production">Lasky corporation</orgName>, has come to
                  <placeName type="set">Honolulu </placeName>to film.</p>
            <p> The beaches, mountains, gardens and palm trees of <placeName type="set">Oahu
               </placeName>and <placeName type="state">Hawaii</placeName> are to provide the setting
               for the story, which <persName ref="ivers">Mrs. Ivers</persName> says could be
               produced nowhere else in the world. "I wrote the scenario here," she told a
               representative of the Star-Bulletin at <placeName type="set"> the Moana</placeName>
               today, "and this is the only spot in the universe where it can be filmed as it should
               be. It is imbued with the breath of <placeName type="set">the islands</placeName>.
               When I returned to <placeName type="city">Los Angeles </placeName>after my visit here
               last spring, at which time I gathered material for the scenario, <persName
                  ref="lasky">Mr. Lasky</persName> asked me if the <objectName type="possession"
                  >picture</objectName> could not be produced on <placeName type="set">the
                  mainland</placeName>. 'I'll read you the story,' I replied, and I did. He had
               nothing more to say, and here we are ready to work.</p>
            <p>While the <objectName type="possession">picture</objectName> was not planned with the
               specific idea of giving publicity to <placeName type="set">the islands</placeName>,
               it still will be of tremendous benefit in portraying to mainland people the marvels
               of this section of the globe. It will be a true mirror in which those of the outer
               world may see life as it is lived in the Paradise of the Pacific.</p>
            <p> "I wrote the story," <persName ref="ivers">Mrs. Ivers</persName> said, "with a
               genuine love and affection for the islands, and I will produce it in the same way. No
               'roughneck' of a director will have a chance to squeeze the fragrance out of the
               plot, for I am going to direct the action myself. It is some time since I did that
               sort of work, but I have chosen my cast and staff myself. I know something of the
               atmosphere of <placeName type="state">Hawaii</placeName> and I wrote the story
               myself. I am just sure that if we can get things into film as we see them here the
               island will owe us a very great deal of gratitude.</p>
            <p> "One scene will be taken showing the departure of a steamer and including that
               lovable custom of giving leis, which is to me most touching. When I left <placeName
                  type="setting">Honolulu</placeName> last spring returning to <placeName
                  type="city">Los Angeles</placeName> I cried as the boat pulled away from the dock.
               I was not leaving a host of friends either, but there is something about the strains
               of 'Aloha Oe' which brings the moisture to the eyes and a catch to the throat. This
               atmosphere is what we hope to catch in our <objectName type="possession"
                  >picture</objectName>, and we hope that when it comes back to <placeName
                  type="set">Honolulu </placeName>as a finished product the people will think that
               we have done full justice to our theme."</p>
            <p>
               <persName ref="ivers">Mrs. Ivers</persName> is a pioneer in the moving <objectName
                  type="possession">picture</objectName> profession, having been identified with it
               in every sort of a capacity for the last nine years. She knows the game from A to Z.
               "I will have no one to blame if I fail to get a good <objectName type="possession"
                  >picture</objectName>," she says. "<persName ref="lasky">Mr. Lasky</persName>
               permitted me to select my own cast and to choose my technical force, camera man, art
               director and all. I am in full charge and I have every confidence in my company.
               There is not a person in it who will not go the limit to do as he or she is told. I
               know they will all give their very best to make the <objectName type="possession"
                  >picture</objectName> a success."</p>
            <p>
               <persName ref="ivers">Mrs. Ivers</persName> believes she is especially fortunate in
               her choice of her art director, George Hopkins<persName/>. "He is really very
               superior," she said, "and has done some wonderful work on interiors. He has a weird
               touch which makes his work stand out."</p>
            <p> While a number of locations have been chosen, <persName ref="ivers">Mrs.
                  Ivers</persName> said that they may not be used. "You see," she said, "the art
               director, the camera man, and electrician always inspect a location before we begin
               to 'shoot.' If any one of them has a fault to find I simply give up the location and
               seek something else that will be suitable. The art director and <objectName
                  type="film">the camera</objectName> man have to produce the artistic part of
                  <objectName type="film">the film </objectName>. I have my company in the center of
               the location and I am often called upon to move the actors to one side or another in
               order that <objectName type="film">the camera</objectName> may register striking
               features that may be at one side or the other of those of the cast. It would never do
               to have <objectName type="film">the film </objectName>unbalanced."</p>
            <p>The very newest in motion <objectName type="possession">picture</objectName>
               <objectName type="film">cameras</objectName>s will be used by the company here.
                  <objectName type="film">The "Mitchell,"</objectName> a machine which combines all
               of the good points of all other <objectName type="film">cameras</objectName> with
               none of their bad points, is included in the equipment brought from <placeName
                  type="set">the mainland</placeName>. There also are <objectName type="film">two
                  other older style cameras</objectName> to be used.</p>
            <p>It is possible that work of filming may start before Friday, <persName ref="ivers"
                  >Mrs. Ivers</persName> said.</p>



         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
