<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>HUMN100 FALL 2025: The Murder of William Desmond Taylor</title>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Diane Jakacki</persName>
               <resp>Instructor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Waina Ali</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Jada Alvarez</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Colin Caricato</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>John Cochran</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Lucy DiChristina</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Nick Eisele-Bockelkamp</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Ethan Esclamado</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Spencer Firestone</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Henry Gibbons</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Daniel Hou</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Campbell Killian</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Olivia King</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>William Le</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Charlie Meehleib</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Carter Morton</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Kate Reyen</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Blythe Sena</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Hunter Sloan</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Rylie Smith</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Lily Stein</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Riley Twiss</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Katrina von Behren</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Emma Walkowiak</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Amanda Woertz</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Produced by members of the HUMN100: Introduction to Text Analysis course, Fall
               2025</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>These interviews and statements are gathered from a number of sources, including
               "Taylorology" and Robert Giroux's Deed of Death</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="interview">
            <head>Interview with Mrs.Charlotte Shelby</head>
            <byline>William Le</byline>

            <p> MRS. CHARLOTTE SHELBY mother of Mary M.Minter Statement taken 4-9-26 </p>


            <p> POLICE: During the time in the east there, when he (Taylor) was directing her
               (Mary), did you observe any awakening of a friendship or love between the two of
               them?</p>

            <p>SHELBY: No.</p>

            <p>POLICE: When did you first see that, or did you at all?</p>

            <p>SHELBY: I never did know it, <persName ref="Keyes">Mr. Keyes</persName>, until <persName ref="Mott">Mr. Mott</persName> told
               me of the letters that had been found in Taylor's <placeName type="home">drawer</placeName> that
               absolutely is convincing that there had been something there.</p>

            <p>POLICE: You mean after he was killed</p>

            <p>SHELBY: Yes, and <persName ref="Eyton">Mr. Eyton</persName> told me also after <persName ref="Taylor">Mr. Taylor</persName>
               was killed that he knew that, that he knew for a long time that <persName ref="Mary">Mary</persName> and <persName ref="Taylor">Mr.
                  Taylor</persName> had been intimate, and I said then "<persName ref="Eyton"> Mr. Eyton</persName> you
               should have told me."</p>

            <p>POLICE: During that time. <persName ref="Shelby">Mrs. Shelby</persName> (referring to latter part of 1919
               and early part of 1920), was Mary going around with Taylor to your knowledge at
               all?</p>

            <p>SHELBY: Why no, and <persName ref="Taylor">Mr. Taylor</persName> was the most perfectly poised man, such a
               proper man. He would take Mary out to <name type="event">dinner</name> and he would invariably invite me and my
               mother to go to dinner with them.</p>

            <p>POLICE: Did you make any objections?</p>

            <p>SHELBY: Not the least in the world.</p>

            <p>POLICE: Were you friendly with him?</p>

            <p>SHELBY: Oh, yes. ***</p>

            <p>POLICE: Do you remember anyone in particular with whom she was associating at that
               time?</p>

            <p>SHELBY: It wasn't men. Men hadn't begun to give me any trouble at that time. It was
               women.</p>

            <p>POLICE: Who was that?</p>

            <p>SHELBY: <persName ref="Jeannie">Jeannie McPherson</persName>.</p>

            <p>POLICE: Taylor's name never entered into <name type="conversation">the discussion</name> then?</p>

            <p>SHELBY: No. I always felt that, when <persName>Mary</persName> was out with <persName ref="Taylor">Mr.
                  Taylor</persName> she was under a good influence. ***</p>

            <p>POLICE: Did you ever have any words with <persName ref="Taylor">Mr. Taylor</persName> over
                  <persName ref="Mary">Mary</persName>?</p>

            <p>SHELBY: Never a word, never the slightest word. (Speaking of the time <persName ref="Shelby">Mrs.
                  Shelby</persName> went to <placeName type="house">Taylor's home</placeName> at 2 a.m. looking for
                  <name>Mary</name>).</p>

            <p>POLICE: Did this secretary of yours, <persName ref="Whitney">Miss Whitney</persName>, go in <placeName type="house">the
                  house</placeName> with you?</p>

            <p>SHELBY: No, I know she didn’t because there was nobody in <placeName ref="house">the
                  room</placeName> but <persName>Mr. Taylor</persName> and me. She stayed in the <objectName ref="vehicle">car.</objectName></p>

            <p>POLICE: Did you have any weapon with you at that time?</p>

            <p> SHELBY: Good lord, no.</p>

            <p>POLICE: You are sure you didn't have <objectName type="weapon">a revolver</objectName> with
               you?</p>

            <p>SHELBY: No, <persName ref="Keyes">Mr. Keyes</persName>.</p>

            <p>POLICE: Well, you owned <objectName type="weapon">a revolver</objectName> at that time?</p>

            <p>SHELBY: No. If I owned <objectName type="weapon">a revolver</objectName> at that time, I don’t
               know where it was. It was thrown away.</p>

            <p>POLICE: What date was it when you were at <placeName type="home">Mr. Taylor's home</placeName> that you were telling
               about?</p>

            <p>SHELBY: I think I could almost fix that date,<persName ref="Keyes"> Mr. Keyes</persName>, referring to
                  <objectName type="book">a certain little book</objectName>, you know. Because I was reading
                  <objectName type="diary">Mary's diary</objectName> and she goes on to say in this
               <objectName type="diary">diary</objectName> that she and I had some little words that evening,
               you see, and she has written it very clearly, about the small girl going out in a
               huff, etc., and she adds that mother was right. **** And I think the date of that
               happeningis right in her diary.</p>

            <p>POLICE: Did you ever make a threat to kill<persName ref="Taylor"> Mr. Taylor</persName></p>

            <p>SHELBY: No, <persName ref="Keyes">Mr. Keyes</persName>. I never had any reason or desire to kill
                  <persName ref="Taylor">Mr. Taylor</persName>.</p>

            <p>POLICE: And you are positive, are you, <persName ref="Shelby">Mrs. Shelby</persName>, that you never at
               any time threatened <persName ref="Taylor">Mr. Taylor</persName>?</p>

            <p>SHELBY: Certainly not, I had no reason. I never threatened to shot <persName ref="Taylor">Mr.
                  Taylor</persName>. I don't think I ever threatened to shoot any man. To shoot him? No,
               because I had no reason. I had no provocation. I never had a quarrel with <persName ref="Taylor">Mr.
                  Taylor</persName> in my life.</p>

            <p>POLICE: You spoke of having thrown <objectName type="weapon">a gun</objectName> away?</p>

            <p>SHELBY: No, my mother did that.</p>

            <p>POLICE: That was your gun?</p>

            <p>SHELBY: Yes. It was <objectName type="weapon">a gun</objectName> I used once. I shot it once and
               once was enough.</p>

            <p>POLICE: How long had you had <objectName type="weapon">the gun</objectName>?</p>

            <p>SHELBY: <objectName type="weapon">The gun</objectName> was given to me in Santa Barbara by
               <persName ref="Harry Eaves">Harry Eaves</persName>, who has <placeName type="jewelry_shop">a jewelry shop</placeName> up there — <objectName type="weapon">a very
                  short little pistoi</objectName> - a little automatic - ***** and he said to me,
               "I have got two and you ought to have one.</p>

            <p>POLICE: Where did you say you shot it once?</p>

            <p>SHELBY: I got a friend of mine to take me out in <placeName type="Santa_Barbara">Santa
               Barbara</placeName>, just off the road, and we shot it into a bank and I shot it
               once.</p>

            <p>POLICE: Did you ever do any target practice with it?</p>

            <p>SHELBY: Yes, that one time. It was enough for me. The thing was too short. I can
               shoot a long pistol. I wouldn’t mind shooting <objectName type="weapon">a shot gun</objectName>. ***</p>

            <p>POLICE: Well, <persName ref="Shelby">Mrs. Shelby</persName>, <persName ref="Mary">Mary</persName> shot that
                  <objectName type="weapon">pistol</objectName> off one time, didn't she?</p>

            <p>SHELBY: Yes, she shot it off twice.</p>

            <p>POLICE: Was that the "suicide"?</p>

            <p>SHELBY: That’s the “suicide” (Re: supposed suicide) "Well, we were living at
                  <placeName type="home">56 Fremont Place</placeName>. **** I remember the secretary was there
               that night, <persName ref="Whitney">Miss Whitney</persName> *** She (Mary) rushed up <objectName type="home">the
                  stairs</objectName> saying "I am going to end it, all. I am going to end it all.
               ** Then <persName ref="Charlotte">Charlotte</persName> (Miss “Whitney) said to me, "<persName ref="Shelby">Mrs.
                  Shelby</persName>, oh, <persName ref="Shelby">Mrs. Shelby</persName>, there's a pistol in your <placeName type="home">closet</placeName>." ***
               But she ran up the stairs and ran in my room and closed the door.</p>

            <p>POLICE: Did she lock <placeName type="home">the door</placeName>?</p>

            <p>SHELBY: Oh, locked <placeName type="home">the door</placeName>, and the first thing we knew- bang. *** and a second more
               and - bang – the second shot. **** The chauffeur (<persName ref="Chauncey">Chauncey Eaton</persName>)
               appeared, and <persName ref="watchman">the night watchman</persName> (?), and I said "Break in the door" The two men
               rushed against the door, the door fell in, and there lay <persName ref="Mary">Mary</persName> on my bedroom floor ***
               They picked her up so tenderly, and <persName>Chauncey</persName> turned her over and he said, "Why,
                  <persName ref="Shelby">Mrs. Shelby</persName>, there is no blood on her." **** By that time the
               secretary had faded out of the picture in a faint *** and she (<persName  ref="Shelby">Mrs. Shelby's mother</persName>,
               Mrs. Miles) said, "Why no, she is not shot; stand her up, Chauncey." *** Then she
               (Mary) looked at us and said, "I thought I would give you all a jolt."</p>

            <p>POLICE: ** was there anything said about <name ref="Taylor">Taylor</name> in that? Did he have
               anything to do with that quarrel?</p>

            <p>SHELBY: No, I don't think he had anything to do with that *** I may have asked her if
               she had been out with . But there was no quarrel about <name ref="Taylor">Mr. Taylor</name>? It
               seems to me she mentioned Taylor's name. I don't remember now, or what. Then the
               report that I got that you have been practicing some rerevolver shooting - is there
               anything to that? I told you I shot it once. I know a man who will verify it -
                  <name ref="Stockdale">Mr. Stockdale</name>.</p>

            <p>POLICE: No other <objectName type="weapon">pistol</objectName> at any other time?</p>

            <p>SHELBY: No, I am afraid of <objectName type="weapon">pistols</objectName>. ***</p>

            <p>POLICE: What did your mother do with<objectName type="weapon"> your pistol</objectName> after
                  <persName ref="Mary">Mary</persName> pulled this stunt.</p>

            <p>SHELBY: That was all there was to it. Of course, we found <persName ref="Charlotte">Charlotte
                  Witney</persName> in a faint on the <placeName type="home">floor</placeName> and we had to revive her. *** And
               <persName ref= "Chauncey">Chauncey</persName> was trying to find out where <objectName type="weapon">the
                  bullets</objectName> went, and we discovered <objectName type="weapon">one bullet</objectName>
               had been shot into my closet, and we found that, and another one went up in the
               ceiling of the closet. I remember mother taking <objectName type="weapon">the pistol</objectName>.
               he said, "Here, give me that. That’s enough of <objectName type="weapon" >pistols</objectName> lying around.</p>

            <p>POLICE: What did she do with it. I never saw it again. I think I asked her once or
               twice what she did with it, and she said, "It's out. It's put away."</p>

            <p>SHELBY: I had <name type="engagement">an engagement</name> with a man the next morning at 9 o'clock. ** This man was
               a client of a friend of my daughter's, <name ref="Albert">Mr. Albert Heiner</name>. *** I also had
               been talking to a man about buying <objectName type="music">an Aeolian Organ</objectName>, and he stopped in that morning
               *** And while these two men were in the room, the telephone rang. It was then a
               little after 9, and <persName ref="Stockdale">Mr. Carl Stocktdle</persName> called me up. He had gone to the
               studio to work and had learned of the death of <persName ref="Taylor">William Desmond Taylor</persName>.
               Naturally, knowing that he directed <persName ref="Mary">Mary</persName>, he called me up and told me
               that <persName ref="Taylor">William Desmond Taylor</persName> had been found dead that morning.</p>

            <p>POLICE: Just what did he tell you?</p>

            <p>SHELBY: He said, "<persName ref="Shelby">Mrs. Shelby</persName>, I just wanted to call you up and tell
               you, I am at <placeName type="studio">the studio</placeName>. <persName ref="Taylor">William Desmond Taylor</persName> was found dead this
               morning." "Oh," I said, "that's terrible." That's all he knew. ** I turned to these
               gentlemen and said, "Oh, my, it's terrible. A man who directed my daughter, a very
               charming gentleman, was found dead this morning." **** Then <objectName type="telephone">the
                  telephone</objectName> rang again and the inevitable Miss Berger again. *** I
               said, "Oh, <persName ref="Margery">Margery</persName>, <persName ref="Stockdale">Mr. Stockdale</persName> just telephoned me from
               <placeName type="studio">the studio</placeName> that <name ref="Taylor">Mr. Taylor</name> was found dead this
               morning." **** In a few minutes <objectName type="telephone">the telephone</objectName> rang again.
               *** This time <persName>Miss Berger</persName> said, "<persName ref="Taylor">William Desmond Taylor</persName> was
               murdered this morning. He was shot." I said, "Oh, my, this is terrible; the man was
               murdered," Was shot? So we discussed that and the organ man knew I was waiting to go
               out with <persName ref="Rice">Mr. Rice</persName> so ** <persName ref="Rice">Mr. Rice</persName> and I got in his car *** and I said, “Mr. Rice, do
               you mind if I stop at <placeName type="house">my house</placeName> and tell my people?" *** and it seems to me that on
               the way crossing <placeName type="Vermont">Vermont</placeName> met my mother coming over in a car with the chauffeur and I
               just waved to her to turn around and come on back with us. I remember that
               distinctly. ***** I was in a great hurry because <persName ref="Rice">Mr. Rice</persName> was waiting
               for me in front, and I remember the chauffeur had parked <objectName type="car">my blue Packard</objectName> in the
               <placeName type="house">driveway</placeName>, and something was said about Mary wanted <objectName type="vehicle">the car</objectName>.
               <persName ref="Chauncey">Chauncey</persName> had gone to get <objectName type="vehicle">Mary's car</objectName>. However, I went
                  <placeName type="house">upstairs</placeName> in a great hurry, and I said, "Oh,
               <persName ref="Julia"> Julia</persName>, dear, Mr. Taylor was murdered last night." She said, "Oh, it
               isn't possible. I can't believe it. It isn't true." I said, "Oh, yes, it is.
                 <persName ref="Berger">Miss Berger</persName> told me so." *****</p>

            <p>POLICE: Did <persName ref="Woolwine">Mr. Woolwine</persName> ever try to take your statement?</p>

            <p>SHELBY: No, he never asked me a thing, <persName ref="Keyes">Mr. Keyes</persName>. Nobody ever questioned
               me.</p>

            <p>MR. MOTT: Tell <persName ref="Keyes">Mr. Keyes</persName> exactly now, that part of the conversation with
               <persName ref="Chauncey"> Chauncey</persName>?</p>

            <p>SHELBY: I said "<persName ref="Chauncey">Chauncey</persName>, what did you tell them?" He said, "I told them
               that you called me up very early that morning, about half past seven, and my wife
               said you went ever there without breakfast; that you wanted to go over to
                  <placeName type="Horbart_house">the Hobart house</placeName>." I said, "The morning of the Taylor
               murder." He said, "Yes." I said, "Why, I couldn't have known until after 9
               o’clock.” He said that he drove me over that morning and said that I was at the
               wisdom with <objectName type="papers">the papers</objectName> I said, "How could that be; besides there wasn't any <objectName>papers</objectName>
               that morning." "No," he said, "that's what they told me down at <placeName type="office">the
                  office</placeName>, that there wasn’t any papers that early." I said, "Well,
               that's nothing, it is just a laps of memory, it is of no consequence." And finally he
               saw he was in the wrong. I explained to him that <persName ref="Rice">Mr. Rice</persName> had driven me
               over."</p>

            <p>MR. MOTT: Now explain that Monte Blue proposition.</p>

            <p>SHELBY: (<persName ref="Shelby">Mrs. Shelby</persName> tells about some night when Mary had failed to come
              <placeName type="house"> home</placeName>, and they had looked for her until about 2:30 a.m. and finally located
               <objectName type="vehicle">her car</objectName> in front of <placeName type="house">Charlotte Whitney's house</placeName>) So <persName>Margaret</persName> and I rushed in and went up the steps
               hurriedly and opened <placeName type="house">the door</placeName> and came upon Mary &amp; Monte (Blue) on the couch. The
               door opened right into the front room. This Monte Blue started to run out into <placeName type="house">the
                  kitchen</placeName> and out <placeName type="house">the back door</placeName>.</p>

            <p>POLICE: You mean that they were in a compromising position?</p>

            <p>SHELBY: Yes. I was about the maddest woman that could ever be. I grabbed this
               halfbreed Indian by his shirt tail and I said, "Come right back in <placeName type="house">this
                  room</placeName>. I have something very forceful to say to you. Come back
               here!"</p>

            <p>MR. DAVIS: That time she went out with <persName ref="Marshall">Marshall Neilan</persName>, after the
               murder; wasn't that about two nights afterwards?</p>

            <p>SHELBY: Yes.</p>

            <p>POLICE: Immediately afterwards, wasn't it?</p>

            <p>SHELBY: It was.</p>

            <p>MR. KEYES: She tried to kill you, you say?</p>

            <p>SHELBY: Yes. *** Oh, "Mary said around the house freely. "Oh, <name>4</name> killed
               <persName ref="Taylor">Taylor</persName>". Not only once but many times. The was always saying that.</p>



         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
