<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>HUMN100 FALL 2025: The Murder of William Desmond Taylor</title>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Diane Jakacki</persName>
               <resp>Instructor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Waina Ali</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Jada Alvarez</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Colin Caricato</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>John Cochran</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Lucy DiChristina</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Nick Eisele-Bockelkamp</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Ethan Esclamado</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Spencer Firestone</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Henry Gibbons</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Daniel Hou</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Campbell Killian</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Olivia King</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>William Le</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Charlie Meehleib</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Carter Morton</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Kate Reyen</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Blythe Sena</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Hunter Sloan</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Rylie Smith</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Lily Stein</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Riley Twiss</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Katrina von Behren</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Emma Walkowiak</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Amanda Woertz</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Produced by members of the HUMN100: Introduction to Text Analysis course, Fall 2025</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>These interviews and statements are gathered from a number of sources, including "Taylorology" and Robert Giroux's Deed of Death</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="interview">
            <head>Interview with <persName ref="ethel">Ethel Mae Harrison</persName></head>
            <byline>YOUR NAME</byline>
            <p>
               
               Interviews with <persName ref="ethel">Ethel Mae Harrison</persName>
               
              <date>February 13, 1922</date>
              <orgName type="newspaper">NEW YORK HERALD</orgName> </p>
           
            <p>...<persName ref="ethel">Mrs. Robins</persName>, who married <persName ref="Taylor">William Cunningham Deane-Tanner</persName>, or <persName ref="Taylor">William
               Desmond Taylor</persName>, as he was later known, in <date>1902</date>, said her former husband had
               spent some time on a <placeName type="job">pony ranch</placeName> in <placeName type="region">southwestern</placeName> <placeName type="state">Kansas</placeName> before <persName ref="ethel">she</persName> met him in
               <placeName ref="city">New York</placeName>.  The only information she had ever had was that which <persName ref="Taylor">Deane-Tanner</persName>
               gave her personally.</p>
            
            <p>"<persName ref="Taylor">Mr. Deane-Tanner</persName> told me that when he arrived here from <placeName type="country">Ireland</placeName> he had
               gone out to this <placeName type="job">ranch</placeName>," <persName ref="ethel">Mrs. Robins</persName> said, "and his family in <placeName type="country">Ireland</placeName> had
               <eventName type="investment">bought</eventName> for him a part interest in it.  When I met him he referred to it and
               told me a flaw in the <objectName type="document">title</objectName> had forced several of the shareholders,
               including <persName ref="Taylor">himself</persName>, to give up their part, and he then joined the <orgName type="company">Davenport
               road company</orgName>.  After the failure of his venture in <placeName>Kansas</placeName> he returned to his
               home in <placeName type="country">Ireland</placeName> for a visit.</p>
            
            <p>"With reference to the claim of this <persName ref="Taylor">Mr. Taylor</persName> in <placeName ref="state">California</placeName> that he
               is the son of the murdered <persName ref="Taylor">director</persName>, I would not like to say flatly that the
               claim is or is not true, for I knew little of <persName ref="Taylor">Mr. Deane-Tanner's</persName> life on the
               <placeName type="job">ranch</placeName> in <placeName type="state">Kansas</placeName> and did not find it necessary to catechize him minutely, and
               he never mentioned anything to me about having been married out there.
               Perhaps there is some truth in the story, or it may be another of the many
               persons who come forward whenever there is an <objectName type="money">estate</objectName> to be settled.  I have
               been interested in the number of persons who claim <persName ref="Taylor">Mr. Deane-Tanner</persName>, or
                  <persName ref="Taylor">Taylor</persName>, was their father.  To date he must have had at least six or seven
                  children besides my own daughter, if the stories are all correct.  As <persName ref="Taylor">Mr.
               Deane-Tanner</persName> would only be about <time>fifty years</time> old now, that is rather
               ridiculous, I think."</p>
             
            <p> Referring to the criminal end of the case, <persName ref= "ethel">Mrs. Robins</persName> criticized the
               work of the <placeName type="city">Los Angeles</placeName> detectives and prosecutors, saying they do not seem
               to be particularly anxious to solve the mystery of the identity of the
               murderer.</p>
               
            <p>"<persName ref="ethel">I</persName> have bitterly resented the accounts printed in some of the
               newspapers here that my daughter and myself are merely interested in the
               financial part of the affair and are more interested in the <persName ref="Taylor">Taylor</persName> <objectName ref="money">estate</objectName>
               than in the identity of the person who killed my former husband.  This is
               absolutely untrue, for, as <persName ref="Taylor">Mr. Taylor's</persName> former wife, I am deeply grieved at
               this terrible affair and am anxious to see the guilty person punished."
               Returning to the discussion of the claim of the man who says the <persName ref="Taylor">movie
               director</persName> was his <persName ref="Taylor">father</persName>, <persName ref="ethel">Mrs. Robins</persName> said that it seemed improbable that her
               first husband ever used the name of <persName ref="Taylor">Taylor</persName> before he left <placeName type="city">New York</placeName> in <date>1908</date>.
               <persName ref="ethel">She</persName> said that to old friends who knew him when he first came to <placeName type="country">this country</placeName>
               and had been in constant touch with him during his stay in <placeName type="state">Kansas</placeName> nothing
               was known of any marriage while he was in the <placeName>West</placeName>.  After that, and until
               he <eventName type="leaving">disappeared</eventName>, <persName ref="ethel">Mrs. Robins</persName> said, he never used the name of <persName ref="Taylor">Taylor</persName>, or
               referred extensively to his visit to the <placeName type="job">ranch</placeName> in the <placeName type="region">West</placeName>.</p>
            
            <p>"I never really knew <persName ref="Taylor">Mr. Deane-Tanner's</persName> right age," <persName>Mrs. Robins</persName> said,
               "and I understood that he had been in <placeName type="country">his country</placeName> about eight or nine years,
               when I <eventName type="marriage">married</eventName> him at the <orgName type="church">Little Church Around the Corner</orgName> in <date>1901</date>.  He was a
               fine, lovable man, and I never had occasion to closely question him about
               his 'past,' which every one seems trying to <eventName type="investigation">dig up</eventName>."</p>
              
            <p>No decision whether <persName ref="ethel">Mrs. Robins</persName> or her daughter, <persName ref="daughter">Ethel</persName>, will go to
               <placeName type="state">California</placeName> in connection with the settling of the <objectName type="money">estate</objectName> has been reached.
               <persName ref="frank">Frank E. Schrenseisen</persName> of <placeName type="city">New Rochelle</placeName>, attorney for <persName>Miss Tanner</persName>, said that
               he was awaiting developments and instructions from the office of the Public
               <title type="politician">Administrator</title> in <placeName type="city">Los Angeles</placeName>.  Another attorney for <persName ref="ethel">Miss Tanner</persName> has been
               engaged in <placeName type="city">Los Angeles</placeName>.  Should the <title type="politician">Public Administrator</title> place credence in
                  the story of <persName ref="Taylor">Taylor</persName>, it is probable that <persName ref="ethel">Miss Tanner</persName> will accompany her
               attorney to <placeName type="region">the coast</placeName>.</p>
           
            <p> "<persName ref="Taylor">Mr. Deane-Tanner</persName> told my <persName ref="daughter">daughter</persName> that he had made a <objectName type="document">will</objectName> in her
               favor," <persName ref="ethel">Mrs. Robins</persName> said, "and had placed it in his <objectName type="bank">safe deposit box</objectName>.  I
               understand that this is another one of the <objectName type="document">items</objectName> which the <orgName type="law">police</orgName> say have
               strangely '<eventName type="disapearnce">disappeared</eventName>.'  What he did with it I have no idea, but I feel
               that the entire matter will be straightened out.  Just at present I am
               hoping that the murderer of <persName ref="Taylor">Mr. Taylor</persName> will be brought to justice for this
               terrible crime."</p>
              
            <p><persName ref="ethel">Mrs. Robins</persName> commented on the strange disappearance of <persName ref="dennis">Dennis Deane-
               Tanner</persName>, <persName ref="dennis">brother</persName> of the murdered <persName ref="Taylor">director</persName>, and said she had never heard a
               word from him since he left this <placeName type="city">city</placeName> in <date>1912</date>, just <time>four years</time> after her
               husband <eventName type="disappearance">disappeared</eventName>.  She said the two brothers had been good friends and
               business associates, and that <persName ref="dennis">Dennis</persName> had visited their home at <placeName type="town">Larchmont</placeName> on
               several occasions, and had met many of their friends.  There was never any
               trouble between the brothers as far as she knew, <persName ref="ethel">Mrs. Robins </persName>said.</p>
            
               <p><date>February 14, 1922</date>
               <orgName type="newspaper">NEW YORK AMERICAN</orgName></p>
              
            <p>To the two names suggested in the <orgName type="newspaper">New York American</orgName> <date>yesterday</date>--<persName ref="sands">Edward
               F. Sands</persName> and <persName ref="dennis">Dennis Gage Deane-Tanner</persName> as persons whose discovery may furnish
               a clue to the identity of the slayer of <persName ref="Taylor">William Desmond Taylor</persName>--was added
               <date>yesterday</date> a third.</p>
             
            <p> The third person is a woman, a fascinating blonde who was the companion
               of <persName ref="Taylor">Taylor</persName> (or <persName ref="Taylor">W. C. Deane-Tanner</persName>, as he was then known) on a trip through
               the <placeName type="region">Adirondacks</placeName> during the <date>Summer of 1908</date>, <date>three months prior</date> to the sudden
               disappearance of <persName ref="Taylor">"Pete" Tanner</persName> in <date>late October, 1908</date>.</p>
              
            <p>This woman, who had completely enchained the fancy of the aristocratic,
               handsome <persName ref="Taylor">Tanner</persName>, was married.  Her identity is said to be known to a few of
               <persName ref="Taylor">Tanner's</persName> associates of the old days when he was a director in the <orgName type="company">A. J.
               Crawford Company</orgName> firm at <placeName type="address">No. 253 Fifth avenue</placeName>.  She was the co-respondent in
               the divorce <eventName type="divorce">suit</eventName> instituted some two years after <persName ref="Taylor">"Pete" Tanner's</persName>
               disappearance by <persName ref="ethel">Mrs. Ethel May Hamilton Robins</persName>, now the wife of <persName ref="robins">Edward L.
               C. Robins</persName>, managing proprietor of <orgName type="restaurant">Delmonico's</orgName>.</p>
              
            <p>Does this hitherto hidden episode in the life of the murdered <persName ref="Taylor">man</persName> bear
               any significance upon the crime?</p>
               
            <p>Was the woman's husband implacably determined to <eventName type="revenge">avenge</eventName> himself upon
               the <persName ref="Taylor">man</persName> who had won the affections of his wife?</p>
              
            <p>Was it the hand of the husband that <eventName type="murder">fired</eventName> the fatal <objectName type="bullet">bullet</objectName> (from twelve
               to fourteen years old, according to the testimony of experts in ballistics)
               that killed <persName ref="Taylor">William Desmond Taylor</persName>?</p>
              
            <p> ...At her home, <placeName type="house">Orienta Point,</placeName> <placeName type="town">Mamaroneck</placeName>, <persName ref="ethel">Mrs. Robins</persName>, former wife of
               the slain <persName ref="Taylor">director</persName>, <date>yesterday</date> refused to discuss this episode in the life of
               her former <persName ref="Taylor">husband</persName>.  <persName ref="ethel">She</persName> refused to see <persName ref="reporter">newspaper men</persName> but told a friend:
               "<persName ref="ethel">I</persName> would do anything in my power to solve the mystery of <persName ref="Taylor">Mr. Tanner's</persName>
               death but I do not think there can be any possible relation between this
               incident and the crime.  It was not until <date>long after</date> <persName ref="Taylor">Mr. Tanner's</persName>
               disappearance that I learned definitely there was another woman in his life.
               "This information was placed in the hands of my attorney, <persName ref="george">Mr. George
               Thoms</persName>, and he brought a successful <eventName type="divorce">suit</eventName> for divorce against <persName>Mr. Tanner</persName>.
               This was in <date>the latter part of 1918</date> [sic].  At that time I did not know
               whether <persName ref="Taylor">Mr. Tanner</persName> was dead or alive.</p>
             
            <p>"It was <date>later</date>, perhaps <date>seven years ago</date>, that I <eventName type="recognize">saw</eventName> <persName ref="Taylor">Mr. Tanner</persName> for the
               first time on the screen.  I cannot remember the name of the photoplay in
               which he appeared.  However, it was not until <date>two and one-half years ago</date>
               that I learned definitely that <persName ref="Taylor">William Desmond Taylor</persName> was my former
               husband."</p>
              
               <p><date>February 14, 1922</date>
               <orgName type="newspaper">WASHINGTON TIMES</orgName></p>
              
            <p> <placeName type="city">New York</placeName>, <date>Feb. 14</date> -- Of the many screen stars he knew, some of whom
               have been thrown squarely into the spotlight by the unrelenting inquiry into
               his association with <persName ref="Taylor">William Desmond Taylor</persName>, slain director, mentioned but
               one--<persName ref="minter">Mary Miles Minter</persName>--in his letters to his nineteen-year-old <persName ref="daughter">daughter</persName>,
               <persName ref="daughter">Miss Ethel Daisy Deane-Tanner</persName>.</p>
              
            <p> Disclosing this fact to a reporter today, <persName ref="daughter">Miss Tanner</persName> and her mother,
               <persName ref="ethel">Mrs. Edward L. C. Robins</persName>, who live in <placeName type="town">Mamaroneck</placeName>, both of whom were <eventName type="abondon">deserted</eventName>
               by the man of mystery in <date>1908</date>, said that <persName ref="minter">Miss Minter's</persName> name was used by the
               <persName ref="Taylor">director</persName> only in an impersonal way.</p>
               
            <p><persName ref="Taylor">He</persName> referred to <persName ref="minter">her</persName> as an actress of ability, and said he had directed
               <persName ref="minter">her</persName> in some of her photoplays.  This was one of the last letters written to
               his daughter by <persName ref="Taylor">Taylor</persName> before he was <eventName type="murder">murdered</eventName> in his <placeName type="city">Los Angeles</placeName> <placeName type="house">bungalow</placeName>.
               <persName ref="ethel">Mrs. Robins</persName> and her <persName ref="daughter">daughter</persName> expressly asserted that the name of <persName ref="mabel">Mabel
               Normand</persName>, screen comedienne, and last person to see the director alive, did
               not appear in <persName ref="Taylor">Taylor's</persName> letters to his <persName ref="daughter">daughter</persName>, which had been more or less
               frequent during the <date>last two years</date>.</p>
               
            <p>Curiously enough, (and one reason why <persName ref="ethel">Mrs. Robins</persName> is increasingly
               inclined to the opinion that her husband's sudden <eventName type="abandon">disappearance</eventName> from <placeName type="city">New
               York</placeName> was due to loss of memory), her former husband never mentioned her in
               the letters.</p>
              
            <p>Another reason for this belief, she declared, was that on the times she
               and her <persName ref="daughter">daughter</persName> lunched here with <persName ref="Taylor">Taylor</persName>--after it was definitely
               established that <persName ref="Taylor">Taylor</persName> was in reality <persName ref="Taylor">Deane-Tanner</persName>--he never mentioned the
               fact that he <eventName type="abandon">deserted</eventName> his <persName ref="ethel">wife</persName> and <persName type="ethel">daughter</persName>.  On these occasions all three
               felt the subject was rather delicate and it was never brought up.
               <persName ref="ethel">Mrs. Robins</persName> said that when <persName type="ethel">she</persName> and her <persName ref="daughter">daughter</persName> became convinced <date>two
               years ago</date>, after seeing pictures of <persName ref="Taylor">Taylor</persName>, that he was the girl's father,
               <persName ref="daughter">Miss Deane-Tanner</persName> took the initiative and wrote to him.  His reply came
               <time>immediately</time>.</p>
            
            <p>In it he said he was very glad to hear from her; that he had not heard
               from he for so <time>long</time> that he thought <persName ref="daughter">she</persName> was dead.  This is one more reason
               why <persName ref="ethel">Mrs. Robins</persName> believes her former <persName ref="Taylor">husband</persName> was a victim of aphasia when he
               left, after attending the <placeName type="town">Vanderbilt</placeName> cup races in <date>1908</date>.
               <persName>Taylor</persName> also, <persName>Mrs. Robins</persName> asserted, was unable to recall friends of
               their married life, and when their names were mentioned, his face failed to
               show the slightest signs of remembrance.  He did remember, however, favorite
               dishes of his former wife when he was dining with his daughter, pointing
               them out to the latter on the menu during their luncheon together.
               <persName ref="ethel">Mrs. Robins</persName> declared that these points proved that his mind, while
               vague as to consequential facts about <persName ref="ethel">her</persName> married life with the <persName ref="Taylor">director</persName>,
               retained minor details.</p>
             
            <p> The director's experiences in <placeName type="state">Alaska</placeName> also were set forth in one <objectName type="letter">letter</objectName>.
               <persName ref="Taylor">Taylor</persName> told of how he contracted scurvy, consequently suffering from loss of
               hair, headaches and neuralgia.  Another letter dismissed with a few scornful
               words <persName ref="sands">Sands</persName>, his chauffeur, who is still being sought by <orgName type="law">police</orgName>.  The
               <persName ref="Taylor">director</persName> declared <persName ref="sands">Sands</persName> had upset his home and said his name had been forged
               to checks by his unfaithful servant.</p>
              
            <p>Signatures <persName ref="Taylor">Taylor</persName> used in his letters to his <persName ref="daughter">daughter</persName>, for whom he
               showed deep devotion, were "<persName ref="Taylor">Father</persName>" and "<persName ref="Taylor">Daddy Pete</persName>."  The origin of how
               <persName ref="Taylor">Taylor</persName> came to be known as "<persName ref="Taylor">Pete</persName>" was explained by <persName ref="ethel">Mrs. Robins</persName>.  She said
               when <persName ref="Taylor">Taylor</persName>, or as he was known then, <persName ref="Taylor">Deane-Tanner</persName>, first came to live in
               <placeName type="city">New York</placeName> he took lodging with several Englishmen.</p>
             
               <p><persName ref="Taylor">Taylor</persName>, always deliberate and calculating in his methods, was nicknamed
               "<persName ref="Taylor">P. D. Q.</persName>," by his roommates, which was quickly shortened to "<persName ref="Taylor">Pete</persName>."
               The <persName ref="Taylor">director's</persName> promise to leave his <objectName type="money">estate</objectName> to his <persName ref="daughter">daughter</persName> was
               contained in a <objectName type="letter">letter</objectName> written in <date>February, 1920</date>.  <persName ref="ethel">Mrs. Robins</persName> said her
               former husband said in this message he thought it would be good policy to
               leave them both an <objectName type="money">annuity</objectName>, in addition to telling of his <objectName type="document">will</objectName> bequeathing
               his <objectName type="money">estate</objectName> to <persName ref="daughter">Ethel Daisy</persName>.</p>
              
               <p><date>February 7, 1922</date>
               <orgName type="newspaper">NEW YORK AMERICAN</orgName></p>
             
            <p> [relating the testimony of <persName ref="Taylor">Taylor's</persName> <persName ref="ethel">wife</persName> during the divorce <eventName type="divorce">hearing</eventName> in
               <date>1911</date>]...<persName ref="ethel">Mrs. Tanner</persName>, in her testimony, said she was married on
               <date>December 7, 1901</date>, at the <orgName type="church">Little Church Around the Corner</orgName>.
               The ceremony was performed by <persName ref="reverend">Rev. George C. Houghton</persName>, pastor of the
               church.  Following the marriage the couple went to live at <placeName type="adress">No. 40 Washington
               Square South</placeName>, and later moved to the <placeName type="hotel">Hotel Colonial</placeName> at <placeName type="street">Columbus Avenue</placeName> and
               <placeName type="street">Eighty-first street</placeName>, at which time her husband became associated with <orgName type="company">A. J.
               Crawford &amp; Co.</orgName>, at <placeName type="adress">No. 251 Fifth Avenue</placeName>.
               <persName ref="ethel">Mrs. Deane-Tanner</persName> added:</p>
             
            <p>"My husband left home at <time>noon</time> on <date>October 23, 1908</date>, and I have never
               seen him since.  The last word received from him was on <date>October 26, 1908</date>,
               when he was stopping at the <placeName>Broadway Central Hotel</placeName>.  He sent word to the
               <orgName type="company">Crawford firm</orgName> asking for a sum of <objectName type="money">money</objectName>.  This was sent to him by <persName type="Daniel">Daniel J.
               Barker</persName>, of the firm.  Then he disappeared."</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
