<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>HUMN100 FALL 2025: The Murder of William Desmond Taylor</title>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Diane Jakacki</persName>
               <resp>Instructor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Waina Ali</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Jada Alvarez</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Colin Caricato</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>John Cochran</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Lucy DiChristina</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Nick Eisele-Bockelkamp</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Ethan Esclamado</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Spencer Firestone</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Henry Gibbons</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Daniel Hou</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Campbell Killian</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Olivia King</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>William Le</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Charlie Meehleib</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Carter Morton</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Kate Reyen</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Blythe Sena</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Hunter Sloan</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Rylie Smith</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Lily Stein</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Riley Twiss</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Katrina von Behren</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Emma Walkowiak</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Amanda Woertz</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Produced by members of the HUMN100: Introduction to Text Analysis course, Fall
               2025</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>These interviews and statements are gathered from a number of sources, including
               "Taylorology" and Robert Giroux's Deed of Death</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="interview">
            <head>Interview with Stockdale+Dumas</head>
            <byline>Riley Twiss</byline>
            <p> Statements by Carl Stockdale <date>June 10, 1937</date> <orgName>LOS ANGELES NEWS</orgName></p>

            <p> It was divulged that <persName ref="Carl">Carl Stockdale</persName>, veteran
               character actor and close friend of Mrs. <persName ref="Charlotte">Charlotte
                  Shelby</persName>, mother of <persName ref="Mary">Mary Miles Minter</persName>,
               screen star who collapsed at news of <persName>Taylor's</persName> death, had
               admitted that he was in the company of Mrs. <persName>Shelby</persName> at the time
                  <persName>Taylor</persName> is believed to have been murdered.
                  <persName>Stockdale</persName>, interviewed at his home, <placeName>6325 Fountain
                  Avenue</placeName>, chuckled when asked for his own conclusions on the long
               unsolved murder.</p>

            <p> "So <persName>Fitts</persName> thinks I killed <persName ref="taylor">William
                  Desmond Taylor</persName>," he remarked. "I'll tell you this, I was never in
                  <persName>Bill Taylor's</persName> home. I met him at a big party thrown by Mrs.
                  <persName>Shelby</persName>." Pressed for his own suspicions of the killer's
               identity, <persName>Stockdale</persName> promptly answered,
                  "<persName>Sands.</persName>" He referred to <persName>Taylor's</persName>
               one-time chauffeur [sic], <persName ref="Edward">Edward Sands</persName>, whose
               mysterious disappearance immediately after the murder and before authorities could
               question him, has caused his name to be listed among those "wanted for questioning"
               by police. The veteran actor, now 63, declared he was with Mrs. <persName>Charlotte
                  Shelby</persName> at her home the night <persName>Taylor</persName> was murdered
               February 1, 1922. He fixed the time of his <eventName>visit</eventName> from 7 to 9
               p.m. Police have set the hour of the shooting at <time>7:45 p.m.</time> "I told my brother,
                  <persName>Frank</persName>," <persName>Stockdale</persName> said, "that I was
               droppin' in on Mrs. <persName>Shelby</persName> that night." </p>
            <p>
               <persName>Stockdale</persName> said he first met Mrs. <persName>Shelby</persName> in
                  <persName>Santa Barbara</persName> at the time when her daughter, <persName>Mary
                  Miles Minter</persName> was working for the old American Film Company. ---</p>

            <p><date>June 10, 1937</date> <orgName>LOS ANGELES TIMES</orgName></p>

            <p> While authorities deferred definite action yesterday in the investigation into the
               fifteen-year-old murder of <persName>William Desmond Taylor</persName>, a 63-year-old
               film character actor stepped forward to make the most important statement to be added
               recently to the mazes of <placeName>California's</placeName> most famous murder
               mystery. The new figure in the case is <persName>Carl Stockdale</persName>, for years
               well known as an actor in Hollywood and who now lives at <placeName>6325 Fountain
                  Avenue</placeName>. </p>
            <p>Disclosing that he had been a close friend of Mrs. <persName>Charlotte
                  Shelby</persName>, mother of <persName>Mary Miles Minter</persName>, the latter,
               who admitted she was in love with <persName>Taylor</persName> at the time of his
               slaying, <persName>Stockdale</persName> had this to say yesterday: "I have expected
               the authorities to question me for some time and have made no effort to evade such
               interrogation despite the fact that no one welcomes publicity of the sort. </p>
            <p> "I was with Mrs. <persName>Shelby</persName> on the night that
                  <persName>Taylor</persName> was murdered at about the time fixed by the
               authorities that the fatal <objectName>bullet</objectName> was fired. That may be
               considered of importance to the authorities and is information I am quite willing to
               give." </p>
            <p><persName>Stockdale</persName> indicated that he is in complete sympathy with a
               statement recently issued by Mrs. <persName>Shelby</persName> in which she declared
               that, sick of the innuendoes which have followed in the wake of the
                  <persName>Taylor</persName> murder, she wanted action to clear up the case once
               and for all.</p>

            <p>Although apparently unwilling to move at once, the <placeName>District Attorney's
                  office</placeName> yesterday stated that Stockdale is scheduled to be questioned
               before the present investigation is concluded.</p>

            <p> "I am willing to tell all I know to the District Attorney or anyone else," commented
               the actor. "I have known Mrs. <persName>Shelby</persName> and her family for
               approximately twenty years. I was living on Winona Boulevard with my brother
                  <persName>Frank</persName>, and my mother and father on the day of the
                  <eventName>shooting</eventName> of <persName>Taylor</persName>. "In the evening I
               left my home and went to pay a visit to Mrs. <persName>Shelby</persName> in the new
               house she had purchased at <placeName>Seventh street and New Hampshire
                  avenue</placeName>. I arrived shortly before <time>7 o'clock </time>in the evening and left
               about 9 o'clock."</p>

            <p><persName>Taylor</persName>, as near as authorities could fix the time, was shot
               about <time>7:45 p.m.</time> on <date>February 1, 1922</date>. Several persons in the neighborhood of his
               bungalow at <placeName>404-B South Alvarado street</placeName> reported hearing a
               shot at that time. </p>
            <p>"I was the first person," went on Stockdale, "to inform Mrs. Shelby that Taylor had
               been killed. That was about <time>9 o'clock</time> the next morning. I had gone to the studio
               where I was working on a picture with Mabel Normand and some one told me that Taylor
               had been found dead. I telephoned Mrs. <persName>Shelby</persName> at once because I
               knew that he had been <persName>Mary's</persName> director and that the whole family
               knew him well." </p>
            <p>--- <date>August 26, 1937</date> <orgName> LOS ANGELES EXAMINER</orgName></p>

            <p> When a <objectName>bullet</objectName> snuffed out the life of <persName>William
                  Desmond Taylor</persName>, noted picture director, in <date>1922</date>, Mrs.
                  <persName>Charlotte Shelby</persName> was at home. </p>
            <p>
               <persName>Carl Stockdale</persName>, veteran actor and friend of Mrs.
                  <persName>Shelby</persName>, so testified in Superior Judge <persName>Parker
                  Wood's</persName> court yesterday.</p>

            <p> He appeared as a defense witness in trial of the civil suit by which <persName
                  ref="Margret">Margaret Shelby Fillmore</persName>, Mrs.
                  <persName>Shelby's</persName> daughter, is seeking to regain $48,750 in bonds,
               which she contends her mother removed from a joint safety deposit box.</p>

            <p> "I was with Mrs. <persName>Shelby</persName> from <time>7:30 to 9:30 p.m.</time> in her apartment
               at <placeName>Seventh street and New Hampshire avenue the night</placeName> of the
               murder," <persName>Stockdale stated.</persName>
            </p>
            <p>"I did not know of the tragedy until the following morning when I arrived for work at
               the <orgName>Mack Sennett Studios</orgName>. </p>
            <p>"I immediately called Mrs. <persName>Shelby</persName> and told her to prepare
               herself for a shock. Then I told her Mr.<persName> Taylor</persName> had been slain. </p>
            <p> "She screamed: 'Impossible!' "</p>

            <p> The actor's testimony, while perhaps not strictly pertinent to the present
                  <eventName>suit</eventName>, was introduced to answer certain pointed intimations
               made during its trial, attorneys explained.</p>

            <p>
               <persName>Mary Miles Minter</persName> and the late <persName>Mabel
                  Normand</persName> frequently were mentioned in gossip concerning the
                  <persName>Taylor</persName> mystery, <persName>Stockdale</persName> said. But at
               no time had he heard rumors that Mrs. <persName>Shelby</persName> might be involved
               as a suspect, he added. </p>

            <p> The actor also testified that he had seen Mrs. <persName>Fillmore</persName> under
               the influence of <objectName>liquor</objectName> four times between <date>1925 and 1931</date>. </p>
            <p> --- <date>August 26, 1937</date> <orgName>LOS ANGELES NEWS</orgName></p>

            <p>...<persName>Stockdale's </persName>testimony was in the nature of a reply to that of
               Mrs. <persName>Fillmore</persName> two days ago when she said she did not know her
               mother's whereabouts at the hour of the murder. Cross-examined as to whether he had
               ever heard that Mrs. <persName>Shelby</persName> was a suspect in the murder, the
               veteran actor replied, "I did not hear any such rumors, but I did hear rumors that
                  <persName>Mary</persName> (Miss Minter) and <persName>Mabel Normand</persName>
               were suspected of the murder." ~~~~</p>

            <p>
               <persName ref="Verne"> VERNE DUMAS</persName>, neighbor Statement taken 2-9-22.</p>

            <p> A. ** About <time>7:30 </time>as near as I remember *** I was in my bath room
                  <eventName>shaving</eventName> ** I heard this noise or the nigger hollering, **
               and he hollered Mr. <persName>Taylor</persName> was dead, <objectName type="Material"
                  >stone</objectName> dead, somebody come quick. I ran back in the bathroom, grabbed
                  a<objectName type="Cloth"> towel</objectName>, wiped the lather from my
                  <objectName>face</objectName>, put on a bath <objectName type="clothing">robe</objectName> and ran
               over there. **** Well, when I went in <persName>Henry</persName> preceded me ** and
               there was Mr. <persName>Harrington</persName> and some gentlemen whose names I do not
               know 1iving across the street there. In other words, 4 of us in a room *** evidently
               he had died from a hemorrhage because blood had run from his mouth and his nose and
               then looked like from his <objectName>ear </objectName>and had congealed and he was
               lying perfectly natural as though he was simply laid out as a corpse. *** but the
               body was lying parallel with the <objectName type="Furniture">desk </objectName>with the feet to the
                  <objectName>door</objectName> and the <objectName type="Furniture">rug</objectName>, the corner of
               the <objectName type="Furniture">rug</objectName> near his <objectName type= "Body">foot</objectName> was pushed
               back a little bit *** and the <objectName type="Furniture">chair</objectName> upright and this
                  <objectName type="Body">foot</objectName> under it and the <objectName type="Furniture">chair</objectName> at
               the <objectName type="Furniture">desk</objectName> wee pushed just partially under the
                  <objectName type="Furniture">desk</objectName> ** and the <objectName type= "furniture">chair</objectName> right
               between his <objectName type="Body">head</objectName> and the <objectName type="Furniture">desk</objectName>.
               Well, on the <objectName type="Furniture">table</objectName> was a <objectName>check book</objectName>
               open and two piles of <objectName>checks</objectName>. </p>
            <p>Q. Has the rear <objectName>door</objectName> a spring <objectName>lock</objectName>
               or is it locked with a <objectName>key</objectName>.</p>
            <p> A. Locked with a <objectName>key</objectName> from the inside.</p>

            <p> Q. There was no chance for anybody at straightening this body out between the time
               the colored boy hollered and you went in there. </p>
            <p> A. No, the only part of his body I touched was this <objectName>arm</objectName> and
               it was absolutely stiff.</p>

            <p>Q. How about his <objectName>coat</objectName>?</p>

            <p>A. It was as straight as if it had been pressed. ** and it was absolutely pulled
               perfectly straight. </p>





         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
