<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>HUMN100 FALL 2025: The Murder of William Desmond Taylor</title>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Diane Jakacki</persName>
               <resp>Instructor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Waina Ali</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Jada Alvarez</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Colin Caricato</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>John Cochran</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Lucy DiChristina</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Nick Eisele-Bockelkamp</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Ethan Esclamado</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Spencer Firestone</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Henry Gibbons</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Daniel Hou</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Campbell Killian</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Olivia King</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>William Le</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Charlie Meehleib</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Carter Morton</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Kate Reyen</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Blythe Sena</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Hunter Sloan</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Rylie Smith</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Lily Stein</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Riley Twiss</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Katrina von Behren</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Emma Walkowiak</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Amanda Woertz</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Produced by members of the HUMN100: Introduction to Text Analysis course, Fall
               2025</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>These interviews and statements are gathered from a number of sources, including
               "Taylorology" and Robert Giroux's Deed of Death</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="interview">
            <head>Interview with Charlotte Shelby</head>
            <byline>Katrina von Behren</byline>


            <p> December 26, 1929 A. M. Rochlen LOS ANGELES EXAMINER</p>

            <p>In a remarkable interview, given exclusively to the LOS ANGELES EXAMINER, <persName
                  ref="cshelby">Mrs. Charlotte Shelby</persName>, mother of <persName ref="minter"
                  >Mary Miles Minter</persName>, last night for the first time revealed hitherto
               unknown phases of <eventName type="murder">the <persName ref="taylor">William Desmond
                     Taylor</persName> murder case</eventName>. From the wealth of memories so
               closely associated with the career of <persName ref="minter">her talented
                  daughter</persName> she brought forth details that shed a new light on the many
               investigations that sought to unravel the tangled threads of the <eventName
                  type="murder">murder of the film director</eventName> -- a case famous the world
               over. "The time for action has come. I'm not going to sit idly and be a target for
               base rumors and vicious innuendo. there must be some justice in this world -- even
               for a helpless woman." Breaking a silence of more than seven eventful years,
                  <persName ref="cshelby">Mrs. Shelby</persName>, one of the dramatic and
               ever-interesting figures of <eventName type="murder">the Taylor case</eventName>,
               thus struck back at the endless chain of "whispers and theories" linking her, as well
               as others, in the events of that <eventName type="murder">baffling
                  mystery</eventName>. Of <persName ref="minter">Mary Miles Minter</persName>, who
               was a film star under <persName ref="taylor">Taylor</persName>'s direction, she had
               little to say. </p>

            <p>What here is disclosed would remain forever in her own <objectName type="bodyPart"
                  >heart</objectName>, she said, were it not for the rumors, reports and
               insinuations that are making her life a dreadful dream. Desiring only to be left
                  alone,<persName ref="cshelby"> Mrs. Shelby</persName> now feels that she must cut
               through the web of whispers and suspicions to bring to an end the repetitions of her
               name in connection with the <eventName type="murder">case</eventName>. And she wants to serve notice that every recourse
               of law will be brought to bear to stop unwarranted bantering of her name and to force
               those who have used it to come out in the open. "I have made complete statements to
               the <persName ref="police">proper authorities</persName> in the past and I stand
               ready to do it again if it will help in a sincere and honest effort to solve
                  <eventName type="murder">the mystery</eventName> of <persName ref="taylor">Mr.
                  Taylor's</persName> death," <persName ref="cshelby">Mrs. Shelby</persName> said in
               the <eventName>interview</eventName>. "But somewhere, somehow, this thing has got to
               stop. I demand it. We cannot go through life like this -- I and my <persName
                  ref="minter">daughter</persName>, <persName ref="mshelby">Margaret</persName>. We
               are not hiding from anyone one anything. All we ask is to be left alone, and somebody
               has got to help us fight this terrible thing." For the purpose of an earnest and
               legitimate investigation, <persName ref="cshelby">Mrs. Shelby</persName> revealed for
               the first time to THE EXAMINER <time>last night</time> that -- She was not in love
               with <persName ref="taylor">William Desmond Taylor</persName>. She did not make
               threats against the <persName ref="taylor">famous director</persName>.</p>


            <p>She did not go to <persName ref="taylor">Taylor</persName>'s <placeName
                  type="residence">bungalow</placeName> at <placeName type="address">404B South
                  Alvarado Street</placeName> at an <time>early morning hour</time>
               <date>several weeks before the murder</date>, armed with a
                  <objectName>revolver</objectName>. She did not, shortly before the murder,
               purchase a <objectName type="gun">gun</objectName> and practice with it. "I know that
               some of these things, with many vicious details added, had been whispered around,"
               Mrs. Shelby said. "How most of them originated, no one knows. Some, I'm sure, were
               spread by a person formerly in my employ. I know that person and I know the motive.
               At the proper time and place I shall make known this motive, but in the meantime I am
               interested in just this: "I want to find out who circulates these rumors. I want to
               get definite information of definite statements against me, and then I am going to
               take definite action to the limit of my ability and the law." Mrs. Shelby's
                  <objectName type="bodyPart">blue eyes</objectName> lost some of their softness as
               she spoke. Only a <time>few minutes before</time> she came into the room to greet
                  <persName>the visitor</persName>. Attired in a soft, clinging <objectName
                  type="clothes">Viennese gown</objectName> of golden brown, with brown suede shoes
               to match, she sat near the window of her <placeName type="residence">charming
                  apartment</placeName> in a court that looked like a corner of some far-away nook
               in old Granada. Outside Christmas crowds and <objectName type="vehicle">laden
                  automobiles</objectName> moved back and forth. <persName ref="mshelby">Margaret
                  Shelby Fillmore</persName>, always a close pal and companion of her mother, sat
               nearby. </p>

            <p> The two had but recently returned from <placeName type="continent" subtype="europe"
                  >Europe</placeName>. <placeName type="country" subtype="france">France</placeName>, <placeName
                  type="country">Belgium</placeName>, <placeName type="country">Germany</placeName>,
                  <placeName type="country" subtype="germany">Switzerland</placeName> and <placeName type="country"
                  >Italy</placeName>. <placeName type="city" subtype="paris">Paris</placeName>, <placeName
                  type="city" subtype="london">London</placeName>, <placeName type="city">Vienna</placeName> -- art
               museums and <placeName type="city" subtype="florence">Florence</placeName> -- and then all the crash and
               cruel reverberations of the old Taylor case. "We arrived in <placeName type="state" subtype="california"
                  >California</placeName>
               <date>November 17</date>. For <time>more than three years</time> we lived in
                  <placeName type="continent" subtype="europe">Europe</placeName>. You know, there are many things we
               do not discuss with the outside world. There are many sorrows one must always bear
               alone or with those who are very near and close. "My <persName ref="minter"
                  >daughter</persName> and I (to Mary Miles Minter, Mrs. Shelby never alluded as "my
               daughter") traveled and saw everything that was beautiful in old <placeName
                  type="continent" subtype="europe">Europe</placeName>, but now we are back -- and to all this."
                  As<persName ref="cshelby"> Mrs. Shelby</persName> talked, framed against the
                  <objectName>deep window</objectName> and the <objectName>dazzling white
                  walls</objectName> of the <placeName type="landscape">courtyard</placeName>, there
               flashed before the <persName>interviewer</persName> another
                  <eventName>occasion</eventName>, <time>almost eight years ago</time>, when
                  <persName ref="cshelby"> Mrs. Shelby</persName> was an actress in a drama in which
                  <persName ref="minter">Mary Miles Minter</persName> was playing the leading part.
               It was in the <placeName type="house">artistic living room</placeName> of their
                  <placeName type="residence">home</placeName>, on North Hobart boulevard, in
                  <date>February 1922</date>. <persName ref="taylor"> William Desmond
                  Taylor</persName>, a man of mystery and romance, a leading figure in the motion
               picture world, was <eventName type="murder">murdered in his home</eventName>
               <date>a few nights before</date>. One by one several beautiful women -- names known
               throughout the world -- were brought into the case. And <persName ref="minter">Mary
                  Miles Minter</persName>, young, vivacious, and then at the <time>height of her
                  artistic career</time>, was one of these. Mary, her face like a Greek profile of
               exquisite marble, sat on a couch and told of her last visit with Taylor -- in the
               darkened chamber of the undertaking parlors. She had gone there alone to place a
               beautiful dark red rose on the body of the man who was her director, friend, ideal.
               And Mrs. Shelby, close by, listened to the story and watched over Mary.</p>


            <p> But <time>yesterday</time>, as the brilliant <date>Christmas afternoon</date> was
               changing into <time>evening</time>, it was a different story. "Yes, I remember that
               night, <time>nearly eight years ago</time>," Mrs. Shelby replied, and paused. "I want
               to forget it. Of <persName ref="minter">Mary</persName> I shall have nothing to say.
               She is in good hands and can take care of herself, I'm sure. "In those days my whole
               life was wrapped up in her. It was my work. Now I must fight for vindication. I've
               had enough of this, and I am going to ask that they put an end to the case once and
               for all." Throughout the entire discussion <persName ref="cshelby">Mrs.
                  Shelby</persName> was careful not to express any opinion on who killed <persName
                  ref="taylor">Taylor</persName>. "<persName ref="taylor">Mr. Taylor</persName> is
               dead. My daughter <persName ref="mshelby">Margaret</persName> and I are still alive.
               We must be protected and not crushed by this gossip. "That's why," she continued,
               "the truth must be revealed, the truth must be spoken, the truth must be printed.</p>

            <p>"Of course I have heard the dastardly whisperings about me and my connection with the
               case. I have heard them all -- that I was in love with Mr. Taylor, that I owned a
                  <objectName type="gun">gun</objectName> and used to practice on a target a short time before
               the murder, that I went to Mr. Taylor's <placeName type="residence"
                  >apartment</placeName> early <time>one morning</time> searching for Mr. Taylor and
               threatening him with death, that I had made many other threats, and so on and on. </p>

            <p>"Each and every one of these rumors and whisperings is ridiculous". </p>

            <p>Let us take them one by one and see," she declared.</p>

            <p>"I did have a <objectName>gun</objectName>."</p>

            <p>"It was given to me by a jeweler friend of ours in <placeName type="city" subtype="santaBarbara">Santa
                  Barbara</placeName>, way back in <date>1916</date>. That was a long time
                  before<persName ref="taylor"> Mr. Taylor</persName> was killed.</p>

            <p>"We were living in <placeName type="city" subtype="santaBarbara">Santa Barbara</placeName>. I was <persName
                  ref="minter">Mary</persName>'s business manager. I had to read the stories for her
                  <objectName type="possession">pictures</objectName>, work on the scenarios, watch over her
                  <objectName type="clothes">clothes</objectName>, the cast, everything.</p>

            <p>"We lived alone. No men folks in the <placeName type="residence"
                  >household</placeName>. Our friend brought the <objectName>gun</objectName> to the
                  <placeName type="residence">house</placeName> one night. He said I must keep
               it.</p>

            <p> "'But I don't know how to use it. I never held one in my hand before,' I told him. </p>
            <p>"'Well, let's learn,' he replied."</p>

            <p><persName ref="cshelby">Mrs. Shelby</persName> smiled.</p>

            <p>"You know, this really bears a strange element of humor, now that I look back on
               it.</p>

            <p> "We went out to some open spaces and I took this <objectName>gun</objectName> in my
               right hand. It was a pretty little thing -- had a pearl handle and all that. I
               pointed the <objectName type="gun">gun</objectName> at something or other, shut my eyes and
               pulled hard. The thing went 'boom' and threw my arm back.</p>

            <p> "I did that several times in succession. That was all."</p>

            <p>"Still, they call it target practice."</p>

            <p>Mrs. Shelby said she did not remember what had become of the
                  <objectName>gun</objectName>. She says she has no recollection of bringing it back
               to <placeName type="city" subtype="losAngeles">Los Angeles</placeName> when the household moved from
               <placeName type="city" subtype="santaBarbara">Santa Barbara.</placeName></p>

            <p> "That much for target practicing," she declared.</p>

            <p>"Now about that visit to <placeName>Mr. Taylor's house</placeName>.</p>

            <p>"To understand it, I must take you <time>back a few years</time>. I must ask you to
               keep in mind the fact that <persName ref="minter">Mary</persName> was at the height
               of her career, was making big pictures. We had been in New York. I negotiated new
               contracts. There were trips and conferences and all that. Many, many details that
               play no part here, except incidentally as they relate to the contacts made with a
               former employee for whom I sent to <placeName type="state" subtype="newNork">New York</placeName> and
               who later figured in the visit story.</p>

            <p>"We were back in <placeName type="state" subtype="california">California</placeName>. <persName
                  ref="minter">Mary</persName>'s contract originally called for pictures to be made
               in <placeName type="state" subtype="newYork">New York</placeName>. <time>One day</time>
               <persName ref="zukor">Mr. Adolph Zukor</persName> held a conference with us. It was
               decided that climatic conditions were better out here on <placeName>the
                  Coast</placeName> for the type of picture <persName ref="minter">Mary</persName>
               was making. So we came out.</p>

            <p>"<persName ref="taylor">Mr. Taylor</persName> was <persName ref="minter"
                  >Mary</persName>'s director.</p>

            <p>"About the time of this much-discussed visit <persName ref="minter">Mary</persName>
               bought a new <objectName type="vehicle">car</objectName>. It was a big, fast roadster, and <persName
                  ref="minter">Mary</persName> liked speed. She used to go out, tearing along the
               roads at 60 and 70 miles an hour. I was her mother and it worried me --
               naturally.</p>

            <p>"We were living on <placeName type="residence">Fremont place</placeName>. At
                  <time>that time of the year</time> there was lots of fog at nights.</p>

            <p>"One night <persName ref="minter">Mary</persName> did not come home to dinner. We
               waited and waited. She did not call. We began to worry. </p>


         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
