<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>HUMN100 FALL 2025: The Murder of William Desmond Taylor</title>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Diane Jakacki</persName>
               <resp>Instructor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Waina Ali</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Jada Alvarez</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Colin Caricato</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>John Cochran</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Lucy DiChristina</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Nick Eisele-Bockelkamp</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Ethan Esclamado</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Spencer Firestone</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Henry Gibbons</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Daniel Hou</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Campbell Killian</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Olivia King</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>William Le</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Charlie Meehleib</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Carter Morton</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Kate Reyen</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Blythe Sena</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Hunter Sloan</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Rylie Smith</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Lily Stein</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Riley Twiss</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Katrina von Behren</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Emma Walkowiak</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Amanda Woertz</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Produced by members of the HUMN100: Introduction to Text Analysis course, Fall
               2025</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>These interviews and statements are gathered from a number of sources, including
               "Taylorology" and Robert Giroux's Deed of Death</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="interview">
            <head>Interview with Charlotte Shelby</head>
            <byline>Emma Walkowiak</byline>


            <p> December 26, 1929</p>
            <p>A. M. Rochlen</p>
            <p>LOS ANGELES EXAMINER</p>

            <p> In a remarkable interview, given exclusively to the <orgName type="Publication">LOS
                  ANGELES EXAMINER</orgName>, <persName ref="Shelby">Mrs. Charlotte
                  Shelby</persName>, mother of <persName ref="Minter">Mary Miles Minter</persName>,
                  <time>last night</time> for the first time revealed hitherto unknown phases of the
                  <persName ref="Taylor">William Desmond Taylor</persName> murder case.</p>

            <p> From the wealth of memories so closely associated with the career of her talented
               daughter she brought forth details that shed a new light on the many investigations
               that sought to unravel the tangled threads of the murder of the film director -- a
               case famous the world over.</p>
            <p>(continued below) </p>
            <p> "Perhaps she went to dinner at <placeName type="anonymous_house">someone's
                  house</placeName>, it was suggested to me. We tried to reassure ourselves of this,
               but somehow I kept worrying about getting no telephone call and about that
                  <objectName type="Car">big, fast car</objectName> and the <placeName type="road"
                  >foggy roads</placeName>. </p>
            <p> "We began to call up persons at the <placeName type="studio">studio</placeName>. We
               called the <persName ref="camera crew">cameraman</persName> and the <persName
                  ref="camera crew">assistant cameraman</persName>. The <persName ref="camera crew"
                  >cameraman</persName>, a big, jolly Irishman, was a favorite of <persName
                  ref="Minter">Mary's</persName>. He was married and had small children. She was
               fond of children and occasionally stopped at <placeName type="cameraman_house">his
                  house</placeName>. The <persName ref="camera crew">cameraman</persName> told us
                  <persName ref="Minter">Mary</persName> had not been there. No one could remember
               seeing her leave the <placeName type="Studio">studio</placeName>. </p>
            <p> "We thought <persName ref="Taylor">Mr. Taylor</persName> perhaps would know. But we
               did not have his phone number. No one seemed to know it. </p>
            <p> "Then we remembered that <time>one day</time>
               <persName ref="Minter">Mary</persName> and her grandmother, <persName
                  ref="Minter Grandmother">Juliette B. Miles</persName>, went to <placeName
                  type="Taylor_Home"><persName ref="Taylor">Mr. Taylor's</persName> home</placeName>
               for <eventName type="Tea">tea</eventName>. </p>
            <p> "<persName ref="Chauncey">Chauncey</persName>, our chauffeur, drove them, so we
               called <persName ref="Chauncey">Chauncey</persName> and asked him if he knew where
                  <persName ref="Taylor">Mr. Taylor</persName> lived. He said he thought he could
               find <placeName type="Taylor_Home">the place</placeName> but did not know the
               address. </p>
            <p> "So we started out, <persName ref="Chauncey">Chauncey</persName>, my secretary and
                  <persName ref="Shelby">I</persName>. </p>
            <p> "We <eventName type="Driving">drove around</eventName> and around. the chauffeur
               said he knew <placeName type="Taylor_Home">the neighborhood</placeName> but was not
               certain of the exact location. Finally he remembered it. We stopped at the <placeName
                  type="Taylor_Home">corner of Fourth and Alvarado streets</placeName>. It was
                  <time>close to midnight</time> then. </p>
            <p> "<persName ref="Chauncey">Chauncey</persName> said he did not know which <placeName
                  type="Taylor_Home">bungalow</placeName> was <persName ref="Taylor">Mr.
                  Taylor's</persName>. There were a number of them," <persName ref="Shelby">Mrs.
                  Shelby</persName> went on, making a wide sweep with her <objectName
                  type="body_part">right arm</objectName>. "As I remember it, there were <placeName
                  type="Taylor_Home">some on the left, some on the right and some bungalows in the
                  back</placeName>. </p>
            <p> "I saw a <objectName type="Lighting">light</objectName> burning in a <placeName
                  type="Neighbor_Home">window on the right</placeName>, so I rang the <objectName
                  type="doorbell">bell</objectName>, or knocked, I don't remember which. Some one
               answered and I asked them if they knew where <persName ref="Taylor">Mr.
                  Taylor</persName> lived. They pointed to <placeName type="Taylor_Home">a house on
                  the left side of the court, the last one in the back</placeName>. I went there and
               rang the <objectName type="doorbell">bell</objectName>. <placeName type="Taylor_Home"
                  >The house</placeName> was dark. </p>
            <p> "<persName ref="Taylor">Mr. Taylor's</persName> voice came from the <placeName
                  type="Taylor_Home">second story window</placeName>. </p>
            <p> "'Who is there?' he asked." </p>
            <p> "'This is <persName ref="Shelby">Mrs. Shelby</persName>,<persName ref="Taylor"> Mr.
                  Taylor</persName>,' I answered. </p>
            <p> "'I'll be right down,' he replied and in a short time opened the door and asked me
               to step in. </p>
            <p> "I entered the room, a sort of combination living and dining room. <persName
                  ref="Taylor">Mr. Taylor</persName> showed much interest. He, too, appeared worried
               over <persName ref="Minter">Mary</persName>'s absence. Then he suggested some more
               persons to call. I waited while he used the <objectName type="Communication"
                  >telephone</objectName>. </p>
            <p> "I remember that he stepped into a sort of <placeName type="Taylor_Home">a telephone
                  room -- an out of the way nook</placeName>, and called. He talked to an assistant
               director, I think his name was <persName ref="O'Connor">Frank O'Connor</persName>,
               and he called several others. None had seen <persName ref="Minter">Mary</persName> or
               knew where she had gone. </p>
            <p> "By this time we both were considerably worried. </p>
            <p> "After some conversation, in which I mentioned my fears of an accident, I left." </p>
            <p> "'Be sure to call me and let me know if anything had happened,'<persName
                  ref="Taylor"> Mr. Taylor</persName> said as he bade me goodbye. I went to
                  <placeName type="Shelby_Car">our car</placeName>, where <persName ref="Whitney"
                  >Charlotte Whitney, the secretary</persName>, waited for me, and we went
                  <placeName type="Shelby_Home">home</placeName>. </p>
            <p> "I do not now remember the time of this visit. It was not, as has been whispered
               around, <time>shortly before <persName ref="Taylor">Mr. Taylor's</persName>
                  murder</time>. I did not 'storm' into <placeName type="Taylor_Home">the
                  house</placeName>, with a <objectName type="weapon">loaded revolver</objectName>
               in hand, as has been whispered around. I did not threaten <persName ref="Taylor">Mr.
                  Taylor</persName>, as has been said." </p>
            <p>
               <persName ref="Minter">Miss Minter</persName>, <persName ref="Shelby">Mrs.
                  Shelby</persName> said, <time>came home some time later</time>. </p>
            <p> "She never told us where she had been <time>that night</time>. We were relieved to
               learn that there had been no accident and that she was well. </p>
            <p> "But months later we learned about that trip. <persName ref="Urson">Frank
                  Urson</persName>, a dear friend of the family, and an old associate from Santa
               Barbara days, told me that he had run across <persName ref="Minter">Mary</persName>,
               driving her <objectName type="Car">big roadster</objectName> at 55 miles an hour and
               that he took her in tow and finally sent her <placeName type="Shelby_Home"
                  >home</placeName>. He told me he feared she would meet with an accident and warned
               us against her habit of speeding. </p>
            <p> "Certainly," <persName ref="Shelby">Mrs. Shelby</persName> declared, "this incident
               is not a hot murder mystery clue. Certainly, had there been anything sinister in
                  <time>that night</time> visit, I would not have taken two witnesses me or made
               public inquiry for <placeName type="Taylor_Home"><persName ref="Taylor">Mr.
                     Taylor's</persName> residence</placeName>. </p>
            <p> "And yet," <persName ref="Shelby">Mrs. Shelby</persName> went on," some one related
               this story and some one has been keeping it alive, until today it is one of the
               endless chains of clues and rumors that keep bobbing up on the least provocation. </p>
            <p> "What's more," <persName ref="Shelby">Mrs. Shelby</persName> declared, this story,
               along with all sorts of others, was related to former District Attorney <persName
                  ref="Keyes">Asa Keyes</persName>. </p>
            <p> "I made a complete statement to <persName ref="Keyes">Mr. Keyes</persName> after he
               returned from <placeName type="state">New York</placeName>. I held back nothing. Why
               this 'mystery' should be resurrected ever so often, is beyond me." </p>
            <p> "To the world in general the <persName ref="Taylor">Taylor</persName> murder case
               brought thrills, mystery and the glamour of big names, but to others it brought
               tragedy and sorrow," she said. </p>
            <p> There was a long pause. </p>
            <p> Perhaps the hectic days of the first <persName ref="Taylor">Taylor</persName> case
               investigation were ringing through<persName ref="Shelby"> Mrs. Shelby's</persName>
               mind. Perhaps there came a train of thought that carried swiftly the amazing story of
                  <persName ref="Minter">Mary's</persName> rise and the events that followed her
               famous director's unexplained murder. </p>
            <p> If <persName ref="Shelby">Mrs. Shelby</persName> thought about the <eventName
                  type="lawsuit"><objectName type="money">$1,000,000</objectName> suit filed by her
                  daughter in <time>1926</time> and of her demand for accountings, for audits and
                  for return of <objectName type="money">money</objectName> earned in the
                  films</eventName>, she gave no indication of this. </p>
            <p> And if the drama of that <eventName type="Body_Viewing">intense recital of <persName
                     ref="Minter">Mary's</persName> visit to the body</eventName> of <persName
                  ref="Taylor">Taylor</persName>, recalled to her <time>a few minutes before</time>,
               took her back to memories tinged with the romance of her beautiful daughter,
                  <persName ref="Shelby">Mrs. Shelby </persName>managed to hide her emotions. </p>
            <p> Earlier in the interview some allusion was made to <persName ref="Minter">Mary Miles
                  Minter's</persName> glowing account of the slain director and to the love letters
               and tokens, most of them unidentified, found <placeName type="Taylor_Home">in his
                  apartment</placeName>
               <time>after the murder</time>. </p>
            <p> "I'm sure, <persName ref="Taylor">Mr. Taylor</persName> was a gentleman," <persName
                  ref="Shelby">Mrs. Shelby</persName> said. </p>
            <p> She hesitated a little, and then went on. </p>
            <p> "I'm going to rip all this innuendo wide open -- there is no other way," she went
               on. </p>
            <p> "I know that there have been reports that I was in love with <persName ref="Taylor"
                  >Mr. Taylor</persName> and that I was jealous of my daughter and also feared that
                  <persName ref="Minter">Mary's </persName>career would suffer, and that I killed
                  <persName ref="Taylor">Taylor</persName> to preserve my love and <persName
                  ref="Minter">Mary's</persName> film future. </p>
            <p> "I am repeating these things just to show the absurdity of them. How is it possible
               to have such a double motive? The mere repetition of it shows the absurdity of the
               whole thing. Killing <persName ref="Taylor">Mr. Taylor </persName>would have wrecked
                  <persName ref="Minter">Mary's</persName> career instead of saving it. </p>
            <p> "But aside from that, the whole thing is ridiculous -- and vicious. </p>
            <p> "I am a woman who has always stood alone. </p>
            <p> "I was not in love with <persName ref="Taylor">William Desmond Taylor</persName>. I
               was not in love with anyone. And no one was in love with me. I never held a purely
               social conversation with <persName ref="Taylor">Mr. Taylor</persName> in my life. He
               was always aloof, a man of mystery, polished, distant and reserved. </p>
            <p> "In <time>those days</time> my tasks and interests were few. I lived, talked,
               planned and worked only for <persName ref="Minter">Mary</persName> and her pictures. </p>
            <p> "How utterly ridiculous, how unjust and criminal, to cast accusations of such flimsy
               nature, merely on 'clues' of such thin stuff. A crime without a motive, or reason." </p>
            <p>
               <persName ref="Shelby">Mrs. Shelby's</persName> references to <persName ref="Taylor"
                  >Taylor</persName> were most impersonal. In fact, she said during the interview,
                  <persName ref="Taylor">Taylor</persName> himself was impersonal. </p>
            <p> She came back to the <date>night of February 1, 1922</date>, when <persName
                  ref="Taylor">Taylor</persName> was shot and killed <time>only a few minutes after
                  the vivacious <persName ref="Normand">Mabel Normand</persName>, his dinner guest
                     <time>that night</time>, left</time>
               <placeName type="Taylor_Home">the bungalow</placeName> of the man she, along with
               many others, admired. </p>
            <p> She talked of <persName ref="Sands">Sands -- Edward F. Sands</persName>, the
               butler-valet of the slain director who <eventName type="Robbery">robbed and flaunted
                  his employer</eventName> because he knew of his checkered past. </p>
            <p> Of the incidents leading up to and following the actual slaying of <persName
                  ref="Taylor">"Bill" Taylor</persName>, <persName ref="Shelby">Mrs.
                  Shelby</persName> said but little. She refused to express an opinion. And of
                  <persName ref="Peavey">Henry Peavey</persName>, the colored house boy and cook,
               who <eventName type="dinner">served dinner</eventName> on <time>the night of the
                  murder</time> and <time>left just before <persName ref="Normand">Miss
                     Normand</persName></time>, <persName ref="Shelby">Mrs. Shelby</persName> also
               had little to say. </p>
            <p> "I do not remember seeing him at the <persName ref="Taylor">Taylor</persName>
               bungalow the night I called to see <persName ref="Taylor">Mr. Taylor</persName>," was
               all she said. </p>
            <p> "But this point seems to be overlooked generally when these vicious whispers are
               passed about," <persName ref="Shelby">Mrs. Shelby</persName> added. </p>
            <p> "The <time>time of the murder</time> was pretty well fixed. <persName ref="Douglas"
                  >Mrs. Douglas MacLean</persName>, who <eventName type="Gunshot">heard the
                  shot</eventName>, saw <persName ref="unidentified man">a man </persName>leave the
                  <placeName type="Taylor_Home"><persName ref="Taylor">Taylor</persName>
                  bungalow</placeName>. <persName ref="MacLean">Mrs. MacLean</persName> was in
                  <placeName type="Neighbor_Home">her own apartment</placeName>, and <placeName
                  type="Neighbor_Home">from the front door, only a short distance away</placeName>,
               saw <persName ref="unidentified man">this man</persName> and described <persName
                  ref="unidentified man">him</persName>. </p>
            <p> "Do I answer that description?" <persName ref="Shelby">Mrs. Shelby</persName> said
               smilingly as she rose to her feet and held out her <objectName type="clothing"
                  >silk-encased arms</objectName>. </p>
            <p> "Dressed in <objectName type="clothing">men's clothes</objectName>? But why" Why
               would a woman run the extra risk of being detected by wearing <objectName
                  type="clothing">clothes</objectName> in which she at once would become
               conspicuous? </p>
            <p> "This whole affair, however, is far from a jest to us. As I have said before, I have
               made complete statements and stand ready to make them if needed and if they can be of
               any use. </p>
            <p> "But I will not remain idle and be a target. From now on I am going to seek out
               those who circulate these rumors. </p>
            <p> "I am back in <placeName type="state">California</placeName>, the land I love. I am
               not in seclusion, as has been printed, nor am I hiding from any one or anything.
               There are some things that I must reserve for the future. Some of them may hold the
               solution to the motive for the circulation of these cruel rumors." </p>
            <p>
               <persName ref="Shelby">Mrs. Shelby </persName>rose to bid her interviewer good-by. </p>
            <p> "You may add," she said smilingly, "that I will remain <placeName
                  type="Shelby_Location">right here</placeName> and that if I do move from this
                  <placeName type="Shelby_Location">charming apartment</placeName> to <placeName
                  type="Shelby_Home">our own home</placeName>, I will not be in seclusion or in
               hiding." </p>

         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
