<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>HUMN100 FALL 2025: The Murder of William Desmond Taylor</title>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Diane Jakacki</persName>
               <resp>Instructor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Waina Ali</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Jada Alvarez</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Colin Caricato</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>John Cochran</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Lucy DiChristina</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Nick Eisele-Bockelkamp</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Ethan Esclamado</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Spencer Firestone</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Henry Gibbons</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Daniel Hou</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Campbell Killian</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Olivia King</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>William Le</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Charlie Meehleib</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Carter Morton</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Kate Reyen</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Blythe Sena</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Hunter Sloan</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Rylie Smith</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Lily Stein</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Riley Twiss</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Katrina von Behren</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Emma Walkowiak</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Amanda Woertz</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Produced by members of the HUMN100: Introduction to Text Analysis course, Fall
               2025</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>These interviews and statements are gathered from a number of sources, including
               "Taylorology" and Robert Giroux's Deed of Death</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="interview">
            <head>Interview with Leslie Henry</head>
            <byline>Diane Jakacki</byline>


            <p>Testimony of <persName ref="henry">Leslie Henry</persName> (<date>July
               1933</date>)</p>

            <p>HENRY: The only thing is that at that time it was just a perfect uproar. I never went
               through hell and high water higher than that was. </p>
            <p>LAWYER: Will you enlarge upon that? </p>
            <p>HENRY: I suddenly discovered a new picture so far as feelings were concerned. There
               was extreme bitterness between her <persName ref="cshelby">[Mary's] mother</persName>
               and <persName ref="minter">herself</persName> that seemed to go beyond business.
                  <persName ref="cshelby">The mother</persName>, on the other hand, was critical of
               the <persName ref="minter">daughter</persName> as being wayward and things of that
               character, and absolutely unwilling to have any advice from her or discussion with
               her. <persName>Mrs. Shelby</persName> then told me that her daughter was then
               charging, that <persName>Mary</persName> was then passing the word that <eventName
                  type="murder">she had killed <persName ref="taylor">Taylor</persName></eventName>. </p>

            <p>LAWYER: That who had killed Taylor? </p>
            <p>HENRY: <persName ref="cshelby">Mrs. Shelby</persName>. That Mary was doing that
               because her mother was jealous of Taylor and her associations -- I hope I cannot be
               sued for libel, because I am trying to tell you the truth. </p>
            <p>LAWYER: You need not have any apprehension on that score. </p>
            <p>HENRY: I am trusting you and trying to tell you what I know of this thing. Then came
               very clearly into line the intense bitterness between <persName ref="mshelby"
                  >Margaret</persName> and her sister. I saw little of it in Mary because I saw
               little of her. ... </p>
            <p>HENRY: Whatever I have been discussing here -- all purchases of <objectName type="document">securities</objectName> under new
               names, all of the rest of this I have been discussing here in relation to the
               employment of the different counsel, I am positive came after <eventName type="murder">the Taylor
                  murder</eventName>. There was untold bitterness mixed up in that. ...</p>

            <p>LAWYER: Did you prepare such a <objectName type="document">schedule</objectName> or
                  <objectName type="document">statement</objectName>? </p>
            <p>HENRY: I did. It was a long extensive thing...The purpose of that paper, as
               eventually developed, Mrs. Shelby told me, was that this showed that at no time had
               Miss Minter had any cash available for the purchase of the <placeName type="residence">Laughlin Park property</placeName>. She kept her all invested up.
               It eliminated the Laughlin Park property as any property that
               Miss Minter could have possibly purchased because at all times she had this block of
               securities she had purchased. There was a lot of bitterness over that Laughlin Park
               property... </p>
            <p>LAWYER: You understood it at the time, did you not, Henry, that Mrs. Shelby was
               making the claim in good faith that it was her money that went into Laughlin Park
               property? </p>
            <p>HENRY: She was making a claim all right. </p>
            <p>LAWYER: You understood there was a basis for the claim? </p>
            <p>HENRY: You are drawing a conclusion in my mind. I had purchased no securities for
               Miss Minter. This total block of securities at that time -- I could not differentiate
               between what should be assigned to Miss Minter or what should be assigned to her
               mother. Here was a big block of securities, while purchased in a variety of names,
               was in Mrs. Shelby's personal account. Anything developed out of them was retained by
               her -- a <objectName>commission</objectName> was paid to
                  <persName>Margaret</persName> for the <eventName>purchase of that
                  property</eventName>. </p>
            <p>LAWYER: You stated a moment ago that you were surprised that your accounting showed
               that the <placeName>Laughlin Park property</placeName> was purchased with Mrs.
               Shelby's and not with Mary's money. </p>
            <p>HENRY: I was not surprised at it. It was only to establish clearly -- I don't
               question it probably was Mrs. Shelby's money. I was handling any money that was
               there, and it was up to me to determine whether it was her money as manager's
               compensation, or whether it was her portion of what was earned which was used to buy
               the Laughlin Park property. What actually developed was that here where possibly
               there was no designation of bonds as being Miss Minter's property and reported as
               such in her <objectName>income tax form</objectName>, anything of that character, it
               suddenly came around in this set up whereby there was not a possibility under it to
               show where there had been at any time cash available for the purchase of this
               property by Miss Minter... </p>
            <p>LAWYER: At the time you prepared this account, you regarded it as an honest account,
               did you not? </p>
            <p>HENRY: If that was Mrs. Shelby's use of the money? I don't quite get you. </p>
            <p>LAWYER: Let me put it this way. </p>
            <p>HENRY: I recognized Mrs. Shelby as her daughter's manager, and if she said that was
               the way the money went, that was the way the money went. </p>
            <p>LAWYER: In other words, you did not regard the account you had gotten up as being a
               dishonest contract to defraud Mary? </p>
            <p>HENRY: No, I didn't at the time, because at the time I prepared that statement it was
               to show what Mary was supposed to own. I didn't and I don't know whether Mrs. Shelby
               had the idea when it was first prepared but it eventually wound up against the
               possibility of Mary ever having the money to buy Laughlin Park property. That was
               really surprising to me. </p>
            <p>LAWYER: So apparently it was prepared with that plan in mind? </p>
            <p> HENRY: I don't know what the plan was. I did what I was expected to do. Later it was
               used in that way. </p>
            <p>... </p>
            <p>LAWYER: You met Mrs. Charlotte Shelby, I believe, as has been stated from the
               probation report, during the Liberty Loan campaign in 1917? HENRY: Either late in
               1917 or early in 1918.</p>

            <p>LAWYER: Your first business relations with her, I believe, were in February 1920?</p>

            <p>HENRY: Yes.</p>

            <p>LAWYER: At that time you were employed by Blyth, Witter &amp; Company?</p>

            <p>HENRY: Yes.</p>

            <p>LAWYER: The report also showed, I believe, that at the beginning of the business
               relationship between you and Mrs. Shelby, she insisted that you should be personally
               responsible for any securities you might sell her? </p>
            <p>HENRY: She did.</p>

            <p>LAWYER: What was your answer to any such request by her?</p>

            <p>HENRY: I told Mrs. Shelby that <placeName type="residence">the house</placeName> I
               represented nor myself could guarantee the securities that were sold, by reason of
               the quantity of them and the number of investors to whom they would be sold, and that
               for me to assure her that she would be personally guaranteed in her investments would
               be an injustice to others who might not assert a requirement of that kind, and on the
               other hand that for me or the house to make any such guarantee to her was unfair, for
               the simple reason that it would be a physical impossibility for any house, with
               millions of dollars of securities outstanding, to make them all good in the event of
               loss. </p>
            <p>LAWYER: Were you later called upon to make good any securities which had defaulted in
               any way? </p>
            <p>HENRY: I was, yes. And then we talked about the <eventName type="mortality"
                  >death</eventName> of William Desmond Taylor .... </p>
            <p>LAWYER: When was the first time, Mr. Henry? </p>
            <p>HENRY: I made good in the winter of <date>1922</date>, or early in <date>1923</date>. </p>


            <p>LAWYER: What did you state to <persName ref="shelby">Mrs. Shelby</persName> on those
               occasions as to her request to pay that back? </p>
            <p>HENRY: I told <persName ref="shelby">Mrs. Shelby</persName> I could not pay the
               interest on the <placeName type="business">Portland Flouring Mills</placeName>; that I did not think in the first place it
               would be necessary and that is she would wait until the adjustment was made between
               dividends and interest on those defaulted bonds, through an exchange for the Sperry
               Flour Mills Company preferred stock, that she would probably be taken care of. Mrs.
               Shelby said, "I haven't anything to wait for, I have my money now," and I told her
               that the adjustment I was satisfied would take care of it. She said, "You understood
               very well when I first dealt with you the circumstances under which I dealt with Mr.
               Stoddard Jess, who was president of the <orgName type="business">First National Bank</orgName>. He had always been in
               the position where if anything went wrong with my securities, he would take care of
               me personally." I told her the situation was an impossible situation, and that I
               thought it would have been an injustice to Mr. Jess to have imposed it on him. She
               said, "It would not have been any imposition on him, for the simple reason that he
               was himself the head of the bank, and would see that the First National Bank took
               care of anything she had." She came back and drove at me on the point that I did
               understand that any obligations I sold her became my personal obligation, if I could
               not get it out of the house, and as a result, in the winter of 1922 or the spring of
               1923 I paid her the interest. </p>


            <p>LAWYER: BY THE COURT...Why was it necessary for you to make good to Mrs. Shelby on
               the interest of bonds she had bought, when there was a default in those bonds, to
               make good her losses; that isn't the usual custom of brokerage houses, is it? </p>
            <p>HENRY: No sir. </p>
            <p>LAWYER: When you sell customers securities, you do not guarantee that those
               securities will continue to pay interest, do you? </p>
            <p>HENRY: No, you don't; you maintain quite the contrary position, and the only answer,
               Your Honor, that I can give is this: Mrs. Shelby is a hard trading woman in the first
               place, as far as business is concerned, in my personal situation I was confronted by
               a woman who so far as any other person I knew of with whom she had done
               business-\-well, she pressed down on them, not only pressed down, but after breaking
               with them, abused them or passed criticism on them throughout the business community,
               and put them in a position of where, as in my particular case, had developed out of
               the income tax situation, put them in a position of, or rather put me in a position
               of where, even if I had broken with the account -\- it was a good account and I want
               that thoroughly understood -\- but had I broken with her, I would not only have lost
               the business, but I would have been subject to abuse, and certainly I would never
               have been free of the liability that approached a criminal nature, so far as the
               income tax return of 1920 was concerned, by reason of one thing I had done in
               connection with the return. </p>
            <p>LAWYER: BY THE COURT: Then, your position is, in effect, that Mrs. Shelby was in a
               position to blackmail you, and you felt she would use that power? </p>
            <p>HENRY: I would not say blackmail me, but had any investigation developed out of the
               income tax situation, which was certain to come if she went into litigation with her
               daughter, the complete onus for what she had done and been the beneficiary of, with
               regard to the 1920, 1921 and 1922 tax returns would have been thrown on me, on the
               basis of complete ignorance of what was involved in her income tax picture. </p>
            <p>LAWYER: Did you make any inquiry when you were first approached on the subject of
               responsibility, to find out whether the statement was true that Stoddard Jess had
               also guaranteed her against loss? </p>
            <p>HENRY: I couldn't, Judge, and I wouldn't have done it. As a matter of fact, to me it
               sounded more like a woman talking at the time and trying to lay the foundation for
               something that might happen in the future. Stoddard Jess, as a matter of fact, was
               sick, which sickness turned out fatally, as Your Honor will remember, and it was on
               his recommendation that she came to me. </p>
            <p>HENRY: Mrs. Shelby called me [in 1920] and told me she would have a dinner at her
               home, and said it would be just a little family party, herself and her mother Mrs.
               Miles, and Mary and Margaret and myself. She said she wanted me to absolutely be
               there, and that she expected I would have an opportunity to talk with Mary, and not
               only listen to Mary, but possibly correct Mary's viewpoint or attitude toward
               herself. </p>
            <p>LAWYER: At that time, Mr. Henry, did you have any idea that Mrs. Shelby was
               attempting to, or going to attempt to deprive Mary of her earnings? </p>
            <p>HENRY: Not at all. </p>
            <p>LAWYER: Incidentally, when was the first time that you became fully cognizant of the
               fact that such an intention existed on the part of Mrs. Shelby? </p>
            <p>HENRY: After the preparation of a set of charts by me, some time late in 1923. </p>
            <p>LAWYER: Up to that time in 1923, what was your feeling in respect to Mrs. Shelby's
               attitude towards Mary and her earnings? </p>
            <p>HENRY: I felt that Mrs. Shelby was holding on to the control of the money much beyond
               any good effect, so far as Mary was concerned. What I mean, not holding the actual
               possession, but withholding information from the girl, which would possibly raise
               some question in the girl's mind against Mrs. Shelby. </p>
            <p>LAWYER: What did you feel as to Mrs. Shelby's attitude, whether it was one of
               attempting to deprive Mary, or to protect her, up to this time in 1923. </p>
            <p>HENRY: I felt very much that Mrs. Shelby was trying to protect Mary. I thought she
               was doing it in a very unintelligent way, and I told her so. </p>
            <p>LAWYER: The things you did at that time, and later, up to 1923, did you do with the
               intention in mind, of assisting Mrs. Shelby in doing what you and she considered to
               be the best thing by Mary? </p>
            <p>HENRY: Yes, I did. </p>
            <p>LAWYER: On this theory, I wish you would state what took place there. </p>
            <p>HENRY: I sat next to Mary. Mary was at one end of the table, and Mrs. Shelby a the
               far end, and I was seated next to Mary. The dinner itself, the conversation at the
               dinner, was valueless, so far as this testimony is concerned, other than that Mary
               would only answer "yes," or "no," so far as her mother was concerned, and Margaret
               was ignored, even by Mrs. Miles, so just a very desultory conversation with me was
               had...After dinner, as we came away from the table, Mrs. Shelby came up to me and she
               whispered to me, "I wish you would make some opportunity to have a few words with
               Mary alone." I moved around the table with Mary and stood alongside of the fireplace
               that was on the side of the room. I went into part of the conversation I had with
               Mary at the dinner table. I said, "Mary, you talk of never again working, so far as
               the Government is concerned, and Liberty Loan campaigns, if the necessity arises. I
               don't think you believe that. I think you would be the very first one to step out and
               do anything you could under those circumstances." Mary very forcefully said, "I would
               not have anything to do with it, if I had to do it over again; I would never have had
               anything to do with the Liberty Loan campaigns, nor with any war work in the future."
               She said, "I was exploited commercially throughout that entire situation. My what
               appears to be patriotism, I felt, was done for nothing at all but to exploit me for
               the value of the box office." </p>
            <p>LAWYER: Did she say who was exploiting her? </p>
            <p>HENRY: She told me, "My mother carried me around from one place to another under
               circumstances which I did not like, for the sole purpose of getting the publicity
               value from the effort...From the time I have been a little girl, an infant virtually,
               my mother has used me for commercial purposes, and has used me for my earning power."
               She said, "I have been surrounded always with the business associates and friends of
               my mother, who could be of value in making further commercial progress." She said, "I
               have been deprived of my childhood; I have never been permitted to play with children
               of my own age or associate with them," and called my attention to the night before I
               had gone to Australia, when at Mrs. Shelby's request I had attended a dinner in the
               Helen Mathewson house. She said, "You remember the type of people you saw there. That
               has been my life ever since I was a child." She wasn't much more than a child then.
               "As a matter of fact," she said, "whenever I have had a chance to be with those of my
               own age, my mother has seen to it that they have been eliminated, and I have been
               associating only with studio directors, accountants and business managers of the film
               companies, and advertising men," and so forth. She ran down the line of the type of
               associations of her mother's that she had to find her life with. She said, "You know,
               when I came out to Santa Barbara, I was only about 14 years old." She said, "That has
               been my life, and that was my life even before then, and has been my life since."
               Mary called to mind my own youngster. I had a little girl who was then 5...she said,
               "You see to it, as the result of my experience, that the daughter of yours, Barbara,
               always plays with people of her own age, and has the association of children and
               young people, and her own life." She said, "I am getting -\- I am awfully sick of
               Hollywood, I am sick of the commercialized existence I have been living in, and the
               first time I can, either through the contract ending, the immediate contract ending
               or some other way, get out, I am going to leave everything and live my own life." </p>
            <p>LAWYER: Did you report the extent of this conversation to <persName>Mrs.
                  Shelby</persName>? </p>
            <p>HENRY: Yes. </p>
            <p>LAWYER: When? </p>
            <p>HENRY: That same evening. </p>
            <p>LAWYER: You told her what had been said? </p>
            <p>HENRY: I told Mrs. Shelby and her daughter Margaret of the effect of my talk with
               Mary, and I told them that I felt she was very much dissatisfied, and Mrs. Shelby
               said to me, "Just ignore it, do not pay any attention to it; she is being influenced
               by someone on the outside." </p>
            <p>LAWYER: At this time, in 1920, did you purchase any securities in the name of
               Margaret Shelby? </p>
            <p>HENRY: Yes...The conversation was substantially that Mrs. Shelby told me she wished
               to buy securities in the name of her daughter Margaret Shelby; that Mary wanted to
               provide $100,000.00 as a protection for Margaret, and that Margaret, as a matter of
               fact, from not being associated with the film industry, although an actress, was
               entitled to protection, entitled to some remuneration from Mary by reason of not
               being a competitor with her. </p>
            <p>LAWYER: Go ahead; did you ever talk to Miss Minter about that matter? </p>
            <p>HENRY: I did. </p>
            <p>LAWYER: When? </p>
            <p>HENRY: In 1923. </p>
            <p>LAWYER: What did Miss Minter say about this $100,000.00 fund for Margaret, for not
               being a competitor? </p>
            <p>HENRY: She told me, "If there is a $100,000.00 fund to be created for Margaret, it
               should have been created out of her [Shelby's] own 30 per cent of the contract;" that
               so far as she was concerned, she owed Margaret nothing; that she has maintained her
               for years in luxury and idleness, and that all she received from her was envy and
               criticism. I told her, I said, "Your mother has told me and Margaret has told me that
               Margaret was an actress in the East and that she stayed out of pictures so as not to
               be a competitor with you," and Mary told me, "If my mother or Mrs. Shelby could have
               made an actress out of Margaret acceptable to the pictures, she would have had her in
               them long ago," and she told me that she had attempted by various facial operations
               to make her presentable before a camera, and having failed in doing that, she was now
               making a misrepresentation so far as her being a competitor with Mary was concerned,
               and that if any provision was to be made for Margaret, it would have to be made out
               of Mrs. Shelby's own 30 per cent of the contract. </p>
            <p>LAWYER: Do you know whether anyone was acting as income tax expert for Mrs. Shelby in
               1920 and 1921, and if so, who was it? </p>
            <p>HENRY: Mrs. Marjorie Berger. </p>
            <p>THE COURT: She wound up in the Federal penitentiary, didn't she? </p>
            <p>HENRY: Yes, sir. </p>
            <p>LAWYER: Did you have any discussion with Mrs. Shelby along in March of 1921
               concerning Marjorie Berger? </p>
            <p>HENRY: Yes, Mrs. Shelby told me that Mrs. Berger would probably call on me for
               information concerning her investments, and asked me neither to give it to her nor to
               discuss her affairs in any degree with Mrs. Berger, and later Mrs. Berger did call me
               and asked that I indicate the securities from which the income was derived that was
               to be reported, and I told her that I did not understand that would be necessary and
               withheld the information. Mrs. Shelby, on my telling her of this, told me that Mrs.
               Berger was altogether too friendly with Mary, and that any information which she
               would receive on investments, she might carry on to Mary, and it was for that reason
               she did not want Mrs. Berger to know about them. </p>
            <p>HENRY: Now, with regard to the income tax. In the income tax for 1921, when I was
               consulted with regard to Mrs. Shelby, there were considerable profits derived through
               the sale of securities. Mrs. Shelby wanted the profits shown on the returns of Julia
               Miles and Margaret Shelby, and not on her own, while any losses might be taken to her
               own account. I prepared statements of those investments made in the previous year or
               two years, and submitted them to her and pointed out to her where she was only
               courting trouble for herself so far as the government was concerned in making
               statements which were contrary to the books of Blyth, Witter &amp; Company, so far as
               the purchase of securities were concerned; and secondly, that the very unusual matter
               for returns under the name of Julia Miles and particularly under the name of Margaret
               Shelby, were not supported by any figures on Blyth, Witter &amp; Company's books or
               even by the ownership certificates filed with the bond coupons during the year. Mrs.
               Shelby's only answer to that was, "Mr. Henry, this is my property, and I can do with
               it as I please, as between myself, my daughter and my mother. Whatever income I wish
               to show as paid to them is quite sufficient." In so far as my own position was
               concerned, and she said, "Marjorie Berger will take care of that, on the information
               by the return of the Federal Agent before the return is actually made." I was simply
               in the position of having to accept the statement of the woman on her own
               distribution of the property and the statement of the income for those years, and the
               profits and losses, and take them according to her own allocation of the property,
               but so far as the Government is concerned, the return was made by Marjorie Berger and
               Mrs. Shelby in association, and the only thing I could do was to take the very
               figures compiled and submit them. </p>
            <p>LAWYER: Did you do that each year? </p>
            <p>HENRY: I did. </p>
            <p>LAWYER: You gave Mrs. Shelby the figures showing her actual income on the securities
               purchased through Blyth, Witter &amp; Company? </p>
            <p>HENRY: Yes. </p>
            <p>LAWYER: You turned that over to her? </p>
            <p>HENRY: Yes, sir. </p>
            <p>LAWYER: And did you know until 1928 that she had not returned the income, or declared
               the profits and dividends received by her and turned over by you to her -\- did you
               know that during any period up until 1928? </p>
            <p>HENRY: No, I did not: the only concern I had about her income tax return for the
               years 1921, '22, and '23, was the possibility that if an investigation was held, the
               Government would show that income had not been allotted according to the purchases on
               the books of Blyth, Witter &amp; Company, and Mrs. Shelby and Mrs. Berger would deny
               any possible knowledge, and would refer to me as her financial agent, and as the only
               one who had prepared a statement of the income from her securities; but it wasn't
               until 1928 that I did know that she had not returned a penny of it. </p>
            <p>LAWYER: Did you have numerous discussions with Mrs. Shelby, at her request,
               concerning the Taylor murder, or supposed murder? </p>
            <p>HENRY: I did, yes. </p>
            <p>LAWYER: In other words, you were called upon to advise her as to various things
               arising out of that? </p>
            <p>HENRY: I can say this, Mr. Judson, that immediately after the Taylor murder case a
               telephone call came through to my office from Miss Margaret Shelby. I dodged
               answering it; I knew what the call would mean, and it was several days afterward that
               I finally did come to the house and excuse myself to Mrs. Shelby for not showing up. </p>
            <p>LAWYER: The deposition shows you had numerous discussions about that time concerning
               the suppression of publicity, and the purchase of letters from a Los Angeles
               newspaper, and so forth, that they had obtained possession of. </p>
            <p>HENRY: Yes. </p>
            <p>LAWYER: You also had further discussions about that affair I believe in 1925, when
               the case was agitated again, and there was a possibility of the indictment of Mrs.
               Shelby? </p>
            <p>HENRY: It was in the spring of 1926. </p>
            <p>LAWYER: Did you have numerous discussions at that time with her upon the subject of
               her possible indictment for the murder of Taylor? </p>
            <p>HENRY: It was the possible indictment of Mrs. Shelby in the Taylor murder case that
               was the one thing that made me agree, so far as Mrs. Shelby was concerned, on leaving
               the country, and her feeling concerning the possibility of that indictment. </p>
            <p>LAWYER: In these troubles between Miss Minter and Mrs. Shelby, were you called upon
               by Mrs. Shelby to prepare various charts, accounting statements, and discuss them
               with Mrs. Shelby's attorney and various accountants? </p>
            <p>HENRY: I was.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
