<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>HUMN100 FALL 2025: The Murder of William Desmond Taylor</title>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Diane Jakacki</persName>
               <resp>Instructor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Waina Ali</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Jada Alvarez</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Colin Caricato</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>John Cochran</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Lucy DiChristina</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Nick Eisele-Bockelkamp</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Ethan Esclamado</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Spencer Firestone</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Henry Gibbons</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Daniel Hou</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Campbell Killian</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Olivia King</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>William Le</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Charlie Meehleib</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Carter Morton</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Kate Reyen</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Blythe Sena</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Hunter Sloan</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Rylie Smith</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Lily Stein</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Riley Twiss</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Katrina von Behren</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Emma Walkowiak</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Amanda Woertz</persName>
               <resp>Editor</resp>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Produced by members of the HUMN100: Introduction to Text Analysis course, Fall
               2025</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>These interviews and statements are gathered from a number of sources, including
               "Taylorology" and Robert Giroux's Deed of Death</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="interview">
            <head>Interview with Ethel May Harrison</head>
            <byline>Charlie Meehleib</byline>
            <p> Interviews with Taylor's Ex-Wife * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * *
               * * * * * * * February 5, 1922 NEW YORK HERALD</p>
            <p><persName ref="taylor">William Desmond Taylor</persName>, the slain movie director,
               was well known in this city in <date>1908</date>. But he was not known as <persName
                  ref="taylor">Taylor</persName>. He was <persName ref="taylor">William Cunningham
                     Deane-Tanner</persName>, expert in <objectName type="furniture"
                        >antiques</objectName> in those days, and he moved in good society, was well
               supplied with <objectName ref="money">money</objectName> from a mysterious source in
               Ireland and eventually was married to <persName ref="eTanner">Ethel May Harrison</persName> of one
               of the<orgName ref="store"> Floradora Sextettes</orgName>.</p>
            <p> Without a word of explanation, according to the woman who was then his wife, he
               disappeared in <date>1908</date>. The first <persName ref="deanetanner">Mrs.
                  Deane-Tanner</persName> now is the wife of <persName ref="robins">E. L. C.
                     Robins</persName>, owner of <placeName type="restaurant">Robins
                        Restaurant</placeName> and other hostelries. <persName ref="eTanner">Mrs. Robins</persName> gave
               out a statement yesterday explaining her marriage and the desertion and her
               subsequent discovery that her former husband had<eventName> popped up in the motion
                  picture colony</eventName> at <placeName ref="state">Hollywood, Cal</placeName>.,
               and became famous the world over as <persName ref="taylor">William Desmond Taylor</persName>. She
               says <eventName ref="murder">his murder</eventName> shocked her and the daughter he abandoned.</p>
            <p>"<eventName ref="marriage">I married, in December, 1901</eventName>, <persName ref="taylor">Mr. William
               Cunningham Deane-Tanner</persName> of <placeName ref="country">Dublin, Ireland</placeName>," the
               statement said. "<eventName>He disappeared in October, 1908</eventName>. We could
               assign no reason for his disappearance except possibly aphasia. "In <date>1912</date>
               I got a decree of divorce in the State of <placeName ref="state">New York</placeName>
               <eventName>and was awarded custody of my only child , now 19.</eventName>
               "In August, 1914, I married Edward L. C. Robins.
               <eventName>Two and a half weeks later I discovered that William Desmond Taylor had
                  been Mr. Deane-Tanner</eventName>. I have no further statement which possibly
               could be of interest. "The news of Mr. Deane-Tanner's death was a great shock to my
               daughter and me NOrienta <placeName ref="town">Point, Mamaroneck</placeName>, last night,
               <persName ref="eTanner">Mrs. Robins</persName> said she held no resentment for the way
               <persName ref="deaneTanner">Deane-Tanner</persName> treated me."</p>
            <p>At her <placeName>home in ted her</placeName>. She presented excuses for him, saying
               he suffered lapses of memory during the time they lived together and that not long
               before he vanished, in <date ref="year">1908</date>, he was stricken with facial neuralgia and
               frequently was in an agony of pain. She does not believe he knew what he was doing
               the morning he left their <placeName ref="residence">home</placeName> and she supposes that a mental
               ailment can be held to account for his failure to return.</p>
            <p>Just as dramatic as were many of the chapters in <persName ref="taylor">Deane-Tanner, or William
               Desmond Taylor's</persName>, life was <eventName>Mrs. Robins's discovery in 1919
                  that he was still living</eventName>.</p>
            <p>With her daughter <persName ref="eTanner">Mrs. Robins</persName> went to a <placeName ref="studio">motion
               picture theater in this city</placeName> one night. They chose <placeName ref="theater">the
                  theater</placeName> without knowing what picture it was featuring. For several
               hundred feet of film it was just a new picture as far as they were concerned, but
               suddenly the hero appeared. <persName ref="robins">Mrs. Robins</persName> sank back in her
               <objectName ref="furniture">seat</objectName> too startled to missing <persName ref="deaneTanner">Deane-
                  Tanner</persName> a little changed--somewhat older looking they decided when they
               finally settled back to wait for the hero's next entry. They sat through the picture
               and then saw it again and learned that the man whose face they knew was acting and
               directing movies under the name of <persName ref="taylor">William Desmond Taylor</persName>.</p>
            <p><persName ref="eTanner">Mrs. Robins</persName> said last night that her daughter would not be
               satisfied until she had written to <persName ref="taylor">Taylor</persName>.
               <persName ref="taylor">Taylor</persName> answered her <objectName ref="document">letter</objectName> and the
               two continued a correspondence which grew with each month until finally
               <persName ref="taylor">Taylor</persName> of the movies came back to <placeName ref="city">New
                  York</placeName> to try to make some amends for his conduct as
               <persName ref="deaneTaylor">Deane-Tanner</persName>, the negligent father.</p>
            <p><persName ref="taylor">Taylor</persName> never explained why he had changed his name. But
               <persName ref="eTanner">Mrs. Robins</persName> said he met her and the daughter on at least one
               occasion and expressed a desire to try to make good for his failure. He spent
               <objectName ref="money">money</objectName> lavishly on the girl, giving
               <objectName ref="money">money</objectName> and other <objectName ref="passage">presents</objectName> to her
               and encouraging her to study. The love of the beautiful in art that appears to have
               impressed his Hollywood friends cropped up in his talks with his daughter, and he
               ultimately prevailed upon her to enter an <placeName ref="school">art school in this
                  city</placeName>. She is now studying there.</p>
            <p>
               <persName ref="eTanner">Mrs. Robins</persName> emphatically denied that her former husband ever
               married after he deserted her. She said she met him <date ref="month">last August</date> and
               remembers distinctly that he said he never had remarried and never would. His
               daughter, she quoted him as saying, was the only pal he wanted.</p>
            <p>According to <persName ref="eTanner">Mrs. Robins</persName>, <persName ref="deaneTanner">Deane-Tanner</persName> was
               of a family well known in <placeName ref="country">Ireland</placeName>--listed among the landed
               gentry or the peers, she wasn't sure which. His father was a Major in the British
               army, and he came of a line of men whose names have figured in British history.</p>
            <p>She said he was prepared for the army at one of the great British
               universities--<placeName ref="college">Oxford or Cambridge</placeName>--and that he was about to
               start for the military school when his health failed. He was sent to the
               <placeName ref="country">United States</placeName>, he told her, so that he might recover.
               <persName ref="eTanner">Mrs. Robins</persName> said she remembers that he told her once he had
               two sisters and one brother, and she met soon after their marriage a man she supposes
               was the brother.</p>
            <p>The stories of <objectName ref="possession">drugs and drinking</objectName>, <persName ref="eTanner">Mrs.
               Robins</persName> thinks, are untrue, because while <persName ref="deaneTanner">Deane-Tanner
               </persName>was her husband he used <objectName ref="possession">liquor</objectName> but sparingly and
               always criticized those who did not know how to handle it.</p>
            <p>Before her marriage to <persName ref="taylor">Taylor--or Deane-Tanner</persName>, as he called
               himself then--<persName ref="etanner">Mrs. Robins was Miss Ethel May Harrison</persName>. No one
               could be found who could explain fully <persName>Deane-Tanner</persName>'s early
               movements in <placeName ref="city">New York</placeName>, but it was established that he came
               from <placeName ref="country">Ireland</placeName> with considerable <objectName ref="money">money</objectName>
               and a habit of spending it freely. He caused some attention in sporting circles,
               talked about his <objectName ref="vehicle">yachts</objectName> abroad, and eventually, it was said,
               became a familiar figure on the float of the <placeName ref="club">Larchmont Yacht
                  Club</placeName>. He made friends easily and held them. Suddenly he began talking
               of previous visits here, and it was said yesterday, by men who knew him but do not
               want their names coupled with his in the murder mystery, that he let it be known he
               had played in roles opposite <persName ref="fanny">Fanny Davenpor</persName>t.</p>
            <p><persName ref="eTanner">Mrs. Robins</persName> would not say where she and her first husband made
               their home or where they were living when he disappeared, but it was established
               through friends that he dropped out of sight <date>in 1908</date> a few weeks after
               the <placeName ref="city">Vanderbilt</placeName> cup races.</p>
            <p>* * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * February 6, 1922
               NEW YORK DAILY NEWS</p>
            <p><persName ref="robins">Edward L. C. Robins</persName>, owner of
               <placeName ref="resturant">Delmonico's</placeName>, who married <persName ref="eTanner">Mrs. Ethel Hamilton Deane
                  Tanner</persName> after she had divorced the romantic Irishman whose murder has
               stirred the continent, knew <persName ref="eTanner">Tanner</persName> well and met <persName ref="eTanner">Mrs.
                  Tanner--now Mrs. Robins</persName>--through that friendship.</p>
            <p>But <persName ref="robins">Mr. Robins</persName> has not the slightest idea of how
               <persName ref="Tanner">Tanner--known to Hollywood and the movie world as William Desmond
                  Taylor</persName>--came to be murdered. <eventName>Talking with a representative
                     of the Daily News at his home in Mamaroneck last night, <persName ref="robins">Mr.
                        Robins</persName> said: "I can't see why the newspapers are paying so much
                     attention to <persName>Mamaroneck</persName>. It seems to me they ought to be
                     trying to solve this mystery out in <placeName ref="city">Los Angeles</placeName>,
                     where it happened</eventName>.</p>
            <p>"I knew <persName ref="pete">'Pete</persName>,' as we called him, long before
               <persName>Mrs. Tanner</persName> and I were married. Pictures of him now?
               <persName ref="ethel">Ethel</persName>, have we any pictures of <persName
                  ref="pete">Pete</persName>?" <persName ref="robins">Mrs. Robins</persName> had
               been listening in an alcove. When called she appeared promptly. A tall, striking
               blonde, with big, wide-open eyes, she did not impress one as the carefree girl who
               twenty years ago played in the <placeName>Floradora company</placeName>.</p>
            <p> "No," she answered. "I destroyed all those pictures when we got married. There might
               be one or two in the <objectName>old trunks</objectName>
               <placeName ref="house">upstairs</placeName>, but I doubt it. Every one I found I tore
               up long ago."</p>
            <p>With just that much interest is the murder of the man who was her husband accepted by
               <persName ref="robins">Mrs. Robins</persName>. She divorced him ten years ago,
               under curious circumstances, after he had gone out of her life four years before.
               Apparently his sudden and unexpected going out from his own life has made only the
               slightest impression upon <persName ref="robinds">Mrs. Robins</persName>.</p>
            <p>But behind all this insouciance there looms some extraordinary mystery. <persName
               ref="robins">Mrs. Robins </persName>cannot imagine any reason why her former
               husband was shot down in cold blood in his quiet home <placeName ref="city">at
                  Hollywood last Wednesday night</placeName>. But she is not surprised, astonished,
               amazed or--to be brutally frank--very much horror-stricken.</p>
            <p>...<persName>Mrs. Robins</persName> said last night that shortly after their marriage
               she and Tanner visited his folks in <placeName ref="country">Ireland</placeName>.
               They were entertained royally and she realized for the first time that the young
               blood she had married <placeName>off Broadway</placeName> was a veritable sportsman
               in <placeName ref="country">Ireland</placeName>. His family entertained her at their
               home in <placeName>Fitzwilliam Square</placeName> and afterward they paid a visit to
               <placeName>Cork</placeName>, where the old family seat was located.</p>
            <p>"They were the <persName ref="taylor">Deane Tanners</persName>," <persName
               ref="robins">Mrs. Robins</persName> explained, "to differentiate them from the
               other Tanners. The name is rather a familiar one in Ireland, and in England I think
               it is rather derogatorily applied to some <objectName ref="money">small
                  coin</objectName>, a six-pence, I think. His father had been a member of
               Parliament; his uncle was a justice of the peace. Altogether the family was quite to
               the front."...</p>
            
            
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
